<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2020-05-07T04:06+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Using twitter and web news mining to predict COVID-19 outbreak</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1951">5 1,309</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kia</forename><surname>Jahanbin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahid</forename><surname>Rahmanian</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Using twitter and web news mining to predict COVID-19 outbreak</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1951">5 1,309</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.4103/1995-7645.279651</idno>
					<note type="submission">Article ¡¤ March 2020 CITATIONS READS</note>
					<note>See discussions, stats, and author profiles for this publication at: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/339770709 2 authors: Ministry of Economic Affairs and Finance Jahrom University of Medical Sciences 6 PUBLICATIONS 10 CITATIONS 31 PUBLICATIONS 18 CITATIONS SEE PROFILE SEE PROFILE Some of the authors of this publication are also working on these related projects:</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1</head><p>Asian Pacific Journal of <ref type="bibr">Tropical Medicine 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">13</ref> Letter to Editor Zoonoses Research Center, Jahrom University of Medical Sciences, Jahrom, Iran</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine</head><p>In December 2019, a cluster of severe respiratory infections were based automatic system can monitor, evaluate, and categorize news, reported in Wuhan, Hubei Province, China. At the beginning, it which, in addition to managing news articles, it is also applied in the appeared that some patients had a history of attending or working field of advisory systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>in the wholesale fish and seafood market <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[1]</ref>. The market was Social networks fall into six groups as follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[8]</ref> SARS and is a subspecies of Sarbecovirus. The virus is temporarily</p><p>The Twitter social networking is a micro-blogging platform named the 2019-nCoV virus <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[2]</ref> and the Coronavirus Study Group considered by researchers as a result of useful applications. There has nominated the virus as SARS-CoV-2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[3]</ref>.</p><p>are over 320 million active subscribers on the social network, which On January 11, 2020, the first deaths from the virus were reported daily generates approximately 6 million tweets containing instant in China, and more positive cases from other countries such as news and comments; due to the wealth of information and their easy Thailand, Japan, South Korea, and the United States of America access. Twitter has extensive applications, such as the predicting were reported by January 20, 2020, and the transmission of a political process, investigating the effectivity of a product, individual-to-health care, further complicated the situation <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4]</ref>. monitoring the events pertaining to the health and hygiene <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Coronaviruses are zoonotic, meaning they are transmitted between Approximately 23% of Twitter subscribers are adults and on a daily animals and people, but the ways in which it is transmitted, animal basis, a total of approximately 500 million Tweets are broadcasted reservoirs, prophylaxis, and precise clinical manifestations requires each day <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[10]</ref>. more investigation. There is currently no vaccine and appropriate</p><p>In the model presented in this study, unstructured data on a novel treatment for COVID-19, so a high index of clinical suspicion and coronavirus (2019-nCoV) are extracted from Twitter and then inquiring about the history of travel and contact from patients with subjected to text cleaning, so-called screening or filtering, and fever and respiratory symptoms play a critical role in the prevention and control of the disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[5]</ref>.  of many researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[6]</ref>.</p><p>Web news mining is one of the most significant tools and the subset Kia Jahanbin et al./ Asian Pacific Journal of <ref type="bibr">Tropical Medicine 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">13</ref> finally classification operations. Since the focus is on real-time evolving of the TSK of mining, monitoring, storage and visualization programming, this model is implemented using a fuzzy rule-based of news and tweets about preparing our COVID-19. To execute the evolutionary algorithm called Eclass1-MIMO.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>method, more than 364 080 clean and integrated tweets and news</head><p>One of the most effective ways to prevent and control epidemics is were then categorized using the Eclass1-MIMO method and finally to monitor and track the news and social networks about the spread viewed in real time on the world map.</p><p>of infectious diseases. In this study, the FAMEC method was used In the recent years, a significant number of researchers have been to send an alert message to surveillance systems for timely detection working on categorizing, clustering, analyzing emotions, thinking outbreaks of the COVID-19. and developing recommenders based on social data, but most of The FAMEC method has four main phases as follows:</p><p>these works have focused on either news websites or Twitter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Clearing and integrating data and extracting vocabulary; 2. Web</head><p>The evolving fuzzy algorithm with the Eclass1-MIMO method was and tweet crawling; 3. Applying fuzzy rules and storing data using used in the study of Iglesias for classifying six areas of knowledge, fuzzy classifier. 4. Visualizing and sending messages.</p><p>health, technology, sports, arts and commerce <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[6]</ref>. Also, Jahanbin et al.</p><p>The visualization component of the suggested method aims to assist used web news mining in infectious disease surveillance systems to in real-time monitoring and tracking of the beginning and spread of timely diagnose epidemics <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[9]</ref>. outbreaks, which can greatly contribute to the effectiveness of public</p><p>The geographical origins of tweets posted about COVID-19 were health surveillance systems in this area.</p><p>found to be consistent with the formal WHO report about incidence networks, using the web news mining of these network used by each <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the results obtained from the monitoring of a novel community, the geographical and demographical of the users can be coronavirus (2019-nCoV) related news in the study period, which identified accurately. This is due to the fact that these network report are associated to 364 080 tweets from 179 534 users. The most easily statistical data with the most comments, photos, videos, etc.</p><p>Tweets about the coronavirus have been from the US (42.1%), China on COVID-19. This helps to predict morbidity rates in each region, (13.0%), Italy (11.8%) and Australia (6.6%). This is consistent with and bring attention of policy-maker in the health care systems to the report of the cases which was obtained from the WHO <ref type="bibr">[11]</ref>. In purposefully implement educational programs in the regions where this study, a new method based on fuzzy algorithm was applied for exposed to higher risks. Finally, this can help to reduce the incidence case and even mortality in communities. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>: 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Micro- immediately shut down on January 1, 2020, and local environmental blogging platforms: such as twitter; 2. Blogging platforms: such health and disinfection measures were fully implemented. On as WordPress and Blogger; 3. Instant messaging Apps: such January 9, 2020, the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus as WhatsApp and Telegram; 4. Networking platforms: such as 2 (SARS-CoV-2), formerly known as 2019-nCoV, was declared the Facebook and LinkedIn; 5. Software elaboration platform: such as causative agent in 15 of the 59 hospitalized patients, causing great GitHub; 6. Photo/video sharing platforms: such as Instagram and concern: this new coronavirus has 70% genetic association with YouTube.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>?</head><label></label><figDesc>To whom correspondence may be addressed. E-mail: rahmanian.vahid@ut.ac.ir On a daily basis, a large number of Websites and online social media produce a large amount of data in a variety of fields such as technology, medicine, history, political and social news, arts This is an open access journal, and articles are distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-ShareAlike 4.0 License, which allows others to remix, tweak, and build upon the work non-commercially, as long as appropriate credit is given and the new creations are licensed under the identical terms.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>For reprints contact:</head><label></label><figDesc>reprints@medknow.com and other fields. Analyzing and classifying these data leads to the ?2020 Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine Produced by Wolters Kluwer- production of knowledge and nowadays, it has attracted the attention Medknow. All rights reserved.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Initially, during the period between Dec. 31 2019 and Feb. 6 2020, cases of COVID-19 during the study period. This reflects the 2019-nCoV (COVID-19) tweets were extracted from the Twitter efficacy of the suggested method to monitor and track this infection. social network and stored in the relevant database. The collected The limitation of the proposed method is that it cannot be used to database contained 364 080 tweets from 179 534 users. 21 805 371 monitor and track infectious diseases in regions with poor or no users who have re-tweet or like these posts and 52 837 975 554 times access to social networks such as Twitter and Facebook. Also, as these posts have been viewed by users. The main hashtags about the language of processing the tweets in this study was English, the novel coronavirus were #corona, #ncov, #wuhan, #china, #2019- results may be affected by the processing language. nCoV, #virus, #corona virus china, #coronavirus outbreak, wuhan In conclusion, due to the revolutionary development of the social virus.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figuer 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figuer 1. Monitoring of geographical distribution of the tweets about COVID-19 between 31/12/2019 and 6/02/2020.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>journal homepage : www.apjtm.org</head><label>homepage</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Impact Factor: 1.77 

Using twitter and web news mining to predict COVID-19 outbreak 

doi: 10.4103/1995-7645.279651 

Kia Jahanbin 

1 

, Vahid Rahmanian 

2? 

1 

Information Technology, Islamic Azad University Branch of Kerman, Iran 

2 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot">Kia Jahanbin et al./ Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine 2020; 13</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Severe acute respiratory syndrome-related coronavirus: The The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest. species and its viruses-a statement of the coronavirus study group</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gorbalenya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Baric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>De Groot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Drosten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gulyaeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1101/2020.02.07.937862</idno>
		<idno>bioRxiv 2020.02.07.937862</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.02.07.937862" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Early transmissibility assessment of a novel coronavirus in Wuhan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Majumder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mandl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The authors would like to thank to the instructors of the online org/10.2139/ssrn.3524675</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Learning for Data Science and Analytics</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Available from: by Columbia University for giving us</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.who.int/health-topics/coronavirus" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Accessed on 10 February data and text mining. 2020</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web news mining in an evolving framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Iglesias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tiemblo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ledezma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sanchis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf Fusion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Authors&apos; contributions</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social big data mining: A survey focused on opinion mining and sentiments analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Guellil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Boukhalfa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference of ISPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2015</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">VR, and KJ conceived and designed the study. VR, and KJ were International Symposium on Programming and Systems</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Algiers</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">responsible for literature search and screening. KJ were responsible</title>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.1109/ISPS.2015.7244976</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">for data collection and analyses. VR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>contributed to data</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mastering social media mining with R. Mumbai: interpretation. KJ drafted the manuscript and VR, critically revised Packt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ravindran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Garg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Publishing Ltd; 2015. the manuscript</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Application of Twitter and web news mining in infectious disease surveillance systems and prospects for public health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jahanbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rahmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Rahmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sotoodeh</forename><surname>Jahromim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">GMS Hyg Infect References Control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Duggan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lampe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lenhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mjprc</forename><surname>Madden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical features of media update</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew Res Center</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lancet [11] World Health Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Wuhan, China</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) situation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5.reports.2020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.who.int/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Nishiura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Linton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kinoshita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The extent of transmission of novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China, 2020</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J [Accessed on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-02-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">View publication stats View publication stats</title>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.3390/jcm9020330</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clin Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
