<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A note on competitive diffusion through social networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Elsevier BV</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noga</forename><surname>Alon</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ariel</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Procaccia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Tennenholtz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A note on competitive diffusion through social networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Information Processing Letters</title>
						<title level="j" type="abbrev">Information Processing Letters</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">0020-0190</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="225"/>
							<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ipl.2009.12.009</idno>
					<note type="submission">Article history: Received 9 August 2009 Received in revised form 31 October 2009 Accepted 23 December 2009 Available online 4 January 2010 Communicated by B. Doerr</note>
					<note>Contents lists available at ScienceDirect Information Processing Letters a r t i c l e i n f o a b s t r a c t</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Graph algorithms Algorithmic game theory Social networks</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce a game-theoretic model of diffusion of technologies, advertisements, or influence through a social network. The novelty in our model is that the players are interested parties outside the network. We study the relation between the diameter of the network and the existence of pure Nash equilibria in the game. In particular, we show that if the diameter is at most two then an equilibrium exists and can be found in polynomial time, whereas if the diameter is greater than two then an equilibrium is not guaranteed to exist.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Social networks such as Facebook and Twitter are modern focal points of human interaction. The pursuit of insights into the nature of this interaction calls for a game-theoretic analysis. Indeed, a number of papers (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>) investigate variations on the following setting. The social network is represented by an undirected graph, where the vertices are users and edges connect users who are in a social relationship. Suppose, for example, that there are several competing applications, e.g., voice over IP systems, that are not interoperable. The users play a coordination game, where if two neighbors adopt the same system they get some reward that is based on the inher-ent quality of the system. The goal is to study the diffusion of technologies through the social network. The point of view here is completely decentralized, and the players in the game are the users of the social network.</p><p>We propose a different, global point of view regarding the incentives that govern the diffusion process. Suppose we have several firms that would like to advertise competing products via "viral marketing". Each firm initially targets a small subset of users, in the hope that the rumor about its product would spread throughout the network. However, a user that adopts one product is reluctant to adopt another, hence the campaign of one firm negatively affects the success of another firm's campaign. To the best of our knowledge our model is the first game-theoretic model to deal with the incentives of interested parties outside the social network. Note that some previous papers did consider the problem of choosing an influential set of users as an optimization problem (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>), but not in a competitive game-theoretic setting. Other papers, which deal with Voronoi games on graphs, provide a game-theoretic study of a static facility location problem where each vertex is assigned to the closest agent and the utility of an agent is the number of vertices assigned to it (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>). In our model, in contrast, vertices are <ref type="bibr">0020</ref> where x i ¡Ê V is the initial vertex selected by agent i. We also denote</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">x ?i = =x 1 , . . . , x i?1 , x i+1 , . . . , x n .</formula><p>Given a strategy profile x ¡Ê V n , the utility of agent i ¡Ê N, denoted U i (x), is the number of nodes that are colored in color i when the diffusion process terminates. For instance, in the example given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Our results</head><p>Given a graph G and u, v ¡Ê V , let d(u, v) be the length of the shortest path between u and v (in terms of the number of edges). The diameter of the graph, denoted D(G), is the maximum distance between a pair of vertices,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(b) Time 2. that is, D(G) = max u,v¡ÊV d(u, v).</formula><p>Our investigation focuses on the relation between the diameter of the graph and the existence of Nash equilibria in the induced diffusion game. Indeed, if we can find a Nash equilibrium then we can often predict the behavior of the agents and the outcome of this competitive diffusion process, or, alternatively, advise the agents how to play. Our first theorem is the following.  a Nash equilibrium. Furthermore, an equilibrium can be found in polynomial time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theorem 2.1. Every game ¦£ = =G, N where D(G) 2 admits</head><p>assigned to agents based on a more complex diffusion process rather than solely on the basis of their distance from the agents.</p><p>Note that a random graph on n labeled vertices where each edge appears with probability p, usually denoted G(n, p), has diameter at most two with high probability whenever p (c ln n)/n for c &gt; 2 (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> for more</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">The model</head><p>details about the diameter of random graphs). In particular (by taking p = 1/2) almost all graphs over n vertices have</p><p>Let G = =V , E be an undirected graph. Furthermore, let N = {1, . . . ,n} be the set of agents (the interested parties). The diffusion process unfolds as follows. There are n + 2 colors: a color for each agent i ¡Ê N, as well as two additional colors: white and gray. Initially, at time 1, some of the vertices are colored in the colors of N, while the others are white. At time t + 1 each white vertex that has neighbors colored in color i, but does not have neighbors colored in color j for any j ¡Ê N \ {i}, is colored in color i. diameter at most two. Finally, social networks typically have a very small diameter. Therefore, it can be argued that assuming a diameter of two is not very restrictive.</p><p>It is now natural to ask whether the existence of Nash equilibria can also be guaranteed for diameters larger than two. It is not too difficult to construct a graph with diameter four that does not admit an equilibrium. Our second theorem gives a negative answer even with respect to diameter three.</p><p>A white vertex that has two neighbors colored by two distinct colors i, j ¡Ê N is colored gray. In other words, we assume that if two agents compete for a user at the same time they "cancel out" and the user is removed from the game. The process continues until it reaches a fixed point, that is, all the remaining white vertices are unreachable due to gray vertices. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 1</ref> for an illustration of the diffusion process. The construction in the proof of Theorem 2.2 can easily be extended to a larger number of agents or to any (finite or infinite) diameter greater than three.</p><p>A game ¦£ = =G, N is induced by a graph G, representing the underlying social network, and the set of agents N. The strategy space of each agent is the set of vertices V in the graph, that is, each agent i selects a single node that is colored in color i at time 1. Note that if two or more agents select the same vertex at time 1 then that vertex becomes</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.">Discussion</head><p>In order to facilitate the game-theoretic analysis we consider a very simple model of diffusion. In particular, conflicts are deterministically resolved by introducing gray vertices, and each agent initially selects just one vertex.</p><p>gray. A strategy profile is a vector x = =x 1 , . . . , x n ¡Ê V n , Richer (probabilistic) models of diffusion through a social network exist in the literature, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. On the other hand, the assumption of discrete time steps is quite common.</p><p>Theorem 2.1 implies that with high probability a random graph (even a relatively sparse one) induces a game that admits a Nash equilibrium. However, social networks are normally not completely random, but rather often exhibit structure. Ideally one would be able to extend our result by showing that under a convincing random graph model of social networks (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref>) the induced game admits a Nash equilibrium with high probability.</p><p>where ¦Ö A i is the indicator function that returns 1 if x ¡Ê A i and 0 otherwise. The rightmost term is required since even if x i is a neighbor of some x j , it is still colored by agent i at time 1, but is nevertheless included in the middle term.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Now, suppose U i (x i , x ?i ) &gt; U i (x). It follows that |N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) + ¦Ö A i x i , x ?i j =i &gt; |N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) + ¦Ö A i (x).<label>(2)</label></formula><p>j =i</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Proofs</head><p>Since ¦Ö A i is a Boolean function, this implies that We begin by proving Theorem 2.1; we subsequently discuss some implications of the proof.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">|N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) |N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) .<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">&gt; N x j (N x i ¡É N x j ) D(G) = 2. Given a profile x ¡Ê V N , let P (x) = |{ j: d(x i , x j ) = + |N x i | ? j =i j =i 1}|, that</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">¦µ(x) = N(x) ¡¤ n + P (x).</formula><p>It is sufficient to show that for every x ¡Ê V n , i ¡Ê N, and jacent pairs of agents by at most n ? 1, i.e., P (x i , x ?i ) &gt; P (x) ? n. We conclude that</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">x ¦µ = N n + P i ¡Ê V , x i , x ?i x i , x ?i x i , x ?i U i x &gt; U i (x) ? ¦µ N(x) n + n + P i , x ?i x i , x ?i &gt; ¦µ(x).<label>(1)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">x i , x ?i</formula><p>Indeed, given Eq. (1) it clearly holds that any strategy pro-&gt; N(x) n + n + P (x) ? n file x ¡Ê V n that maximizes ¦µ(x) must be a Nash equilibrium. Moreover, in order to find one such profile we may start from some preference profile, and in each step attempt to find a profitable deviation for one of the agents. We terminate if there is no such deviation (which, by definition, means that we have found a Nash equilibrium). This algorithm terminates after a polynomial number of steps</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">= ¦µ(x).</formula><p>Otherwise, Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(3)</ref> holds as an equality, and hence </p><formula xml:id="formula_9">|N(x i , x ?i )| = |N(x)|. It</formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">¦µ x = N n + P i , x ?i x i , x ?i x i , x ?i</formula><p>is two then vertices can only be colored by an agent i ¡Ê N = N(x) n + P at time 1 or 2. Specifically, the vertices colored by agent i are roughly the vertices in the neighborhood of x i that</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">x i , x ?i &gt; N(x) n + P (x)</formula><p>are not neighbors of x j for some j ¡Ê N \ {i} (since these vertices are either gray or colored by j). Formally, define = ¦µ(x).</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">A i = x: ? j ¡Ê N \ {i} s.t. d(x i , x j ) = 1 .</formula><p>This establishes Eq. (1), and hence completes the proof of the theorem. 2</p><p>Assuming that x i = x j for all i = j, the utility of agent i under the strategy profile x ¡Ê V n is</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">U i (x) = |N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) + ¦Ö A i (x),</formula><p>What the proof of Theorem 2.1 essentially shows is that when the diameter of the graph is two the diffusion game is a potential game <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>; specifically, a function that satisfies (1) is known as a generalized ordinal potential function. j =i Potential games have the property that better response dynamics converge to a Nash equilibrium; in other words, if at every stage the agents simply behave myopically, that is, some agent deviates to a more profitable strategy, then they will eventually reach an equilibrium.</p><p>We are now ready to prove our second theorem.</p><p>2. Let v i and v j be two nonparallel hubs that are ad-</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">jacent to a clique C k . Then (N v i \ N v j ) ¡É C k contains exactly one of the sets C kl , l = 1, . . . , 5.</formula><p>Note that the construction is essentially symmetric with respect to the hubs.</p><p>G has diameter 3. Using <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2</ref>, it is easy to verify that G Proof. We first give our construction, then establish that it has diameter three and that it does not admit a Nash equilibrium.</p><p>G does not admit a Nash equilibrium. We consider strategy profiles x 1 , x 2 ¡Ê V 2 for the two agents. The symmetries</p><p>The construction. Let G = =V , E be defined as follows. The of our construction allow us to restrict our attention to six cases.</p><p>vertices of the graph are</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">V = {v 1 , . . . , v 6 } ¡È C 1 ¡È C 2 ¡È C 3 , Case 1. x 1 = v 1 , x 2 ¡Ê C 1 (hub and adjacent clique). Agent</formula><p>where for i = 1, 2, 3,</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">C i = C i1 ¡È ¡¤ ¡¤ ¡¤ ¡È C i5 . Each C ij contains ten vertices, that is, |V | = 156.</formula><p>1 colors some of the vertices of C 2 and some hubs, that</p><p>The edges of the graph are defined as follows. Each C i , is, U 1 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 60. By deviating to x 1 = v 5 , agent 1 colors</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">C 21 , C 22 , C 24 , C 31 , C 32 , C 34 , i.e., U 1 (x 1 , x 2 ) 60.</formula><p>for i = 1, 2, 3, is a clique. There is an edge v 1 , u for every since then it colors both v 1 and v 2 at time 2 (rather than just one of them), and colors twenty vertices of C 2 at time 3 (rather than ten). Hence we can assume without loss of generality that x 1 ¡Ê C 11 . In that case, agent 2 colors C 3 and some hubs, therefore U 2 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 60. By deviating to </p><formula xml:id="formula_18">u ¡Ê C 11 ¡È C 12 ¡È C 13 ¡È C 21 ¡È C 22 ¡È C 23 ; an edge v 2 , u for every u ¡Ê C 11 ¡È C 14 ¡È C 15 ¡È C 21 ¡È C 24 ¡È C 25 ; an edge v 3 , u for every u ¡Ê C 11 ¡È C 12 ¡È C 14 ¡È C 31 ¡È C 32 ¡È C 33 ; an edge v 4 , u for every u ¡Ê C 11 ¡È C 13 ¡È C 15 ¡È C 31 ¡È C 34 ¡È C 35 ; an edge v 5 , u for every u ¡Ê C 21 ¡È C 22 ¡È C 24 ¡È C 31 ¡È C 32 ¡È C 34 ; an edge v 6 , u for every u ¡Ê C 21 ¡È C 23 ¡È C 25 ¡È C 31 ¡È C 33 ¡È Case 2. x 1 = v 1 , x 2 ¡Ê C</formula></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. An illustration of the diffusion process, with N = {1, 2}.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Theorem 2. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Let N = {1, 2}. There exists a graph G with D(G) = 3 such that the game ¦£ = =G, N does not admit a Nash equilibrium.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. The construction of the proof of Theorem 2.2. The cliques C 1 , C 2 , C 3 are outlined by dashed ellipses, and the edges inside the cliques are not shown. An edge between v i and C jk implies that v i is connected to all the vertices u ¡Ê C jk .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>of the game ¦£ if an agent cannot benefit¡Ê N and x i ¡Ê V it</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the utility of each 
of the agents is two. A strategy profile x is a (pure strategy) 

Nash equilibrium (a) Time 1. 

from unilaterally deviating to a different strategy, i.e., for 

every i holds that U i (x 

i 

, x ?i ) U i (x). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>j =i j =i Theorem 2.1. Every game ¦£ = =G, N where D(G) 2 admits¡È N x i = N x j + |N x i | ? (N x i ¡É N x j ) j =i j =i j =i</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>We distinguish between two cases. If Eq. (3) holds as a 
strict inequality then 

a Nash equilibrium. Furthermore, an equilibrium can be found 
in polynomial time. 






N x j Proof. If D(G) 1 then the graph is a clique and the 

theorem follows trivially. Therefore, we may assume that 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>¡È N x i , j =i tex u ¡Ê V by N u = {v: d(u, v) 1}, and let N(x) = n i=1 N x i . Consider the potential function which implies that |N(x i , x ?i )| |N</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>is, the number of pairs with distance one from 
each other. Furthermore, denote the neighborhood of ver-

= 






N x j (x)| + 1. In addition, a 

deviation of a single agent can decrease the number of ad-

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>). That is, agent i has no neighbors among x ?i under x i but has at least one neighbor un- der x . Thus the number of neighbors of agent i increases since ¦µ(x) is bounded from above by n|V |+nx ?i ) &gt; P (x). We conclude that</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>then follows from Eq. (2) that 

¦Ö A i (x 

i 

, x ?i ) &gt; ¦Ö A i (x2 for every x, 

i 

and by Eq. (1) every profitable deviation by an agent in-
creases the value of the potential function by at least one. 
We turn to proving Eq. (1). If the diameter of the graph 

and the number of neighbors of agents j ¡Ê N \ {i} does not 
decrease, i.e., P (x 
i , </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>= 3 such that the game ¦£ = =G, N does not admit a Nash equilibrium. has diameter 3. For example, a path from v 1 to u ¡Ê C 32 is given by v 1 ¡ú w ¡ú v 3 ¡ú u, where w ¡Ê C 11 . A path from u ¡Ê C 13 to w ¡Ê C 24 is given by u ¡ú v 1 ¡ú x ¡ú w, where x ¡Ê C 21 .</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Theorem 2.2. Let N = {1, 2}. There exists a graph G with 
D(G) </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>3 (hub and nonadjacent clique). Agent 2 colors the vertices of C 3 and some hubs, hence U 2 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 60. By deviating to x 2 ¡Ê C 11 , agent 2 colors C 14 , C 15 , and C 3 , thus U 2 (x 1 , x 2 ) 70. C 35 . An illustration of the graph G is given as Fig. 2. Case 3. x 1 = v 1 , x 2 = v 3 (nonparallel hubs). Agent 1 col- ors C 13 , C 2 , and some hubs, therefore U 1 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 70. We refer to the vertices v 1 , . . . , v 6 as hubs; we say that By deviating to x v 1 and v 2 are parallel hubs, and so are v 3 and v 4 , v 5 and v 6 . If the hub v i is connected by an edge to some of the vertices of clique C j , we say that v i is adjacent to C j ; for instance, v 1 and C 1 are adjacent, whereas v 1 and C 311 , agent 1 colors C 13 , C 15 , C 2 , so U 1 (x 1 , x 2 ) 70. Case 4. x 1 = v 1 , x 2 = v 2 (parallel hubs). Agent 1 colors C 12 , C 13 , C 22 , C 23 , and some hubs (v 3 , . . . , v 6 are gray and C 3 remains white), hence U 1 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 50. By deviating to x 1 ¡Ê C 3 , agent 1 can guarantee a utility of at least 50 (since it colors C 3 ). 1. Let v i and v j be two parallel hubs that are adjacent to a clique C k . Then (N v i \ N v j ) ¡É C k contains exactly two of the sets C kl , l = 1, . . . , 5. Case 5. x 1 ¡Ê C 1 , x 2 ¡Ê C 3 (different cliques). If x 1 / ¡Ê C 11 , x 2 / ¡Ê C 31 , then agent 1 can benefit by deviating to x 1 ¡Ê C 11 ,</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>are 
not. 
The construction possesses the following important 
properties: 

1 ¡Ê C </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>x 2 = v 5 , agent 2 colors at least C 21 , C 22 , C 24 , C 31 , C 32 , C 34 , hence U 2 (x 1 , x 2 ) 60.1 ¡Ê C 1 , x 2 ¡Ê C 1 (same clique). Since C 1 \ {x 1 , x 2 }1 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 60 or U 2 (x 1 , x 2 ) &lt; 60. By deviating to v 5</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Case 6. x is gray, there are at most 108 vertices that are not gray, 

therefore it must hold that either U an agent can guarantee 
a utility of at least 60. 2 </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emergence of scaling in random networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Barab¨¢si</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Albert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">286</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="512" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bollob¨¢s</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Random Graphs</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nash equilibria in Voronoi games on graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>D¨¹rr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Thang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Annual European Symposium on Algorithms (ESA)</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Annual European Symposium on Algorithms (ESA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Durrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Random Graph Dynamics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of compatibility in the diffusion of technologies through social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Immorlica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mahdian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wexler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 8th ACM Conference on Electronic Commerce (EC)</title>
		<meeting>the 8th ACM Conference on Electronic Commerce (EC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="83" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">?</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Voronoi games on cycle graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mavronicolas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Monien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Papadopoulou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schoppmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd International Symposium on Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science (MFCS)</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd International Symposium on Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science (MFCS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="514" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Monderer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Shapley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Potential games, Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="143" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Random graph models of social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Strogatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2566" to="2572" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
