<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:46+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Survey on Improving the Efficiency of Different Web Structure Mining Algorithms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-02">February 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Md</roleName><forename type="first">Preeti</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ataullah</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Survey on Improving the Efficiency of Different Web Structure Mining Algorithms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">International Journal of Engineering and Advanced Technology (IJEAT)</title>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2249" to="8958"/>
							<date type="published" when="2013-02">February 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>With the rapid increase in internet technology, users get easily confused in large hyper text structure. Providing the relevant information to user is primary goal of the website owner. In order to achieve this goal, they use the concept of web mining. Web mining is used to categorize users and pages by analyzing the users&apos; behavior, the content of the pages, and the order of the URLs that tend to be accessed in order [1]. Web structure mining plays very important role in this approach. It&apos;s defined as the process of analyzing the structure of hyperlink using graph theory. There are many proposed algorithms for web structure mining such as Pagerank Algorithm, HITS, Weighted pagerank Algorithm, Topic Sensitive Pagerank Algorithm (TSPR), weighted page content rank Algorithm (WPCR) etc. In this paper, we have described the outline of all the algorithms and identify their strengths and limitations. Index term: HITS, Pagerank algorithm, TSPR, Web mining weighted pagerank algorithm, WPCR etc.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>Web mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[2]</ref> is an application of data mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref>. As we know data mining is the process of extracting the useful information from large amount of data present in any organization. Web mining is defined as the process of extracting useful information from World Wide Web data. Two different approaches are taken to define the web mining. 1) "Process-centric view" which defines web mining as sequence of task. 2) "Data-centric view" which defines web mining in terms of the types of web data that is being used in the mining process. Mainly web mining is divided into three types: 1) Web Content Mining 2) Web usage mining 3) Web Structure Mining. Web content mining is the process of extracting the useful information from web document. To perform this task there are two main approaches like agent based approach and database approach. Web usage mining is the process of mining the important information from web history. Web usage mining process can be divided into three stages: 1) Pre-processing 2) Pattern discovery 3) Pattern analysis. In preprocessing stage, data is cleaned and partitioned into set of user's transaction that represents the activity of each user during the visiting of different sites. In Pattern discovery stage database, machine learning and statistical operations are performed to obtain the hidden patterns that reflect the behavior of user.</p><p>Pattern analysis: In this, discovered patterns are further processed, filtered and analyses in user model that can be used in model that can be used as input to applications such as visualization tools and report generation tools.</p><p>Web structure mining is very difficult task. It is the process of analyzing the hyperlink and extract important information from it. It is also used to mine the structure of document, analyze the structure of page to describe the HTML or XML usage. The goal of the Web Structure Mining is to generate the structural summary about the Web site and Web page. Web Structure mining will categorize the Web pages and generate the information like the similarity and relationship between different Web sites. This type of mining can be either performed at document level that is referred to as intra-page <ref type="bibr">[11]</ref> or at hyperlink level that referred to as inter-page mining. Due to the importance of this mining technique, there have been several algorithms proposed to solve this. In this paper we will describe and analyze web structure mining algorithms and identify their strengths and limitations.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. In Section II Process of web structure mining is described and several proposed algorithms are introduced. Section III gives the detailed of these algorithms is given. In Section IV we provide a Comparison of the different web structure mining algorithms. In Section V we conclude.</p><p>II. PROCESS OF WEB MINING Web structure mining is also known as "Link Analysis" process. It is an old area of research but with the increasing interest in Web mining, the research of structure analysis had increased and these efforts had resulted in a newly emerging research area called Link Mining. The Web contains a variety of objects with almost no unifying structure, with differences in the style and Content much greater than in traditional collections of text documents. Link mining is divided into four parts and is shown in following figure:  The objects in the WWW are web pages, and links are in-, out-and co-citation i.e. two pages that are both linked to the same page. There are some possible tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[2]</ref> of link mining</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A survey on improving the efficiency of different Web structure Mining Algorithms</head><p>which are applicable in Web structure mining and are described as follows: 1. Link-based Classification: -is the most recent upgrade of a classic data mining task to linked Domains. The task is to focus on the prediction of the category of a web page, based on words that occur on the page, links between pages, anchor text, html tags and other possible attributes found on the web page. 2. Link-based Cluster Analysis. The goal in cluster analysis is to find naturally occurring sub-classes. The data is segmented into groups, where similar objects are grouped together, and dissimilar objects are grouped into different groups. Different than the previous task, link-based cluster analysis is unsupervised and can be used to discover hidden patterns from data. 3. Link Type. There are a wide range of tasks concerning the prediction of the existence of links, such as predicting the type of link between two entities, or predicting the purpose of a link. 4. Link Strength. Links could be associated with weights. 5. Link Cardinality. The main task here is to predict the number of links between objects. There are some uses of web structure mining like it is: ? Used to rank the user's query ? Deciding what page will be added to the collection ? page categorization ? finding related pages ? finding duplicated web sites ? and also to find out similarity between them Many authors have proposed web structure mining algorithms like: Pagerank algorithm, weighted pagerank algorithm, Hyper Induced Topic search algorithm, weighted Topic sensitive pagerank algorithm. In next section we will explain these algorithms in detail.</p><p>quite less than because it uses only one parameter i.e. backlink.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Hits</head><p>This algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> was given by Kleinberg in 1997. According to this algorithm first step is to collect the root set. That root set hits from the search engine. Then the next step is to construct the base set that includes the entire page that points to that root set. The size should be in between 1000-5000. Third step is to construct the focused graph that includes graph structure of the base set. It deletes the intrinsic link, (the link between the same domains). Then it iteratively computes the hub and authority scores. In HITS concept, he identifies two kinds of pages from the Web hyperlink structure: authorities (pages with good sources of content) and hubs (pages with good sources of links). For a given query, HITS will find authorities and hubs. According to him, A good hub is a page that points to many good authorities; a Good authority is a page that is pointed to by many good hubs". Although HITS provides good search results for a wide range of queries, HITS did not work well in all cases due to the following three reasons: 1 Mutually reinforced relationships between hosts. Sometimes a set of documents on one host point to a single document on a second host, or sometimes a single document on one host point to a set of document on a second host.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Automatically generated links. Web document generated by tools often have links that were inserted by the tool. 3. Non-relevant nodes. Sometimes pages point to other pages with no relevance to the query topic</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Weighted pagerank algorithms [6]:</head><p>III. PURPOSED ALGORITHMS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Pagerank algorithm</head><p>Pagerank algorithm is link analysis algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref> that was discovered by Larry page. This algorithm is used by Google internet search engine. In this algorithm numerical weight is assigned to each element of hyperlink set of document such as World Wide Web, with the purpose of measuring the relative importance of that particular set in that hyperlink. Pagerank is a probability distribution algorithm used to represent the person's randomly clicking on links will arrive at any particular page. A probability is expressed as a numeric value between 0 and 1. That numerical value is defined as damping factor. It is represented as d and usually its value set to be 0.85. Also C (A) is the number of link going out of that particular page and is known as backlink. Pagerank of any page is calculated by: PR (A) = (1-d) + d (PR (T1)/C (T1) + ... + PR (Tn)/C (Tn)) (1) Where PR (A) is pagerank of particular web page A D is damping factor. PR (T1) is page link with main page PR (A) C is outlink Note that the rank of a page is divided evenly among it's out-links to contribute to the ranks of the pages they point to. Page Rank can be calculated using a simple iterative algorithm, and corresponds to the principal Eigen vector of the normalized link matrix of the web. Page Rank algorithm needs a few hours to calculate the rank of millions of pages. However this algorithm is not so efficient its efficiency is Wenpu Xing and Ali Ghorbani proposed a Weighted Pagerank algorithm which is an extension of the Pagerank algorithm. This algorithm assigns a larger rank values to the more important pages rather than Dividing the rank value of page evenly among its outgoing linked pages, each outgoing link gets a value proportional to its importance. In this algorithm weight is assigned to both backlink and forward link. Incoming link is defined as number of link points to that particular page and outgoing link is defined as number of links goes out. This algorithm is more efficient than pagerank algorithm because it uses two parameters i.e. backlink and forward link. The popularity from the number of in links and out links is recorded as Win and Wout respectively. Win (v, u) is the weight of link (v, u) calculated based on the number of in links of page u and the number of in links of all reference pages of page v.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Weighted page content rank algorithm:</head><p>Weighted Page Content Rank Algorithm (WPCR) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref> is a proposed page ranking algorithm which is used to give a sorted order to the web pages returned by a search engine in response to a user query. WPCR is a numerical value based on which the web pages are given an order. This algorithm employs web structure mining as well as web content mining techniques. Web structure mining is used to calculate the importance of the page and web content mining is used to find how much relevant a page is? Importance here means the popularity of the page i.e. how many pages are pointing to or are referred by this particular page. It can be calculated based on the number of in links and out links of the page. Relevancy means matching of the page with the fired query. If a page is maximally matched to the query,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>International Journal of Engineering and Advanced Technology (IJEAT) ISSN: 2249 -8958, Volume-2, Issue-3, February 2013</head><p>that becomes more relevant. This algorithm is better than the pagerank as well as weighted pagerank algorithm because its complexity is less than both the algorithm and is &lt; (Ologn).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. CONCLUSION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E. Topic sensitive pagerank algorithm [5]:</head><p>In this algorithm, different scores are computed, multiple important scores for each page under several topics that form a composite Pagerank score for those pages matching the query. At query time, the similarity of the query is compared to each of these vectors or topics; and subsequently, instead of using a single global ranking vector, the linear combination of the topic-sensitive vectors is weighed using the similarity of the query to the topics. This method yields a very accurate set of results relevant to the context of the particular query. For each web document query sensitive importance score. The results are ranked according to this composite score . It provides a scalable approach for search rankings using Link analysis. For each Web page, compute an importance score per topic. At query time, these importance scores are combined based on the topics of the query and associated context to form a composite Pagerank score for those pages matching the query. This score can be used in conjunction with other scoring schemes to produce a final rank for the result pages with respect to the query. This algorithm will improve the order of web pages in the result list so that user may get the relevant pages easily.</p><p>This paper described several purposed web structure mining algorithms like pagerank algorithm, weighted pagerank algorithm, weighted content pagerank algorithm (WCPR), HITS etc. We analyzed their strengths and limitations and provide comparison among them. So we can say that this paper may be used as a reference by researchers when deciding which algorithm is suitable. We also try to overcome from the problem that particular algorithms have.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. ACKNOWLDGMENT</head><p>No volume of words is enough to express my gratitude towards my guide Mr. Md. Ataullah, Department of computer science &amp; Engineering, Lovely professional university, phagwara. He has helped me to explore this broad area in organized manner and provide me with the all the ideas on how to work towards research oriented venture. I would also like to thank my all lecturers and my friends who were always there at the need of the hour and provided with all the help and facilities. Most importantly I would like to thanks my parents to show me a right direction that helps me to stay calm in oddest of the times.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Manuscript received on February 2013. Preeti chopra,</head><label></label><figDesc>M.Tech (cse), Department of computer science and Engineering. Lovely professional university, Phagwara, Punjab, India. Md. Ataullah: Assistant Professor, Lovely professional university, Phagwara, Punjab, India.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig 1: types of web structure mining The objects in the WWW are web pages, and links are in-, out-and co-citation i.e. two pages that are both linked to the same page. There are some possible tasks [2] of link mining</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">it is concluded that each algorithm has some relative strengths and limitations. A tabular summary is given below in table 1, which summarizes the techniques, Advantages and limitations of some of important web page ranking algorithms</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web Mining Research: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kosala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Blockeel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGKDD Explorations</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Link-based classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICML-03</title>
		<meeting>ICML-03</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The pagerank citation ranking: Bringing order to the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Winograd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Stanford Digital Libraries SIDL-WP-1999-0120</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web mining in soft computing framework: Relevance, state of the art and future directions IEEE Trans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Talwar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1163" to="1177" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Effective algorithm for web mining based on Topic sensitive pagerank algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mishra Shesh Narayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International journal of computer science and software engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weighted Pagerank Algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenpu</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Ghorbani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">proceedings of the 2rd Annual Conference on Communication Networks &amp; Services Research</title>
		<meeting>the 2rd Annual Conference on Communication Networks &amp; Services Research</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="314" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Link analysis algorithm for web mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhatia</forename><surname>Tamanna</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International journal of computer science and software engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="976" to="8491" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of Link Algorithms for Web Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Munibalaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Balamurugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Engineering and Innovative Technology (IJEIT)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Syntactic Classification based Web Page Ranking Algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mukhopadhyay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">6th International Workshop on MSPT Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
