<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview</head><p>(1) Small-world networks and decentralized search Stylized models expose basic patterns. Identifying the patterns in large-scale data.</p><p>(2) A problem that is less well understood at a large scale:</p><p>diffusion and cascading behavior in social networks</p><p>The way in which new practices, ideas, and behaviors spread through social networks like epidemics. Models from discrete probability, data from on-line communities, open questions in relating them.</p><p>(3) Privacy and anonymity in on-line data.</p><p>The perils in using anonymized social network data. Attacks on anonymized networks using small identifiable subgraphs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Small-World Networks</head><p>Milgram's small-world experiment <ref type="bibr">(1967)</ref> Choose a target in Boston, starters in Nebraska.</p><p>A letter begins at each starter, must be passed between personal acquaintances until target is reached. Six steps on average ?¡ú six degrees of separation.</p><p>Routing in a (social) network: When is local information sufficient? <ref type="bibr">[Kleinberg 2000]</ref> Variation on network model of <ref type="bibr">Watts and Strogatz [1998]</ref>.</p><p>Add edges to lattice: u links to v with probability d(u, v ) ?¦Á . In HP Labs, groups defined by sub-trees of hierarchy. Links scaled as g ?3/4 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Network Data</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Geographic Data: LiveJournal</head><p>Liben-Nowell, Kumar, Novak, Raghavan, Tomkins (2005) studied LiveJournal, an on-line blogging community with friendship links.</p><p>Large-scale social network with geographical embedding: 500,000 members with U.S. Zip codes, 4 million links.</p><p>Analyzed how friendship probability decreases with distance.</p><p>Difficulty: non-uniform population density makes simple lattice models hard to apply. Rank-based friendship: rank of w with respect to v is number of people</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">x such that d(v , x) &lt; d(v , w ).</formula><p>Decentralized search with (essentially) arbitrary population density, when link probability proportional to rank Generalization of lattice result (diff. from set systems).</p><p>Punchline: LiveJournal friendships approximate 1/rank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Jon Kleinberg Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</head><p>LiveJournal: Rank-Based Friendship Generalization of lattice result (diff. from set systems).</p><p>Punchline: LiveJournal friendships approximate 1/rank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diffusion Curves</head><p>Basis for models: Probability of adopting new behavior depends on number of friends who have adopted. <ref type="bibr">Bass 1969;</ref><ref type="bibr">Granovetter 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr">Schelling 1978</ref> Prob. of adoption  If we can "seed" the new behavior at k nodes, and want to maximize the eventual spread, whom should we choose?</p><p>Computational complexity depends on diffusion curves. Highly inapproximable with critical mass. With diminishing returns: constant-factor approximation <ref type="bibr">[Kempe-Kleinberg-Tardos 2003</ref><ref type="bibr">, 2005</ref><ref type="bibr">Mossel-Roch 2007]</ref> Jon Kleinberg Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diffusion Curves</head><p>Probability of joining a community when k friends are already members </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Specifics of the Attack</head><p>First version of the attack: Create H on (2 + ¦Å) log n nodes. Can compromise ¦¨(log 2 n) targeted nodes. In experiments on 4.4 million-node LiveJournal graph, 7-node graph H can compromise 70 targeted nodes (and hence ? 2400 edge relations). Second version of the attack:</p><p>Create H on c ¡Ì log n nodes. Can compromise ( 1 2 ? ¦Å)c ¡Ì log n targeted nodes. Reconstruct from Gomory-Hu tree: break apart G along small cuts; find H as a "contiguous" piece. Passive attacks:</p><p>In LiveJournal graph: with reasonable probability, you and 6 of your friends chosen at random can carry out the first attack, compromising about 10 users.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>Adamic-Adar 2003]: social network on 436 HP Labs researchers. Joined pairs who exchanged ¡Ý 6 e-mails (each way). Compared to "group-based" model [Kleinberg 2001] Probability of link (v , w ) prop. to g (v , w ) ?¦Á , where g (v , w ) is size of smallest group containing v and w . ¦Á = 1 gives optimal search performance.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Rank-based friendship: rank of w with respect to v is number of people x such that d(v , x) &lt; d(v , w ). Decentralized search with (essentially) arbitrary population density, when link probability proportional to rank ?¦Â . (LKNRT'05): Efficient routing when ¦Â = 1, i.e. 1/rank.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Prob. of adoption k = number of friends adopting k = number of friends adopting Key issue: qualitative shape of the diffusion curves. Diminishing returns? Critical mass? From individual-level model, can build network-level model: Run dynamics of contagion forward from initial "seed set." Jon Kleinberg Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Finding</head><label></label><figDesc>the Most Influential Set Prob. of adoption Prob. of adoption k = number of friends adopting k = number of friends adopting An algorithmic question [Domingos-Richardson 2001]:</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot">Jon Kleinberg Algorithmic Models for Social Network Phenomena</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diffusion in Computing and Information</head><p>Diffusion of Topics [Gruhl et al 2004, <ref type="bibr">Adar et al 2004]</ref> News stories cascade through networks of bloggers and media How should we track stories and rank news sources? A taxonomy of sources: discoverers, amplifiers, reshapers, ... </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Building diffusion into the design of social media</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Perils of Anonymized Data</head><p>Can accomplish a lot with public social network data. But many interesting questions arise in private data:</p><p>E.g. E-mail, IM, voice, members-only communities. Standard approach to protecting the data: anonymize, replacing name at each node by a random string. After doing this, is it safe to release?</p><p>With more detailed data, anonymization has run into trouble: But what about just the unlabeled nodes and edges of a social network?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>An Attack</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>100M nodes</head><p>Scenario from Backstrom-Dwork-Kleinberg 2007:</p><p>Suppose a big company were going to release an anonymized</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Perils of Anonymized Data</head><p>What's the conclusion from this? Doesn't apply to social network data that's already public; orthogonal to issues of legal/contractual safeguards.</p><p>But widespread release of an anonymized social network? Danger: you don't what someone's hidden in there. (And passive attacks don't even require advance planning.)</p><p>Interesting direction: privacy-preserving mechanisms for making social network data accessible.</p><p>May be difficult to obfuscate network effectively (e.g. <ref type="bibr">[Dinur-Nissim 2003</ref><ref type="bibr">, Dwork-McSherry-Talwar 2007</ref>) Interactive mechanisms for network data may be possible (e.g. <ref type="bibr">[Dwork-McSherry-Nissim-Smith 2006]</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reflections: Toward a Model of You</head><p>Further direction: from populations to individuals Distributions over millions of people leave open several possibilities:</p><p>Each individual personally follows (a version of) the distribution, or Individual are highly diverse, and the distribution only appears in aggregate</p><p>Recent studies suggests that sometimes the first option may in fact be true. Example: what is the probability that you answer a piece of e-mail t days after receipt (conditioned on answering at all)?</p><p>Recent theories suggest t ?1.5 with exponential cut-off <ref type="bibr">[Barabasi 2005]</ref> Reflections: Interacting in the On-Line World Social networks -implicit for millenia -are increasingly being recorded at arbitrary resolution and browsable in our information systems. Your software has a trace of your activities resolved to the second -and increasingly knows more about your behavior than you do. Trade-offs between rich data and individual privacy will remain an issue. Models based on algorithmic ideas will be crucial in understanding these developments.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
