<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Competitive Influence Maximization in Social Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shishir</forename><surname>Bharathi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mahyar</forename><surname>Salek</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Competitive Influence Maximization in Social Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Social networks often serve as a medium for the diffusion of ideas or innovations. An individual&apos;s decision whether to adopt a product or innovation will be highly dependent on the choices made by the individual&apos;s peers or neighbors in the social network. In this work, we study the game of innovation diffusion with multiple competing innovations such as when multiple companies market competing products using viral marketing. Our first contribution is a natural and mathematically tractable model for the diffusion of multiple innovations in a network. We give a (1?1/e) approximation algorithm for computing the best response to an opponent&apos;s strategy, and prove that the &quot;price of competition&quot; of this game is at most 2. We also discuss &quot;first mover&quot; strategies which try to maximize the expected diffusion against perfect competition. Finally , we give an FPTAS for the problem of maximizing the influence of a single player when the underlying graph is a tree.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Social networks are graphs of individuals and their relationships, such as friendships, collaborations, or advice seeking relationships. In deciding whether to adopt an innovation (such as a political idea or product), individuals will frequently be influenced, explicitly or implicitly, by their social contacts. In order to effectively employ viral marketing <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2]</ref>, i.e., marketing via "word-of-mouth" recommendations, it is thus essential for companies to identify "opinion leaders" to target, in the hopes that influencing them will lead to a large cascade of further recommendations. More formally, the influence maximization problem is the following: Given a probabilistic model for influence, determine a set A of k individuals yielding the largest expected cascade. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> The formalization of influence maximization as an optimization problem is due to Domingos and Richardson <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, who modeled influence by an arbitrary Markov random field, and gave heuristics for maximization. The first provable approximation guarantees are given in <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we extend past work by focusing on the case when multiple innovations are competing within a social network. This scenario will frequently arise in the real world: multiple companies with comparable products will vie for sales with competing word-of-mouth cascades; similarly, many innovations face active opposition also spreading by word of mouth. We propose a natural generalization of the independent cascade model <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> to multiple competing influences (see Section 2 for details). Our model extends Hotelling's model of competition <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, and is related to competitive facility location and Voronoi games <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>. We first study second-mover strategies and equilibria of the resulting activation game and show that: Theorem 1. The last agent i to commit to a set S i for initial activation can efficiently find a (1 ? 1/e) approximation to the optimal S i .</p><p>Theorem 2. The price of competition of the game (resulting from lack of coordination among the agents) is at most a factor of 2.</p><p>We analyze good first-mover strategies for the two-player game in Section 4, and give exact algorithms for simple special cases. Finally, we give an FPTAS for maximizing the influence of a single player on bidirected trees, even when the edges in opposite directions have different probabilities. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref> proved that the general version of influence maximization is NP-complete, and we conjecture it is so even for arborescences directed into a root.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Models and Preliminaries</head><p>The social network is represented as a directed graph G = (V, E). Following the independent cascade model <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>, each edge e = (u, v) ¡Ê E has an activation probability p e . Each node can be either inactive or active; in the latter case, it is assigned a color denoting the influence for which it is active (intuitively, the product that the node has adopted). To avoid tie-breaking for simultaneous activation attempts by multiple neighbors, we augment the model by a notion of activation time for each activation attempt. When node u becomes active at time t, it attempts to activate each currently inactive neighbor v. If the activation attempt from u on v succeeds, v will become active, of the same color as u, at time t + T uv , where the T uv are independent and exponentially distributed continuous random variables. Subsequently, v will try to activate inactive neighbors, and so forth. Thus, a node always has the color of the first neighbor succeeding in activating it.</p><p>In the influence maximization game, each of b players selects a set S i of at most k i nodes. A node selected by multiple players will take the color of one of the players uniformly at random. Then, with S i being active for influence i, the process unfolds as described above until no new activations occur. Letting T 1 , . . . , T b be the active sets at that point, the goal of each player i is to maximize E [|T i |]. Player i is indifferent between strategies S i and S ¡ä i if their expected gain is the same. In particular, the game is thus not a zero-sum game. Simple examples show that in general, this game has no pure strategy Nash Equilibria; however, it does have mixed-strategy Nash Equilibria.</p><p>In order to gain a better understanding of the influence maximization game, we first focus on best response strategies for players.</p><p>Lemma 1. Suppose that the strategies S j , j = i for other players are fixed. Then, player i's payoff E [|T i | | S 1 , . . . , S b ] from the strategy S i is a monotone and submodular function of S i .</p><p>Proof. We obtain a deterministic equivalent of the activation process by choosing independently if each edge e = (u, v) will constitute a successful activation attempt by u on v (a biased coin flip with probability p e ), as well as the activation time T e , beforehand. Then, we consider running the (now deterministic) activation process using these outcomes and delays.</p><p>If node u has color j, and activates node v successfully, we color the edge (u, v) with color j. A path P is called a color-j path if all its edges have color j. Then, a node u ends up colored with color j iff there is a color-j path from some node in S j to u.</p><p>Conditioned on any outcome of all random choices as well as all S j , j = i, the set of nodes reachable along color-i paths from S i is the union of all nodes reachable from any one node of S i . Thus, if S i ? S ¡ä i , the set of nodes reachable from S i + v, but not from S i , is a superset of those reachable from S ¡ä i + v, but not from S ¡ä i (by monotonicity). Thus, given fixed outcomes of all random choices and S j , j = i, the number of nodes reachable from S i is a monotone and submodular function of S i . Being a non-negative linear combination of submodular functions (with coefficients equal to the probabilities of the outcomes of the random choices), the objective function of player i is thus also monotone and submodular.</p><p>The above lemma implies that for the last player to commit to a strategy, the greedy algorithm of iteratively adding a node with largest marginal gain is within a factor (1 ? 1/e) of the best response (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>), thus proving Theorem 1. Second, as the expected total number of active nodes at the end is also a monotone submodular function of S := j S j , the game meets the requirements of a valid utility system as defined by Vetta <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. We can apply Theorem 3.4 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> to obtain that the expected total number of nodes activated in any Nash Equilibrium is at least half the number activated by the best solution with a single player controlling all of the i b i initial activations. This proves Theorem 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">First Mover Strategies</head><p>We now consider first mover strategies in a duopoly, with 2 players called "red" and "blue". The following variant of the competitive influence maximization problem is motivated by its similarity both to the case of multiple disjoint directed lines (discussed briefly below) and to a fair division problem: Given n lines of lengths ? 1 , . . . , ? n , the red player first gets to make any k cuts, creating k + n pieces whose lengths sum up to the original lengths. The blue player picks the k largest segments ("blue pieces") and the red player gets the next-largest min(n, k) segments ("red pieces").</p><p>Assume for now that we know a "cutoff point" c such that all blue pieces have size at least c, and all red pieces have size at most c. <ref type="figure">Let F (i, r, b, c)</ref> denote the maximum total size of r red pieces in the i th line and G(i, r, b, c) the maximum total size of r red pieces over the first i lines. Then, we obtain the following recurrence relation, which turns into a dynamic program in the standard way.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">G(i, r, b, c) = max r ¡ä =0...r max b ¡ä =0...b F (i, r ¡ä , b ¡ä (r ¡ä ), c) + G(i ? 1, r ? r ¡ä , b ? b ¡ä (r ¡ä ), c)</formula><p>The main issue is then to reduce the number of candidates for the cutoff point c to a strongly polynomial number. The following lemma shows that we only need to try out nk candidate values ? i /j, i = 1, . . . , n, j = 1, . . . , k for c (retaining the best solution found by the dynamic program), making the algorithm strongly polynomial.</p><p>Lemma 2. The optimal solution cuts each line segment into equal-sized pieces.</p><p>Proof. First, we can remove unused line segments from the problem instance. Second, partially used line segments can be converted to completely used line segments by adding the unused part to an existing blue segment (if it exists) or to an existing red segment (if no blue piece exists). The latter may entice the blue player to take a red piece. But this frees up a formerly blue piece (of size at least c) to be picked up by the red player.</p><p>W.l.o.g., all pieces of the same color on a line segment are of the same size. If the optimal solution contains an unevenly cut line with red and blue pieces, we increase the sizes of all red pieces and decrease the sizes of all blue pieces until the line is cut evenly. As before, the red player's gain cannot be reduced by the blue player switching to a different piece, because any new piece the red player may obtain after the blue player switches will have size at least c.</p><p>The above algorithm can be extended to deal with directed lines and even outdirected arborescences. In the former case, the slight difference is that the "leftmost" piece of any line is not available to the red player. These extensions are deferred to the full version due to space constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Influence Maximization on Bidirected Trees</head><p>While the single-player influence maximization problem is APX-hard in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, special cases of graph structures are more amenable to approximation. Here, we will give an FPTAS for the influence maximization problem for bi-directed trees. (This FPTAS can be extended to bounded treewidth graphs with a significant increase in complexity.) Given a target ¦Å, we will give a 1 ? ¦Å approximation based on a combination of dynamic programming and rounding of probabilities.</p><p>For the subtree rooted at node v, let G(v, k, q + , q ? ) denote the expected number of nodes that will be activated by an optimum strategy, provided that (1) v is activated by its parent with probability at most q ? , and (2) v has to be activated by its subtree with probability at least q + . Let v be a node of degree d with children v 1 , . . . v d . Then, for the respective subproblems, we can choose arbitrary k 1 , . . . , k d , q <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> or <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> is satisfied, we call the values consistent. For consistent values, the optimum can be characterized as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">+ ? ? 1 , . . . , q + d , q 1 , . . . , q d , such that (1) i k i = k, q + ¡Ü 1? i (1?q + ? i p vi,v ) and q i ¡Ü p v,vi (1?(1?q ? ) j =i (1? q + ? j p vj ,v )) if v is selected, or (2) i k i = k ? 1, q + ¡Ü 1 and q i ¡Ü p v,vi if v is not selected. If</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">m G(v, k, q + , q ? ) = max G(v i , k i , q + ? i ) + 1 ? (1 ? q + )(1 ? q ? ). (1) (ki),(q + ? i , q i ),(q i ) i=1</formula><p>As discussed above, the maximum is over both the case that v is selected, and that it is not. It can be computed via a nested dynamic program over the values of i. In this form, G(v, k, q + , q ? ) may have to be calculated for exponentially many values of q + and q ? . To deal with this problem, we define ¦Ä = ¦Å/n 3 , and compute (and store) the values G(v, k, q + , q ? ) only for q + and q ? which are multiples of ¦Ä between 0 and 1. The number of computed entries is then polynomial in n and 1/¦Å. Let G ¡ä (v, k, q + , q ? ) denote the gain obtained by the best consistent solution to the rounding version of the dynamic program, and ?q? ¦Ä the value of q rounded down to the nearest multiple of ¦Ä. Then, for the rounding version, we have Theorem 3. For all v, k, q + , q ? , there exists a value r + ¡Ü q + with q</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">+ ? r + ¡Ü ¦Ä|T v |, such that G(v, k, q + , q ? ) ? G ¡ä (v, k, r + , ?q ? ? ¦Ä ) ¡Ü ¦Ä|T v | 3 ,</formula><p>where |T v | is the number of nodes in the subtree rooted at v.</p><p>Applying the theorem at the root of the tree, we obtain that the rounding dynamic program will find a solution differing from the optimum by at most an additive ¦Än 3 ¡Ü ¦Å ¡Ü ¦Å ¡¤ OPT, proving that the algorithm is an FPTAS.</p><p>Proof. We will prove the theorem by induction on the tree structure. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>It clearly holds for all leaves, by choosing r + = ?q + ? ¦Ä . Let v be an internal node of degree d, with children v 1 , . . . , v d . Let (k i ), (q + ? i ), (q i ) be the arguments for the optimum subproblems of G(v, k, q + , q ? ). By induction hypothesis, applied to each of the subtrees, there are values r + + + + i ¡Ü q i with q i ? r i ¡Ü ¦Ä|T vi |, such that G(v i , k i , q + ? + ? i , q i ) ? G ¡ä (v i , k i , r i , ?q i ? ¦Ä ) ¡Ü ¦Ä|T vi | 3 . Define r + := ?1 ? i (1 ? r + i p vi,v )? ¦Ä , (or r + = 1, if the optimum solution included node v). By definition, r + is consistent with the r + i . Using Lemma 4 below and the inductive guarantee on the r + i values, we obtain directly that q + ? r + ¡Ü ¦Ä|T v | (where we used the fact that i |T vi | + 1 = |T v |). Next, we define r ? + i = ?p v,vi (1 ? (1 ? ?q ? ? ¦Ä ) j =i (1 ? r j p vj ,v ))? ¦Ä for all i. Again, the r ? i are consistent by definition, and by using the inductively guaranteed bounds on q + + ? ? j ? r j as well as Lemma 4, we obtain that q i ? r i ¡Ü ¦Ä(|T v | + 1) for all i.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining the network value of customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 7th KDD</title>
		<meeting>7th KDD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Talk of the network: A complex systems look at the underlying process of word-of-mouth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence in a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 9th KDD</title>
		<meeting>9th KDD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influential nodes in a diffusion model for social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 32nd ICALP</title>
		<meeting>32nd ICALP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the submodularity of influence in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mossel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Roch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 38th ACM STOC</title>
		<meeting>38th ACM STOC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability in competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hotelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive facility location along a highway</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Cheong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Golin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Oostrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computing and Combinatorics : 7th Annual International Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Guilin, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="246" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The one-round voronoi game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Cheong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Har-Peled</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Linial</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Matou?ek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Discrete And Computational Geometry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of the approximations for maximizing submodular set functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nemhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wolsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nash equlibria in competitive societies with applications to facility location, traffic routing and auctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vetta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 43rd IEEE FOCS</title>
		<meeting>43rd IEEE FOCS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="425" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
