<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Complex System Classification</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>20 June -24 June 2004</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Magee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>De Weck</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Room</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>E60-275 77 Massachusetts Avenue Cambridge</addrLine>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Room</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>33-410 77 Massachusetts Avenue Cambridge</addrLine>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Complex System Classification</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">20 June -24 June 2004</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Fourteenth Annual International Symposium of the International Council On Systems Engineering (INCOSE)</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The use of terms such as &quot;Engineering Systems&quot;, &quot;System of systems&quot; and others have been coming into greater use over the past decade to denote systems of importance but with implied higher complexity than for the term systems alone. This paper searches for a useful taxonomy or classification scheme for complex Systems. There are two aspects to this problem: 1) distinguishing between Engineering Systems (the term we use) and other Systems, and 2) differentiating among Engineering Systems. Engineering Systems are found to be differentiated from other complex systems by being human-designed and having both significant human complexity as well as significant technical complexity. As far as differentiating among various engineering systems, it is suggested that functional type is the most useful attribute for classification differentiation. Information, energy, value and mass acted upon by various processes are the foundation concepts underlying the technical types.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>There are three inter-related reasons for attempting a classification study of complex systems. First, academic activity indicates interest in forming a field of study and by analogy with other fields, a classification framework has often been a major step forward, and a significant accelerator of development of the field. Second, the development of a framework for classification of complex systems may help delineate the "intellectual boundaries" of engineering systems. The differentiation of ES from other complex systems is most important to fulfill this purpose. Such delineation is significant academically to differentiate Systems (or Engineering Systems) from traditional engineering departments, business schools and other areas while recognizing that such boundaries will be open and blurred as are those defining other fields. The third, and perhaps most important, reason for attempting to classify complex systems is to contribute to the engineering and design of such systems. Achievement of this goal could be facilitated by differentiation between different classes of ES. As the modern world relentlessly evolves towards a highly interactive and interdependent complex set of complex systems, improvement of the ability to design such systems is becoming crucial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Approach</head><p>The first step in this study was to develop a "test bed" list of complex systems. The second step was to use the list to assess the utility of prior classification frameworks, and then to extend them and develop new ones. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows schematically the overall approach. Observation of existing ES</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1. Approach for finding a classification of Engineering Systems</head><p>In order to explore promising classification schemes for Engineering Systems, a topdown and a bottom-up strategy were simultaneously pursued. The top-down strategy consisted of surveying past suggestions for a classification of complex Engineering Systems, generically considering the attributes of Engineering Systems and the kinds of processes that they are involved in, as well as suggesting a meaningful classification scheme based on systems theory. The bottom-up approach consists of qualitatively and quantitatively assessing a wide variety of system attributes for each entry in the test bed list of Engineering Systems to learn about the systems.</p><p>A set of criteria for determining whether a given classification framework is useful has been developed in order to evaluate possible classification frameworks. The first criterion is that the framework be able to differentiate among systems on our list and separate them into distinct groupings. In addition, valuable classification schemes would help by defining categories where different engineering methods and approaches are most useful. A useful framework would also possibly help define potential fundamental issues and principles of importance in various categories suggested by the framework. Finally, a useful scheme might suggest the most viable modeling and representation techniques to apply in different categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Selected Specific Engineering Systems</head><p>The need for a "test bed" set of engineering systems led first to finding (not surprisingly) that no list was known. Since the approach described in the previous section involves actual "bottom-up" observation of engineering systems (as well as application of "topdown" theory and speculation), specific instances of engineering systems are required. In this regard, the prior argument of Miller <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Miller, 1986)</ref> that concrete examples of complex systems are necessary in order to support the development of quantitative approaches is also relevant. Such a specific list culled from an earlier and longer list (Magee and <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">de Weck, 2002</ref>) is given in <ref type="table">Table I</ref> which also contains specific complex systems judged not to be Engineering Systems. Focus on specific instances sharpened the decision process on inclusion whereas generic concepts are suggestions for a possible category in a classification framework. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> above, systems not designed by humans are labeled "natural," and are not included in the ES list-the first sorting principle. However, some of these systems are interesting for comparison in "bottom-up" observations as they may give valuable insight to different categories and strategies for Engineering Systems. In addition, a number of the specific Engineering Systems included in the list incorporate natural "components or subsystems".</p><p>The second and third sorting principles demonstrated in <ref type="table">Table I</ref> are the technical complexity and human complexity (management or social dimension) of the system. For each instance to be specific enough to examine these points, the system boundaries must be defined. In general for this list, all software, artifacts, natural "components", processes, personnel and organizations involved in delivering the product, purpose or service of the system is included. In entries listed "as a system" (e.g., the Boeing 777 example), the named systems only include the software, hardware, and procedures used in the actual product. For many of these same items, if one includes the development teams that design the product and/or the manufacturing systems that make it, the entries would move from the right hand column to left hand one in <ref type="table">Table I</ref>. This is demonstrated by the two different entries for the Intel Pentium V. The "Intel Pentium V System" includes the development Organizations and Manufacturing Plants, personnel, and processes as "components" whereas the "Intel Pentium V as a system" does not.</p><p>Many systems are unambiguously separated into Engineering Systems or "other interesting Systems" using this framework. The entries in the ES list typically contain many thousands of non-repeating artifact, process or algorithm components as well as several multi-level human organizations as "components". Many of the entries in the Other Interesting Systems list are not human designed and the remainder typically has either very low technical or organizational/social complexity.</p><p>It is also now possible to recognize areas where this differentiation is controversial. A single airplane with a pilot is not an engineering system by this framework because of the lack of the organizational or social component/complexity. However, with a very complex airplane many may disagree. Similarly, we assume that use of a complex technical system (such as information systems, weapon systems etc.) without an organizational responsibility for development or production of the system does not impart sufficient technical complexity to consider complex systems such as an Air Force Command System or the Boston Public Library to be engineering systems. Thus, one could make a third list in addition to the binary pair shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> with the third category containing controversial systems. However, such considerations are not further addressed here as they do not affect the further use of the test bed for the purposes of the remainder of this paper. An important point, however, is to recognize that a system can always be viewed as a subsystem from a higher level so that most of the examples in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> can be further expanded or contracted but in keeping with the spirit of this paper remain engineering systems only if sufficient technical and social complexity is retained in a system created by human activity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification Frameworks</head><p>Top-Down Frameworks In this section, the "test bed"-the ES systems list presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>-is used to assess various classification frameworks using the criteria outlined previously. The frameworks of potential interest come largely from past work generally starting with the General Systems Theory ideas of the 1950's (W. Ashby 1963), (Bertalanffy 1968), <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Boulding 1953</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Boulding , 1956</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Boulding , 1956a</ref>), (Hubka, Eder 1988), (Froncois 1997).</p><p>The first system classification scheme is due to Bertalanffy (Bertalanffy 1968) who extended Boulding's work <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Boulding 1953</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Boulding , 1956</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Boulding , 1956a</ref>). These frameworks were suggested as part of their efforts on "General System Theories" in the 1950's. The list as presented by Bertalanffy had a strong orientation towards his discipline of biology, and is summarized in the left side of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> below. Miller <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Miller, 1986)</ref> later described various levels of living systems and this is shown on the right hand side of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. In each of these lists, each successive item increases in complexity, and to some degree incorporates the preceding entries. In addition, Bertalanffy suggests the "theories and models" useful in each level of his hierarchy. Although this is the kind of utility desired, both of these frameworks fail the first criterion as they do not differentiate among the systems of interest. All of the "test bed systems" are similar combinations of the last three levels in both hierarchies and then only if we assume complex human-designed systems are included in these categories.</p><p>A second early framework was proposed by Paynter (Paynter 1960) where he considered four system types:</p><p>1. Services and utilities-water supply, electric power generation, communication 2. Structures-buildings, houses, bridges 3. Instruments-clocks, computers 4. Vehicles-submarines, aircraft, spacecraft, ships, automobiles</p><p>It is clear from this that Paynter was interested in a very broad range of systems. Although some of the systems listed in <ref type="table">Table I</ref> can be fit into his scheme, most are poorly described by the categories and most are simultaneously in two or more of the categories. Moreover, inclusion of manufacturing systems, product development systems and markets in <ref type="table">Table I</ref> (sometimes as "components") indicates-not surprisingly-that Paynter was also not considering Engineering Systems as broadly as defined here.</p><p>A third more fully developed approach from within the European Systems Engineering tradition is due to V. Hubka <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Hubka, Eder 1988)</ref>. Hubka considers a variety of possible bases for classification including function, branch of the economy, type of operand, physical principles of importance, product use, production method, materials, etc. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  2</ref> shows Hubka's overall depiction of Technical Processes, the environment and the human along with the "Technical System". All of his classification discussion focuses on the Technical System. This framework therefore also fails our first criterion as it does not differentiate among or really address our systems of interest-all have significant interwoven technical and human/social complexity. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STS SHu SEnv</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bottom Up Analysis</head><p>In summary, prior classification schemes did not consider ES by the definition in this paper and also fail to usefully separate them from one another. Nonetheless, many prior suggestions of attributes of systems can be used to examine (bottom-up) if these attributes can be a basis for useful characterization and classification.</p><p>The attributes considered are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>, along with the literature sources suggesting the importance of the attribute. The third column in the table gives the basis for the qualitative assessment used in characterizing the test bed list. These are further defined in the legend starting below <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3 which incorporates Tables 4-8</ref>. See <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> Branch of Economy (Hubka, Eder 1988) See <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref> Realm  <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wyk 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">Wyk , 1988a</ref>) See <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref> Legend for <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>: Degree of Complexity: Complexity is related to the amount of information needed to describe the system <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kolmogorov, 1983)</ref> and is also a function of the number of (unique) elements in the system as well as the number and nature of their interconnections. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> shows the specific comparator adopted here. By this measuring scale, all ES in the test bed list turn out to be at the highest complexity (level IV) which confirms that our list as intended addresses complex systems. Branch of Economy: what part of the economic system does the ES belong to? <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref> shows the breakdown adopted here.  Realm of Existence: is the system only present in "thought" or does it manifest itself in the physical world, i.e. in some way connected to matter or energy? (All of the test bed list of ES are real, i.e., have physical aspects.) Origin: is the system naturally occurring without human intervention or is its existence the result of a deliberate or accidental process involving human design and implementation? (All ES are artificial, that is, involve human intervention.)</p><note type="other">Branch of Economy Equipment for Typical Machine Mining Accessing Delivering Preparing Cutting machine Conveyor Screening machine Energy generation Steam raising Electric generating Steam boiler Water conditioner Steam turbine Gas turbine Water turbine Generator Smelting Pig iron smelting Steel smelting Blast furnace Bessemer converter LD oxygen processor Rolling mill Chemical industry Coal scrubbing Color producing Explosives</note><p>Boundary: is there any exchange of matter, energy, or information across the system boundary? (All ES are open.)</p><p>Time Dependence: is the system time invariant, i.e. do any of the system's states change with time or do any of the system's properties change with time?</p><p>The system is time varying if some system properties or system elements or interrelationships change over time System States: are the system states continuous (e.g. temperature) or are they discrete (e.g. "on" or "off") or a mix of both (hybrid)? Few system modeling techniques are good for hybrid systems, usually one finds techniques for dealing with continuous systems or finite state machines ("automata"). (All ES are hybrid.) Human Involvement/System Control: some systems require constant involvement of a human operator, autonomous systems do not need human operators or guidance during operations, mixed systems have elements at least partially controlled by humans and autonomous elements. (All ES are mixed.) Human Wants: On the highest level, the purpose of all engineering is to fulfill human wants so all engineering systems have been designed (over a complex series of designs and redesign that resemble evolution) to fulfill human wants.</p><p>The system attribute associated with this is defined by the Human Wants categories shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 6</ref>. , where q is the state vector. The system is considered time-invariant as long as the entries in the matrices A, B, C, D are constant. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> is the ownership or control of the specific system in question. This attribute is given in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>, where six classes of ownership/control are defined.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ownership: a further attribute of the Engineering Systems in</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 7. Ownership/Control Attribute of Engineering Systems</head><p>SFP: Single, private, for-profit ownership and control of the system MFP: Multiple, private, for-profit entities in control SNFP: Single, not-for-profit controller MNFP Multiple not-for-profit control GOV: Governmental control COMB: Complex combinations of 1 through 5</p><p>Functional Type: a potentially important classification scheme is due to <ref type="bibr">Pahl and Beitz (Pahl, Beitz 1996)</ref>, Hubka (Hubka, Eder 1988) and van <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wyk (van Wyk 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">,1988a</ref>). An example of classification by functional types due to van Wyk is shown below in <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref>. It is a three-by-three matrix consisting of 3 outputs (or operands) and three "types" of manipulators. From the analysis just completed, seven of the eleven attributes in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> are useful in the characterization of ES (differentiation from other systems) but not in classification (differentiation among ES). All ES are complex, real, open, artificial, dynamic, hybrid (system states are both continuous and discrete) and have mixed control (have both autonomous and human-in-the-loop elements or subsystems). It is suggested that these characteristics can serve to strengthen our definition and understanding of Engineering Systems.</p><p>From the same analysis, there remain 4 attributes which differ among the ES in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> and these will be explored individually starting in the next paragraph. However, it is important to recognize that all four attributes (Human Wants, Functional Type, Economy Branch and ownership) essentially involve external descriptors of the systems rather than internal differentiators. The possible internal differentiators such as complexity and system states are -at least in the metrics used here-indistinguishable. This largely arises because of the current limitations in quantifying such internal variables for specific ES (see Magee and <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">de Weck, 2002</ref> for preliminary attempts) and may also arise due to the recursive nature of the systems concept preventing meaningful differentiation among systems that have similar internal features. <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref> shows the ES from <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> listed according to the four attributes that give some differentiation. In <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref>, the ES are shown separated according to Human Wants (given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 6</ref>) as it comes closest to being able to pass the first criteria of differentiating among the ES. Hubka's somewhat similar grouping <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">(Table 5)</ref> is not as effective partly because it does not consider service as opposed to manufacturing industries and does not cover all human wants as demonstrated in the large number of cases in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref> with no Economy Branch . The ownership differentiation is also fairly strong but is shown simply as an additional attribute. The separation by Human Wants still leaves a significant number of systems classified as for multiple human Wants. Among those classified, the largest groupings are for Transportation, Communication, Security and Health. In the multiple use category, many of the systems are markets, software, and other IT tools, all of which support meeting multiple human needs. <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref> shows van Wyk's nine categories from <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref> for each system in the second column. We should note that almost all of the ES transform, transport and store energy to some extent (all information is accompanied by at least a minimum amount of energy). In addition, almost all also process (transform), and store information. Thus, in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref>column 2, the essential functional categories are identified and listed. The essential functions are those necessary to serve the basic human need(s). For more than 1/2 of the ES, a single essential function can be identified. However, for a large number there seem to be at least two major functional types that describe the Engineering System. For some very complex systems such as the Tokyo Metropolitan Area and the U.S. Aerospace Industry, at least three functional types describe the system basic functions.</p><p>Despite these difficulties, Functional Type as originally expounded by Hubka, Pahl and Beitz, and van Wyk appears to be the only technical attribute able to differentiate among ES. Moreover, it is the only one of the 4 "differentiating attributes" that can go beyond the first criteria for assessing usefulness of classification schemes. Differences in modeling and important differences in modularity and other design characteristics are suggested for functional types by the work of Whitney ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Whitney 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Whitney ,2002</ref>) who has shown some significant distinctions between systems that have either information or energy as their major operand.</p><p>Thus, functional type appears useful for classification. However, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref>, the systems are not simply separated by this attribute. This is partly because the ES come from a broader and larger-scale set of systems than those originally of interest to van Wyk. The ultimate ambition is to find a complete set of functions, i.e. an essential set that is sufficient to describe any Engineering System. An initial attempt is made here by first broadening the list of manipulators beyond the three in <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref> to include market and control systems. In addition, the three outputs are also broadened to include value (or money). Thus, following Object Process Methodology (Dori 2001), we have the following operators on objects:</p><p>-Transformation Systems (1): transform objects into new objects -Distribution Systems (2): provide transportation, i.e. change the location of objects -Storage Systems (3): act as buffers in the network and hold/house objects over time -Market Systems (4): allow for the exchange of objects mainly via the Value layer -Control Systems (5): seek to drive objects from some actual state to a desired state</p><p>We distinguish the following operands:</p><p>-Matter (M) physical objects, including organisms that exist unconditionally -Energy (E): Stored work that can be used to power a process in the future -Information (I): Anything that can be considered an informational object -Value (Monetary) (V): Monetary and intrinsic value object used for exchange This Object Process Model thus effectively expands the classification scheme of <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref> to that shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 10</ref>. In this expanded 5 x 4 classification matrix, selected complex systems from the test bed list <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 1)</ref> are assigned to a particular cell of this Engineering Systems Classification Matrix. <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">(Table 8)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 10: Complex Systems Classification MatrixThe gray shaded area corresponds to original matrix according to van Wyk</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Process/Operand</head><p>Matter (M)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Energy (E) Information (I) Value (V) Federal Reserve(T)</formula><p>The entries in the columns of the first row of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 10</ref> correspond to the primary operand classes that an Engineering System can operate on. An operand is the object that is being affected or that results from the primary process that is enabled by the Engineering System. Examples of operands for the four classes are:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Matter:</head><p>packages, vehicles, crude oil, animals, plants, water, memorabilia Energy:</p><p>potential, electrical, kinetic, thermal, nuclear Information: news reports, email, TV shows, voice conversations, books (content), bits Value: stocks, bonds, cash, inventory, loans, credit, currencies, options</p><p>Use of this expanded matrix introduces tighter definitions but more categories (20 vs. 9) than by following <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 8</ref>. The benefit of doing so is demonstrated by the single entry in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 10</ref> for the Health Care System of France vs. the three functional type entries listed for this ES in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 9</ref>. However, such reductions are not general and for systems such as the Tokyo Metropolitan Area and China's Three Gorge Dam, multi-functional classification is probably inescapable.</p><p>The object-process view of Engineering Systems raises a number of questions. One is whether the set of proposed fundamental functions is complete and unique. The examples in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 10</ref> seem to indicate the usefulness of the set, but cannot prove its exhaustiveness. Another valid issue is how this view ties back to the fulfillment of human wants and needs. Each of the Engineering Systems has a particular purpose and helps meet human wants and needs in concert with other Engineering Systems. The functional classification is fundamentally a separate model and is potentially useful in describing (and designing) systems having a variety of purposes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Concluding Remarks</head><p>This paper has reviewed a number of proposed classification schemes from the literature and has attempted to assess their applicability to a test bed list of Engineering Systems. We have augmented the proposed classification schemes using object-process methodology to essentially extend the functional type classification schemes originally suggested by others <ref type="bibr">(Pahl, Beitz 1996)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Hubka, Eder 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">) and (van Wyk 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">, 1988a</ref>. Fundamentally this corresponds to a functional classification of Engineering Systems by specifying the operand on which they primarily operate as well as their function with that operand.</p><p>There are three additional issues about which further discussion and work will be valuable. The first is the question of agreement as to the difference between Engineering Systems (or other special complex systems such as "Systems of systems") and other complex systems. In this paper, it is suggested that the three attributes that make systems "Engineering Systems" are: human designed for a purpose, high degree of human complexity and a high technical complexity. All of these criteria are in agreement with the specific systems considered in this paper but a wider consensus would be valuable in improving communication about this important subject. An alternative has not been suggested that is capable of delineating these fields because of the multi-faceted and quantification difficulties associated with complexity.</p><p>The second issue involves the clarification of all significant system attributes. This paper has shown that classification of Engineering Systems only makes sense if we consider specific system attributes. There are potentially many more attributes of systems than were discussed in this paper. Work will have to be done to see if any other attributes of Engineering Systems are considered to be important. A logical area for fruitful interaction would be economic classification schemes such as standard industrial classification (NAIC).</p><p>The third issue that particularly needs work if substantial progress is to made in understanding engineering systems is quantitative systems analysis. In order to determine the actual usefulness of the functional classification suggested here, extensive study of quantitative attributes is needed. Such quantification has occurred for all successful classification schemes. Mendeleyev measured atomic masses and counted valence electrons, Linnaeus measured animal sizes, catalogued their anatomical features and assembled them into species, Ashby (Ashby, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jones 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jones 1986</ref>) made various cross-plots of material properties such as density, elastic modulus, strength, cost, and particularly ratios of material properties which allow clear classification of complex material systems. Such an approach and its potential value for engineering systems was outlined in the previous paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Magee and de Weck, 2002</ref>). However, obtaining sufficient data to begin to mimic for engineering systems the classification approach for materials properties awaits much further definitional and other measurement work. Many years and numerous contributors did this important kind of quantification and measurement work before the key contribution of Ashby and Jones could be useful.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Hubka's depiction of a complex Technical System (¡ÆTS ) as interacting with a technical process (TP) which turns inputs (¡ÆOd1) into outputs (¡ÆOd2). The environment (¡ÆEnv) and humans (¡ÆHu) are not integrated with the Technical System and the Technical Process (Hubka, Eder 1988) signifying an approach not consistent with engineering systems as defined in this paper.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>(All ES are dynamic.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 1 . Engineering Systems Distinguished From Other Systems</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Complex Systems Considered Engineering 
Systems 

Other Complex Systems 

ES 

Legend: 
N = Natural Systems 
T = Insufficient Technical Complexity 
H = Insufficient Human Complexity 

? Airbus 318-321 Airplane Family System 
? AT&amp;T Telecommunication Network 
? Automotive Products and Plants of Toyota Motor 
Company System 
? Big Dig (central Artery Project, Boston) 
? Boeing Supply Chain System 
? Boeing-777 Aircraft System 
? China's Three-Gorge Dam 
? Chinese "People" Air Transport System (PRC) 

? AIDS activist health care system/ prevention 
system (T) 
? Amazon basin ecosystem (N) 
? Atomic Energy Commission (?) 
? Andromeda galaxy (N) 
? Ant Colony (N) 
? Arms Control Negotiation and Treaty System(T,) 
? ASME JOURNALS Academic peer review 
system (T) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 2 . Some Early Classification of Systems</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bertalanffy 1968 
Miller 1986 
Static Structures 
Cells 

Clock Works 
Organs 

Control Mechanisms 
Organisms 

Open Systems 
Group 

Lower Organisms 
Organization 

Animals 
Society 

Man 
Supra-national System 

Socio-cultural Systems 

Symbolic Systems 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 . System Attributes of Potential Use in Qualitative Assessment of the ES Testbed List</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Attributes 
Reference(s) 
Specific Qualitative Scale 

Degree of 
Complexity 

(Hubka, Eder 1988), (Haberfellner et al. 1992) 
(Pahl, Beitz 1996) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Technical Systems Classified by Degree of Complexity 
(from Theory of Technical Systems) (Hubka, Eder 1988): 

Level of 
Complexity 

Technical 
System 

Characteristics 
Examples 

I (simplest) Part, Component 
Elementary system produced without 
assembly operations 

Bolt, bearing sleeve, 
spring, washer 
II 
Group, 
mechanism, 
Sub-assembly 

Simple system that can fulfill some higher 
functions 

Gear box, hydraulic 
drive, spindle head, 
brake unit, shaft coupling 
III 
Machine, 
Apparatus, 
Device 

System that consists of sub-assembles and 
parts that perform a closed function 

Lathe, motor vehicle, 
electric motor 

IV 
Plant, 
Equipment, 
Complex 
machine unit 

Complicated system that fulfills a number 
of functions and that consists of machines, 
groups and parts that constitute a functional 
and spatial unity 

Hardening plant, 
machining transfer line, 
factory equipment 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 . Branch of Economy attribute defined by Examples of Technical Systems (from Theory of Technical Systems) (Hubka, Eder 1988):</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Technical System TS 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>producing</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Pressure vessel 
Piping 
Distillation column 
Metalworking industry 
Chipless-forming 

Chip-forming 
Heat treatment 
Foundry 
Assembly 

Press 
Forging hammer 
Machine tool 
Furnace 
Forming machine 
Jigs and fixtures 
Constructional industry 
Oil exploration 
Building 
Roadworks 
Hydro-construction 
Materials manufacture 

Drill rig 
Personnel lift 
Scraper 
Concrete mixer 
Block press 
Transportation 
Railway 

Shipping 
Space travel 

Locomotive 
Wagon 
Passenger liner 
Rocket 
Textile Industry 
Textile manufacture 

Dressmaking 

Spinning machine 
Weaving loom 
Sewing machine 
Food Industry 
Sugar refining 
Cheese production 
Milk processing 

Concentrator 
Press 
Centrifuge 
Medicine 
Diagnosis 
Therapy 

X-ray apparatus 
Artificial heart 
Prosthesis 
Printing, offices 
Printing 
Office work 

Printing machine 
Typewriter 
Calculator 
Agriculture 
Transporting 
Harvesting 
Lumbering 

Tractor 
Combine 
Chain saw 
Distribution, trade 
Self-service 
Packing 

Check-out 
Wrapping machine 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="true"><head>Table 6 . Categories of Human Wants</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Shelter 
Food 
Transportation 
Communication 
Security 
Longevity and health 
Entertainment 
Aesthetic pleasure 
Education 
Social, Emotional, Spiritual &amp; Curiosity 

3 For example in a mathematical linear state space system the system dynamics are represented as 

and 
q Aq Bu 
y Cq Du 
= 
+ 
= 
+ 
&amp; 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="true"><head>Table 8 . van Wyk's Table of Functional Types</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Type of Manipulator 
Output 

Processor (1) 
Transporter (2) 
Store (3) 

Matter (M) 
Cement kiln 
Truck 
Silo 

Energy (E) 
Power plant 
Copper cable 
Battery 

Information (I) 
Computer 
Optic fiber 
Compact disk 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="true"><head>Table 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Engineering Systems Grouped According to Basic Human Wants 
(assessed according to the qualitative Attributes in Table 3) 

Attributes 
Functional Types 
Owner 
Economy branch 

Shelter 
Tokyo Metropolitan Area 
ALL 
COMB 
All 
Pilgrim Nuclear Power Plant 
E1 
SFP 
Energy generation 
U.S. Power Grid System 
E2 
COMB 
Energy 

Food 
Hudson River Watershed Water Supply System M3,M2 
COMB 
Food, energy 
U.S. Agricultural Food Production and 
Distribution System 

M1 
COMB 
Food 

Transportation 
Airbus 318-321 Airplane Family System 
M1,I1 
SFP 
Transportation 
Boeing Supply Chain System 
M1,I1 
MFP 
Transportation 
Automotive Products and Plants of Toyota 
Motor Company System 

M1,I1 
SFP 
Transportation 

Big Dig (central Artery Project, Boston) 
M2,M1 
GOV 
Transportation 
Chinese "People" Air Transport System (PRC) 
M2 
GOV 
Transportation 
European Union Roadway System 
M2 
COMB 
Transportation 
FAA/IATA Certification System 
I1 
GOV 
Transportation 
Exxon Mobil Fossil Fuel Drilling, Refining and 
Distribution System 

E1,E2 
SFP 
Transportation 

General Motors (GM) Supply Chain 
M1,I1 
SFP 
Transportation 
Global Air Traffic Control System 
I1,I2, 
GOV 
Transportation 
Mexico City Transportation System 
M2 
COMB 
Transportation 
New York City Subway System 
M2 
GOV 
Transportation 
Pratt and Whitney Gas Turbine Family System 
E1 
SFP 
Transportation 
U.S. Aerospace Industry 
M1,I1 
COMB 
Transportation 
Boeing-777 Aircraft System 
M1,I1 
SFP 
Transportation 

Communication 
AT&amp;T Telecommunication Network 
I2, 
SFP 
none 
Global Satellite Launching System 
M2 
COMB 
none 
Global Wireless Communication System 
I2 
COMB 
none 
Global Internet 
I2 
COMB 
none 
Reuters Global News Distribution Service 
I2,I1 
SFP 
none 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Professor of the Practice, Engineering Systems Division and Mechanical Engineering, Center for Innovation in Product Development 2 Assistant Professor, Engineering Systems Division, Department of Aeronautics and Astronautics</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Biographies</head><p>Professor Christopher L. Magee has been with MIT since January 2002 as a Professor of the Practice in the Engineering Systems Division and Mechanical Engineering. He also directs a multidisciplinary research center (Center for Innovation in Product Development). Before Dr. Magee joined MIT, he had more than 35 years of experience at Ford Motor Company beginning in the Scientific Research Laboratory and progressing through a series of management positions to Executive Director of Programs and Advanced Engineering. Prof. Magee is currently engaged in research and teaching relative to complex system design. Prof. Magee is a member of the National Academy of Engineering, a fellow of ASM and SAE and a participant on major National Research Council Studies. Dr. Magee is a native of Pittsburgh, PA and received his B.S. and Ph.D from Carnegie-Mellon University in that city. He later received an MBA from Michigan State University.</p><p>Professor Olivier L. de Weck is the Robert N. Noyce Assistant Professor of Aeronautics and Astronautics and Engineering Systems at MIT. His research interests are in Multidisciplinary Design Optimization (MDO) and System Architecture. He investigates the benefits of optimization during early conceptual design and the relationship between performance and cost with system lifecycle properties (extensibility, reconfigurability, diversifiability). His applications of interest are in aerospace, automotive and communications systems. Prof. de Weck has been at MIT since 1997, where he obtained S.M. (1999) and <ref type="bibr">Ph.D. (2001)</ref> degrees in Aerospace Systems. He holds a graduate engineering degree in Industrial Engineering (1993) from ETH Zurich, Switzerland, where he was born. Before coming to MIT, Prof. de Weck worked as a liaison engineer and as Engineering Program Manager on the F/A-18 aircraft program at McDonnell Douglas (now Boeing) from 1991-1996.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">City Police (T,)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Central Nervous System (N) ? Earth Climate System(N) ? Ebay trading system (T) ? Embryonic Stem Cell (N) ? Federal Reserve System</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>T</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">?</forename><surname>Gre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Graduate Record Examination) System (T) ? Human (homo sapiens) (N) ? Human Brain (N) ? Intel Pentium V as a system ? International Police</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Interpol) (T</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">? Kidney/Urinary Tract System (N) ? Microorganism (Bacterium) (N) ? Milky Way (N)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">?</forename><surname>Mit Engineering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Systems Learning Center (T) ? Name Tracking of Terrorism Attack Casualties</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>T,H</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">? NASA Deep Space Network (DSN)(H)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">? NASDAQ Trading System (T)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">? Nba (</forename><surname>Nfl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nhl</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">MLB) sports system (T) ? Olympic Competition System (T) ?</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Planet Earth, Planet Mars (N)</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">? Wright Brothers Wind</forename><surname>Tunnel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MIT Aero-Astro</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R H</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Engineering Materials, Part</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<publisher>Pergamon Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Introduction to Cybernetics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ashby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bertalanffy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">General System Theory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>George Braziller, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Organization Revolution: A Study in The Ethics of Economic Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Boulding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1953" />
			<publisher>Harper</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">General Systems Theory -The Skeleton of Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Boulding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">General Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">I</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a General Theory of Growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Boulding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">General Systems, I</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Crawley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>De Weck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>16.882/ESD</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">34J course on System Architecture</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>MIT</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Object-Process-Methodology (OPM)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Appendix A: ESD Terms and Definitions (Version 13)</title>
		<ptr target="http://esd.mit.edu/WPS/ESDInternalSymposiumDocs/ESD-WP-2003-01.20-ESDInternalSymposium.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ESD Symposium Committee Overview</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-05" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Engineering Systems Division, MIT</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Saur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">International Encyclopedia of Systems and Cybernetics</title>
		<editor>C. Francois</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Munich</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Hubka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Eder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of Technical Systems</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Haberfellner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Von</forename><surname>B¨¹chel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Massow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Verlag Industrielle Organisation</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Z¨¹rich</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Daenzer and Huber &quot;Systems Engineering-Methodik und Praxis</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Combinatorial Foundations of Information Theory and the Calculus of Probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Kolmogorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Russian Mathematical Surveys</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Attempt at Complex System Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Magee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>De Weck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Symposium Docs/ESD-WP-2003-01.02-ESD Internal Symposium.pdf</idno>
		<ptr target="http://esd.mit.edu/WPS/ESDInternal" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ESD Internal Symposium</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Magee, de Weck</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can Systems Theory Generate Testable Hypothesis?: From Talcott Parsons to Living Systems Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Engineering Design -A systematic Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Beitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Spinger</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2 nd Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis and Design of Engineering Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Paynter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Class Notes for MIT Course 2.751</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Panamoric Scanning and the Technological Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Wyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Technovation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">121</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Standard Framework for Product Protocols</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Wyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Management of Technology</title>
		<editor>T. Khalil</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Geneva</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Management of Technology: new frameworks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Wyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="351" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technovation</note>
	<note>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Why Mechanical Design Cannot Be Like VLSI Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Whitney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://web.mit.edu/ctpid/www/Whitney/papers.html#P1" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Physical Limits to Modularity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Whitney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://esd.mit.edu/WPS/ESDInternalSymposiumDocs/ESD-WP-2003-01.03-ESDInternalSymposium.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MIT website</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
