<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:51+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DRIMUX: Dynamic Rumor Influence Minimization with User Experience in Social Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Biao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>xwang8@sjtu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Jiao Tong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Jiao Tong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luoyi</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Jiao Tong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Jiao Tong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinbing</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xue</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>xueliu@cs.mcgill.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electronic Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Jiao Tong University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">McGill University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DRIMUX: Dynamic Rumor Influence Minimization with User Experience in Social Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Rumor blocking is a serious problem in large-scale social networks. Malicious rumors could cause chaos in society and hence need to be blocked as soon as possible after being detected. In this paper, we propose a model of dynamic rumor influence minimization with user experience (DRIMUX). Our goal is to minimize the influence of the rumor (i.e., the number of users that have accepted and sent the rumor) by blocking a certain subset of nodes. A dynamic Ising propagation model considering both the global popularity and individual attraction of the rumor is presented based on realistic scenario. In addition, different from existing problems of influence minimization, we take into account the constraint of user experience utility. Specifically, each node is assigned a tolerance time threshold. If the blocking time of each user exceeds that threshold, the utility of the network will decrease. Under this constraint, we then formulate the problem as a network inference problem with survival theory, and propose solutions based on maximum likelihood principle. Experiments are implemented based on large-scale real world networks and validate the effectiveness of our method.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>With the soaring development and rising popularity of largescale social networks such as Twitter, Facebook, and Chinese Weibo, etc., hundreds of millions of people are able to share all kinds of information with each other online. On one hand, these online social platforms provide great convenience to the diffusion of positive information such as new ideas, innovations, and hot topics <ref type="bibr">(Montanari and S- aberi 2010)</ref>. On the other hand, however, they may become a channel for the spreading of malicious rumors or misinformation (Budak, Agrawal, and Abbadi 2011). For example, some people may post on social networks a rumor about an upcoming earthquake, which will cause chaos among the crowd and hence may hinder the normal public order. Undoubtedly, these malicious rumors should be stopped as soon as possible once detected so that their negative influence can be minimized.</p><p>Most of the previous works studied the problem of maximizing the influence of positive information through social networks based on the Independent Cascade (IC) model, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Kempe, Kleinberg, and Tardos 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Chen, Wang, and Wang 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Shirazipourazad et al. 2012</ref>). In contrast, the negative influence minimization problem has gained much less attention, but still there have been consistent efforts on designing effective strategies for blocking malicious rumors and minimizing the negative influence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Budak, Agrawal, and Abbadi 2011)</ref> introduced the notion of a "good" campaign in a social network to counteract the negative influence of a "bad" one by convincing users to adopt the "good" one. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Kimura, Saito, and Motoda 2009</ref>) studied the problem of minimizing the propagation of malicious rumors by blocking a limited number of links in a social network. They provided two different definitions of contamination degree and proposed corresponding optimization algorithms. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Fan et al. 2013</ref>) investigated the least cost rumor blocking problem in social networks. They introduced the concept of "protectors" and try to select a minimal number of them to limit the bad influence of rumors by triggering a protection cascade against the rumor cascade. However, there are a few limitations in those works. First, they consider the rumor popularity as constant during the whole propagation process, which is not close to the realistic scenarios. Second, in the design of the rumor blocking strategies, either blocking nodes or links, they fail to take into account the issue of user experience in real world social networks. We have to avoid blocking the users' accounts for such a long time that they may lodge complaints or even quit the social network. Therefore, it is necessary to consider the impact of blocking time on both individual node and the entire network. In this paper, we investigate the problem of dynamic rumor influence minimization with user experience. First, we incorporate the rumor popularity dynamics in diffusion model. We analyze existing investigations on topic propagation dynamics (Yang and Leskovec 2011) and choose Chisquared distribution to approximate the global rumor popularity. Inspired by the novel energy model proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Han et al. 2014</ref>), we then analyze the individual tendency towards the rumor and present the probability of successful rumor propagation between a pair of nodes. Finally, inspired by the concept in Ising model <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chelkak and Smirnov 2012)</ref>, we derive the cooperative succeeding probability of rumor propagation that integrates the global rumor popularity with individual tendency. After that, we introduce the concept of user experience utility function and analyze the impact of blocking time of nodes to the rumor propagation process. We then adopt the survival theory to explain the likelihood of nodes getting activated, and propose both greedy and dynamic algorithms based on maximum likelihood principle.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows: First, we introduce the preliminaries; then we give an overview of the related work; after that, we propose the problem formulation and the solutions; experiments are presented in the following section; and finally, the paper is concluded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Related Work</head><p>Topic Dynamics Preliminaries Social Network Definition A social network, in mathematical context, can be formulated as a directed graph G = (V, E) consisting of a set of nodes V representing the users, and a set of directed edges E denoting the relationship between users (e.g. following or being followed). Let |V | = N denote the number of nodes, and (u, v) ¡Ê E denote the directed edge from node u to node v (u, v ¡Ê V ), and ¦Á uv ¡Ê {0, 1} denote the edge coefficient, where ¦Á uv = 1 represents the existence of edge (u, v), and ¦Á uv = 0, otherwise. We use p uv to denote the probability of u sending the rumor to v and v accepting it, i.e., the success probability of u activating v. Let D(u) denote the in-degree of node u.</p><p>Researchers have studied the temporal dynamics of web topics based on real-world statistics. (Yang and Leskovec 2011) analyzed how the number of tweets related to a specific theme (i.e., the popularity of a topic) changes with time, and revealed that a topic evolution generally consists of three phases, i.e., a rising phase from the start, a peak period and then a fading phase. Fluctuations in each phase may result in different temporal characteristics. (Yang and Leskovec 2011) proposed K-Spectral Centroids clustering algorithm for classifying online content according to their temporal patterns and finally extract six representative patterns from million-scale tweets and blog posts. (Crane and Sornette 2008) demonstrated the existence of Poisson distribution and Power-law relaxation in controlling the topic evolution over time. In our work, we use the Chi-squared distribution to simulate the rumor propagation dynamics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Energy Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diffusion Model</head><p>Diffusion models describe the process of information propagating through the network. Two classic diffusion models are Linear Threshold (LT) and Independent Cascade (IC) model. In LT model, an inactive node u becomes activated if the ratio of its activated parent nodes surpasses a certain predefined threshold 0 &lt; ¦È &lt; 1. Although it indicates a latent tendency of a node becoming activated when its neighbors do, the LT model fails to consider the individual difference of each node in a social network. Therefore, we adopt the more complex IC model in our work.</p><p>The IC model has been widely adopted in information diffusion problems. The whole propagation process proceeds in discrete time steps t 0 , t 1 , t 2 , . . . . Initially, the cascade is triggered by a set of activated nodes, i.e., the seed nodes at t 0 . In our rumor diffusion context, we assume the rumor is started by one source node s in the network, and the other nodes are inactive. We use s u (t) ¡Ê {0, 1} to denote the state of node u at time step t, where s u (t) = 1 represents u is activated and s u (t) = 0, otherwise. For every following time step t ¡Ý 1, each node u which was activated at time step (t ? 1) has a single opportunity to activate any of its currently inactive neighbors v with a success probability p uv . In our context, it means in each time step, any node that has accepted the rumor in previous time step has a chance to let their inactive neighbors accept the rumor. For simplicity, we assume that once a node is activated by the rumor, it will stay activated until the end of the diffusion process.</p><p>( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Han et al. 2014)</ref> proposed a novel energy model to describe the rumor propagation process. They introduce the heat energy calculation formula ?E = cm?T in Physics to analogize the rumor impact. The rumor's influence on individual node is formulated as the amount of accumulated heat energy. Inspired by the simulated annealing algorithm (Bertsimas and Tsitsiklis 1993), they define the rumor's attraction to the nodes as an annealing process. Based on the model, we define the individual tendency with the success activation probability between a pair of nodes</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>User Experience</head><p>User experience is an important factor for various services including social networks. Existing rumor blocking strategies block either nodes (users) or links (connections between users) in social networks to prevent the rumor from further propagation. However, none has analyzed the impact of blocking nodes. Generally speaking, the longer the user is blocked, the less satisfactory the user feels about the social network. Therefore, if the blocked time surpasses a certain threshold, it is possible that the user may quit the social network or at least lodge a complaint to the administrator. (Bhatti, Bouch, and Kuchinsky 2000) analyzed the user-perceived quality in web server design and found that users' tolerance for latency decreases over the duration of interaction with a site. A utility function was presented to measure the customer satisfaction. Inspired by that, in our work, we apply a modified utility function to measure user experience in rumor blocking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rumor Influence Minimization</head><p>Rumor influence minimization addresses the problem of minimizing the propagation effect of undesirable rumors in social networks. It is converse to the classic influence maximization problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Kempe, Kleinberg, and Tardos 2003)</ref>. The rumor influence minimization (RIM) problem has been investigated in different influence diffusion models in social networks. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Fan et al. 2013</ref>) studied the least cost rumor blocking problem in social networks, and introduced the notion of "protectors" to limit the bad influence of rumors by initiating a protector cascade to propagate against the rumor cascade. Greedy algorithm is proposed for both opportunistic and deterministic cascade models. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Kimura, Saito, and Motoda 2009)</ref> proposed the strategy of blocking links instead of nodes in social networks so as to minimize the propagation of malicious rumors. Different contamination minimization problems are defined based on different definitions of contamination degree of a network.</p><p>atmosphere" that could affect the judgements or decisions of users on online social networks.</p><p>According to the Ising model (Chelkak and Smirnov 2012), the "phase transition" of a spin involves both shortrange interaction with its nearest neighbors and long-term system evolution, and is a cooperative result. Inspired by that, we propose the cooperative propagation probability integrating p glb (t; k) with p ind (t) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p uv (t) =¦Â 1 ¡¤ p glb (t; k) + ¦Â 2 ¡¤ p ind (t) (1? k ? t 2 2 =¦Â 1 2 2 ) t k?1 e ¦£( k + ¦Â 2 1 D v p 0 lg(10 + t j ) ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Problem Formulation</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">)</head><p>Dynamic Rumor Propagation with Ising Model <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Kempe, Kleinberg, and Tardos 2003)</ref> considered the success probability p uv as a system parameter and is fixed at the very first beginning of the cascade. However, based on the topic dynamics we discussed in a previous section, at different time steps of the propagation process, a topic can vary dramatically in its popularity. Besides, the rumor attraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Han et al. 2014</ref>) for each individual node u ¡Ê V is also a realistic factor we should take into account. That means the success of rumor propagation between neighbors includes two aspects: first, the activated node u has to be so attracted by the rumor that it will choose to send the rumor to its neighbors; second, one of u's inactive neighbors v decides to accept the rumor. Only after those two steps, can we claim that v is activated. In other words, the success of rumor propagation depends both on the global popularity and the individual tendency of the rumor topic, which can be regarded as a generalized feature of the Ising model. Now we investigate the two steps of a successful rumor propagation. In the first step, at any time stamp t j , u is one of the activated nodes in time stamp (t j ?1). Based on the work in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Han et al. 2014</ref>), we give the modified version of the probability of node u sending the rumor to one of its inactive neighbors v as p where ¦Â 1 , ¦Â 2 ¡Ê (0, 1) are the balance coefficients which satisfy ¦Â 1 + ¦Â 2 = 1.</p><p>Based on this cooperative propagation probability, the probability of node v getting activated at time stamp t j can be given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P r[s v (t j ) = 1] = 1 ? [1 ? s u (t j?1 )p uv (t j )],<label>(4)</label></formula><p>u¡ÊPv where P r <ref type="bibr">[¡¤]</ref> represents probability, and P v represents the parent nodes of v.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>User Experience Utility</head><p>Before giving the concrete algorithm, we first elaborate on the user experience utility function <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bhatti, Bouch, and Kuchinsky 2000)</ref>.</p><p>For simplicity, we assume that all the nodes have the same blocked time threshold T th . In other words, we assume that all users have the same tolerance when being blocked. Under this assumption, we define the user experience utility function as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">N T th ? T b (u) T th ,<label>(5)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">send p0 U b = 1 N u (t j ) = lg(10+tj )</formula><p>, where p 0 is the initial sending probability at time stamp 0. The probability of node v accepting the rumor is also given as p u=1 acc v = 1/D v , where D v is the in-degree of node v. Thus, we give the probability of successful rumor propagation from u to v as where the T th represents the tolerance time threshold, T b (u) is used to record the blocked time of node u in the whole propagation process.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">p ind (t j ) = p send u ¡¤ p acc Objective Formulation v = 1 D v p 0 lg(10 + t j ) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>which can be defined as the individual tendency between different pair of nodes in the network. Now we discuss the global topic popularity of the rumor. As mentioned in related work, the rumor popularity generally includes three phases and approximately subject to the chi square distribution, which is given by Now our goal is to minimize the influence of a rumor as much as possible (e.g. minimize the number of activated nodes at the end of propagation process) under the constraint of user experience utility. We formulate the DRIMUX problem as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">min E[ s v (t th ) ] (1? k ? t 2 2 v¡ÊV (6) p glb (t; k) = 2 2 ) t k?1 e s. t. U b ¡Ý U th , ¦£( k ,<label>(2)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proposed Solutions</head><p>In this section, we analyze the DRIMUX optimization problem from the perspective of a network inference problem with survival theory and then propose the greedy algorithm and dynamic blocking algorithm based on different nodes selection schemes and the maximum likelihood principle.</p><p>where S (t) is the derivative of S(t). Accordingly, we can have</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">S(t) = e ? t 0 ¦Áv(¦Ó |s(¦Ó ))d¦Ó ,<label>(11)</label></formula><p>and for a certain node v, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">F v (t|s(t)) = 1 ? e ? t 0 ¦Áv(¦Ó |s(¦Ó ))d¦Ó .<label>(12)</label></formula><p>Survival Theory</p><p>Based on the survival analysis, we propose an additive survival model where the hazard rate is given by</p><p>In our model, we assume that the rumor has spread for some time, and it is detected at time t 0 by the system. It is also assumed that by time t 0 , there have already been a total number of N 1 activated nodes, and N 2 = N ? N 1 nodes are remain inactive. Let V N1 and V N2 denote the set of activated and inactive nodes at time t 0 respectively. Therefore, from t 0 on, the system can be viewed as N 1 independent cascades propagating through the network, and our goal is to select K nodes and block them so that the final number of activated nodes during the observation time window T can be minimized. Let C = (c 1 , . . . , c N1 ) denote the set of cascades triggered by N 1 activated nodes by time t 0 . A cascade c i ¡Ê C can be represented by a N -dimensional time vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">t ci = (t ¦Á v (t|s(t)) = ¦Á T v s(t) = ¦Á uv p uv (t),<label>(13)</label></formula><p>u:tu&lt;t where ¦Á v = (¦Á uv ), u = 1, 2, . . . , N is a non-negative parameter vector indicating the existence of the edge between node u and v. ¦Á uv = 1 if there is an edge between them; and ¦Á uv = 0, otherwise. We define a coefficient matrix</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">A := [¦Á v ] ¡Ê R N ¡ÁN +</formula><p>to denote the structure of network, and A 0 be the original network coefficient matrix before any nodes are blocked. Then we calculate F v (t|s(t)) as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">? t ¦Áuvpuv(¦Ó )d¦Ó ci ci ci tu u:tu &lt;t 1 , . . . , t N2 ) where t j ¡Ê [t 0 , t 0 + T ] ¡È {¡Þ}, j = 1, 2, . . . , N 2</formula><p>is the activated time of node j in cascade c i . The observation time window T is decided by the user experience utility constraint mentioned in (6), and ¡Þ means the node is not activated until the end of the observation time</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">(t 0 + T ).</formula><p>Here we consider only one cascade and the results can be extended to multiple cascades. Define ¦Á v (t|s(t)) as the hazard rate of node v conditioned on the set of nodes activated by time t. Our goal now is to analyze the impact of the hazard rate of different nodes to the rumor influence minimization problem.</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">F v (t|s(t)) =1 ? e ? t ¦Áuvpuv(¦Ó )d¦Ó =1 ? e u:tu &lt;t tu =1 ? e ?¦Áuv t tu puv(¦Ó )d¦Ó .<label>(14)</label></formula><p>u:tu&lt;t</p><p>Accordingly, we have the likelihood function of the activation of node v, f v (t|s(t)), as following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">?¦Á t f v (t|s(t)) = ¦Á uv p uv (t) e t p )d¦Ó . u:tu&lt;t<label>(15)</label></formula><p>Survival Function First, we introduce the survival function defined as <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Aalen, Borgan, and Gjessing 2008)</ref> S(t) = P r(t &lt; T ),</p><p>where T is the occurrence time of an event of interest, t is some specified time. The survival function represents the probability that the event of interest occurs after the observation "deadline". If we use the terminology "death" to represent the occurrence of the event, we can claim that the target "survives". Then we have the cumulative distribution function F (t):</p><p>Given the activation likelihood of a single inactive node v ¡Ê V N2 , now we consider any number of inactive nodes in a cascade. During the entire observation window T , t ¡ÜT = (t 1 , . . . , t i , . . . , t N |t 0 ¡Ü t i ¡Ü t 0 + T ). We assume that every activation is conditionally independent on activations occurring later given previous activations. Then we can compute the activation likelihood as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">f (t ¡ÜT ; A) = ¦Á uv p uv (t i )¡Á i:ti&lt;T u:tu&lt;ti e ?¦Á t i t p )d¦Ó .<label>(16)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_16">F (t) = P r(T ¡Ü t) = 1 ? S(t).<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Accordingly, the probability density function f (t) is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">f (t) = d dt F (t).<label>(9)</label></formula><p>Hazard Rate The hazard rate which characterizes the instantaneous rate of occurrence of an event is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">¦Á v (t|s(t)) = lim dt¡ú0 P r(t ¡Ü T ¡Ü t + dt|T &gt; t) dt = ? S (t) S(t) ,<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Based on the activation likelihood function, we design the blocking algorithms. First, we choose to select and block all K nodes at the same time t 0 . As is shown in Eq. (16), the activation likelihood of an inactive node v is related to the hazard rate coming from all previously activated nodes. Therefore, the early activated nodes play a significant role in the entire process. Hence, we propose the following greedy algorithm to minimize the influence of the rumor within one time stamp after it is detected. We assume that there are M time steps: t 1 , . . . , t M during the whole observation window T , with each time step lasting T /M . Greedy Algorithm. At time t 0 when we detect the rumor, we immediately select K nodes and block them, trying to minimize the likelihood of nodes getting activated at t 1 . The likelihood of nodes getting activated at time t 1 is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">f (t 1 |s(t 0 )) = ¦Á uv p uv (t 1 )¡Á v¡ÊV N 2 u:tu¡Üt0 e ?¦Á t 1 t p )d¦Ó .<label>(17)</label></formula><p>Correspondingly, the objective function is</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">min A f (t 1 |s(t 0 ))<label>(18)</label></formula><p>s. t. ¦Á uv ¡Ê {0, 1}.</p><p>Then, the greedy algorithm is presented as below:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">Algorithm 1 Greedy Algorithm Input: Initial Edge matrix A 0 . Initialization: V B = ?. for i = 1 to K do u = arg max</formula><p>to block based on the Edge matrix and previously infected nodes; in the next round, we move forward with the rumor diffusion, and then use the updated status to block additional k 2 nodes. The blocking process continues at each following instants until the budget runs out at a moment t n , which can be expressed as n j=1 k j = K. In real implementation, we decrease k j as time goes by, and a practical example is k j = 2 (?j) * K. Instead of blocking K candidates at the moment of detection, as previous static blocking strategies do, this dynamic approach is carried out in a progressive way. The design philosophy is to take advantage of instantaneous information all along the dissemination, since this the activation likelihood of a given moment is a variable which depends on the temporal Edge matrix and previous status. Rather than sparing all the efforts at once, we apply consequent force to block the diffusion of rumors. In this way, the global efficiency outweighs the previous static decisions. </p><formula xml:id="formula_22">A i := A i?1 \u, V B = V B ¡È {u}. end for Output: V B .</formula><p>Dynamic Blocking Algorithm Different from the greedy blocking algorithm, the dynamic blocking algorithm blocks the K nodes in separated steps. In this way, the algorithm is able to capture the dynamic characteristics along rumor propagation. Correspondingly, the likelihood function is given by Dataset: Network extracted from the SinaWeibo, with 23086 nodes, and 183549 edges. Notations: Let N init denote the number of initial nodes at the beginning of the propagation, T start denote the time when the rumor is detected, and B amount represent the amount of nodes to be blocked. All the parameters are selected based on empirical results that approximate the realistic scenario. Three algorithms are presented in the experiments for comparison which are listed as follows:</p><p>? Classic Greedy: Greedy algorithm based on descendant order of nodes degree and is used as the baseline algorithm.</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">f (t j |s(t j?1 )) = ¦Á uv p uv (t j )¡Á v¡ÊV (tj ) u:tu&lt;tj e ?¦Á t j t p )d¦Ó , (19)</formula><p>? Proposed Greedy: the order is determined by the maximum likelihood function. By blocking a node, we can generate a new propagation matrix and reach a new maximum survival likelihood value.</p><p>where V (t j ) represents the set of nodes which remain inactive at time stamp t j . Based on Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_4">(19)</ref>, the algorithm is presented as following:</p><p>? Dynamic Algorithm: This algorithm adjusts to each propagation status, and gradually includes new targeted nodes as long as the cost is within the scope of tolerable user experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 2 Dynamic Blocking Algorithm</head><formula xml:id="formula_24">Input: Initial Edge matrix A 0 . Initialization: V B (t) = ?. for j = 1 to n do for i = 1 to k j do ? f = f (t j |s(t j?1 ); A i?1 )?f (t j |s(t j?1 ); A i?1 \v), u = arg max v¡ÊV {? f }, A i := A i?1 \u, V B (t j ) = V B (t j ) ¡È {u}. end for end for Output: V B (t).</formula><p>The dynamic blocking algorithm runs as follows: at the very first stage of blocking, we select a number k 1 nodes In order to simulate a real-scenario dissemination process, we assign several nodes as rumor initiators at the beginning. After a certain period of natural propagation, the rumor is detected by the system and thus we launch our blocking strategy. The vertical dashed line in every figure marks the debut of blockage on potential nodes.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref>, each selected node is blocked for a predefined constant period of time T b . We repeat the propagation process for 1000 times and take the average value as the general feature. The black curve stands for Classic Greedy, blue one for Proposed Greedy, and finally red for Dynamic Blocking Algorithm. Obviously, the propagation rate is decreased to different degrees after the introduction of blockage. As previewed, according to eventual infection range, the dynamic algorithm performs the best among these strategies, since the propagation range is minimized at the end of   propagation under this schema. In the following is our proposed maximum likelihood greedy algorithm, which blocks all candidates at once and use a metric different from traditional approach. The dynamic property is revealed from the early stage of rumor blocking. In detail, during the period <ref type="bibr">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr">25]</ref>, the blue curve lies under the red one, which indicates the slower propagation rate for the static schema. This can be explained by the fact that the dynamic algorithm does block fewer nodes than the static ones at the first moment. After certain moments (about 25 iterations), the blue curve overpasses the red because the dynamic strategy constantly introduce new seeds for blocking. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> and 3 illustrate the blocking efficiency under different costs, i.e., the number of nodes that could be blocked. It is shown that when the investment is abundant, and we have enough nodes to block under certain circumstances, the advantage of our proposed dynamic strategy becomes more obvious since the subsequent efforts on blockage are increased and thus more powerful in dealing with variances. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> is generated using the dynamic blocking algorithm and reflects the effect of different block durations on rumor propagation range, i.e., the infection ratio at the end of the propagation. As is shown in the figure, the longer a node is blocked, the slower the rumor propagates. This benefit, however, is obtained at the expense of declined user experience. The result helps us to analyze the possibility of achieving close performance with less cost. It is also noticeable that this result is coherent to our analysis on User Experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we investigate the rumor blocking problem in social networks. We propose the dynamic rumor influence minimization with user experience model to formulate the problem. A dynamic rumor diffusion model incorporating both global rumor popularity and individual tendency is presented based on the Ising model. Then we introduce the concept of user experience utility and propose a modified version of utility function to measure the relationship between the utility and blocking time. After that, we use the survival theory to analyze the likelihood of nodes getting activated under the constraint of user experience utility. Greedy algorithm and a dynamic blocking algorithm are proposed to solve the optimization problem based on different nodes selection strategies. Experiments implemented on real world social networks show the efficacy of our method. In our future work, we plan to assign different blocked time thresholds to different nodes and design the corresponding blocking strategies. We will also verify our algorithms on multiple datasets.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Copyright c 2016 ,</head><label>2016</label><figDesc>Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (www.aaai.org). All rights reserved.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Experiments v¡ÊV [f (t 1 |s(t 0 ); A i?1 )?f (t 1 |s(t 0 ); A i?1 \v)]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Rumor infection ratio varies along time with N init = 54, T start = 12, and B amount = 64.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :Figure 2 :</head><label>32</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Rumor infection ratio varies along time with N init = 32, T start = 12, and B amount = 64.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Rumor infection ratio varies along time with different block durations using dynamic blocking algorithm.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> ) where k &gt; 0 represents the degree of freedom, ¦£(¡¤) is the Gamma function. It explains a common social phenomenon that when a rumor spreads for a while, it may create a &quot;rumor where t th represents the time instant when the user experience utility U b just triggers the threshold T th , and it determines the observation time window T that we are going to discuss in the following section.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blocking links to minimize contamination spread in a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kimura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Saito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Motoda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transaction on Knowledge Discovery from Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The spread of innovations in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montanari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Saberi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>PNAS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20196" to="20201" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence propagation in adversarial setting: How to defeat competition with least amount of investment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shirazipourazad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bogard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Vachhani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patterns of temporal variation in online media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Minig</title>
		<meeting>ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Minig</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>This work was partially supported by NSF China (No. 61532012</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Survival and event history analysis: a process point of view</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Aalen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">?</forename><surname>Borgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Gjessing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simulated annealing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bertsimas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tsitsiklis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bhatti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bouch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kuchinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limiting the spread of misinformation in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Budak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Abbadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th International World Wide Web Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 20th International World Wide Web Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="665" to="674" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universality in the 2d ising model and conformal invariance of fermionic observables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chelkak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smirnov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inventiones mathmaticae</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">189</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="515" to="580" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable influence maximization for prevalent viral marketing in large-scale social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1038" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust dynamic classes revealed by measuring the response function of a social system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Crane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sornette</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15649" to="15653" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Least cost rumor blocking in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thuraisingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="540" to="549" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy model for rumor propagation on social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zhuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Ao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications</title>
		<meeting>Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 9th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1175" to="1180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
