<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:53+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Fuzzy Influence Diagrams: An Alternative Approach to Decision Making Under Uncertainty</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright IEEE</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-10-20">Retrieved on: 20 October 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mateou</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hadjiprokopis</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Andreou</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">AUTHORS, INCLUDING</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cyprus University of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Cyprus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>75 Kallipoleos str</addrLine>
									<postCode>CY1678</postCode>
									<settlement>Nicosia</settlement>
									<country key="CY">Cyprus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cyprus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>75 Kallipoleos str</addrLine>
									<postCode>CY1678</postCode>
									<settlement>Nicosia</settlement>
									<country key="CY">Cyprus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cyprus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>75 Kallipoleos str</addrLine>
									<postCode>CY1678</postCode>
									<settlement>Nicosia</settlement>
									<country key="CY">Cyprus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Fuzzy Influence Diagrams: An Alternative Approach to Decision Making Under Uncertainty</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">International Conference on Computational Intelligence for Modelling, Control and Automation and International Conference on Intelligent Agents, Web Technologies and Internet Commerce (CIMCA-IAWTIC&apos;06)</title>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
							<date type="published" when="2015-10-20">Retrieved on: 20 October 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/cimca.2005.1631242</idno>
					<note>See discussions, stats, and author profiles for this publication at: http://www.researchgate.net/publication/221216532 CONFERENCE PAPER ¡¤ JANUARY 2005 148 PUBLICATIONS 731 CITATIONS SEE PROFILE Available from: Andreas Andreou</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper proposes a strategic management methodology using Influence Diagrams to represent and model decision problems. While Decision Trees have been extensively used for this purpose and are still highly useful, Fuzzy Influence Diagrams, a new representation for decision problems, outperform them in many respects. This paper describes influence diagrams, proposes their extension via fuzzy logic and demonstrates their use in crisis management and decision making. Simulation experiments using the proposed Fuzzy Influence Diagrams indicate specific conditions and constraints that enable political analysts and decision makers to set targets and plan their actions on a prediction basis.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>This paper is about the role of Influence Diagrams (ID) in strategic management as an effective means to represent decision problems. It is important to realize that formally representing a decision problem is a task that reflects someone's perception of the world. The best-known representation language for decision problems is the decision tree <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[5]</ref>. Nevertheless, decision trees present several significant drawbacks in the decision process, especially when it comes to modelling problems with uncertainty.</p><p>Decision Trees often do not allow independent relations to be exploited due to the fact that they are highly symmetric structures and take little or no advantage of independence among variables. Large decision problems usually require a highly redundant tree representation, introducing asymmetries to correct this inefficiency, something which finally leads to significant loss of information <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[3]</ref>.</p><p>Influence diagrams have significant theoretical and practical advantages over decision trees. In addition to representing probabilistic independence effectively, IDs enforce a clear distinction between informational and probabilistic relationships and prevent loss of information from asymmetries as they grow linearly.</p><p>What we propose in this paper is a combination of Fuzzy Logic and Influence Diagrams so as to create hybrid models that emulate reasoning and decision making using fuzzy causal relationships. The flexibility of such models is improved by using a different kind of fuzzy reasoning known as scalable monotonic chaining <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4]</ref>. Using this technique we manage to overcome problems and difficulties associated with probabilities, which rise up in crisis management: How to represent problems expressed by such factors that cannot be assigned numerical values or expressed with probabilities. In addition, a large ID with numerous nodes and arrows produces a high number of combinations among the possible values of its nodes. As a result, the effort and time spent to assign probabilities to all possible outcomes of each node is huge. Our proposition aspires to eliminate the aforementioned difficulties and expand the areas of ID usage.</p><p>A Fuzzy Influence Diagram (FID), as proposed in this work, is different from an ID in that the possible values of each node are not expressed as probabilities. An FID with n children nodes employs n+ 1 fuzzy set and m parent nodes. One of those, node F, serves as a fuzzificator and converts the current node's possible input values to fuzzy values via its membership function <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>. Then, for each of the children nodes there is a fuzzy set G i which represents the way the current node influences the given child node.</p><p>The use of fuzzy sets eliminates the dependence on probabilistic contribution. In our scheme the influence of each parent node to a certain child is weighted by the set of the m scalars using a technique called hedges <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>. The output to the i th child node is produced by the combination of F and G i using scalable monotonic chaining <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4]</ref>, which will be described later on.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organized as follows: Section 2 provides a brief description of the theoretical background of Influence Diagrams. The different steps needed for the development of Fuzzy Influence Diagrams are given in section 3, which also describes how the FID works. A case study related to the Imia Crisis is presented in section 4, which serves as the empirical verification of our proposition. Finally, section 5 draws the conclusions and suggests further research steps. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Background Theory</head><p>The theory of ID was developed recently <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref> as an extension of Decision Trees used for planning and making decisions in the fields of medicine <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref>, economics, etc. For example, there is a set of decision making problems where it is difficult to quantify the probability contribution of each factor (node) of the model. In a typical crisis management problem, such as the 1967 Cuban Missile Crisis, it is extremely difficult to estimate the probability of USA attacking Cuba.</p><p>An ID is a graph composed of nodes and edges, the former introducing the qualitative concepts of the analysis, while the latter indicates the various causal relationships. Each concept node possesses a numeric state which denotes the qualitative measure of its presence in the conceptual domain. In general, an ID is a single-connected, directed, acyclic graph, representing a decision problem. The ID essentially models the subjective beliefs, preferences and available actions from the perspective of a single decision maker or group of decision makers and experts <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>.</p><p>An example of an ID is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">figure 1</ref>. The nodes of the system and the weighted arrows are set to specific values based on the knowledge and beliefs of experts. Some nodes are more important than others, while they influence more the value of their direct children nodes and less their indirect ones. The same applies for most of the nodes in an ID, especially if the problem modeled is quite complex.</p><p>There are three kinds of nodes and two kinds of arrows in an ID. The first type of node is called the chance node and it represents random variables that cannot be controlled by the decision maker. Chance nodes are often depicted as circles. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">figure 1</ref> nodes K, L, X, Y and Z are chance nodes. The second type of node is the decision node which represents the mutually exclusive actions the decision maker can take. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">figure  1</ref>, nodes D and B are decision nodes, depicted as squares.</p><p>The third and last type of node is called the value node and it represents the decision maker's preferences in the form of a value function. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">figure 1</ref> node V is the value node, depicted as a hexagon.</p><p>Arrows or edges in an ID represent the dependencies among its nodes. However, arrows have a different meaning and do not represent the same relation as branches in decision trees. Conditional arrows are always directed towards a chance node and denote probabilistic dependence. The arrows from D to X, or L to Y, are examples of conditional arrows. Informational arrows, on the other hand, are always directed towards a decision node and denote available information. The arrows from D to B or L to B are examples of informational arrows. Chance nodes K and L, also called the frontier nodes, are not influenced by any other factor (node); basically they influence directly or indirectly the other nodes. A common approach for the generation of IDs is the goal directed. This is the one also employed in this study <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The methods for evaluating and solving IDs so far are based on probabilities. The input and output values of a node in an ID are represented by probabilities. A common technique for evaluating and solving an ID is based on the Bayesian Theorem <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. In IDs, the use of probability tables with many elements is prohibitive because of the combinatorial explosion arising from the requirement that the solution must be extracted by the cross product of all probability tables.</p><p>Our aim is to combine the features of IDs taken from graph theory and the flexibility of fuzzy logic to produce a modeling tool in the hands of decision makers <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>, which is easy to understand and conceptualized, but also it does not suffer from combinatorial explosion problems when a high descriptive accuracy is needed, or when the system being modeled is highly demanding at the stage of quantification (i.e. quantification of the probability of USA attacking Cuba).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Fuzzy Influence Diagrams</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Overview</head><p>In this paper we propose a special type of IDs called Fuzzy Influence Diagram (FID). Its architecture is the same as that of an ordinary ID in the sense that it has the same type of nodes and arrows. However, an FID employs fuzzy reasoning instead of probabilities.</p><p>As mentioned earlier, a node with n children has n+1 fuzzy sets. The first one (F) takes the node's input values and converts it to fuzzy values via its membership function defined by a group of experts. Each of the other fuzzy sets G i controls the output to the corresponding child node. Its membership function is selected by the experts from a set of symbol sigmoid and bell-shaped (Gaussian) functions.</p><p>These functions indicate the nature of the influence the parent node exerts to the child and may be adjusted to suit the situation under study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Scalable Monotonic Chaining</head><p>The output of a node to its i th child is produced by the combination of fuzzy sets F and G i. A commonly used technique for combining fuzzy sets is MIN/MAX inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref>, where the solution is updated by taking the maximum of the solution fuzzy set <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>. However, after a few iterations the "high" mark of the solution set will soon become equal 1.0, leading to significant loss of information because values less than the solution's current truth level will be ignored.</p><p>In "real world" decision making problems and crisis management problems in particular <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>, it is important to allow every factor to represent itself and appear in the model irrespectively of its significance.</p><p>Scalable Monotonic Chaining is a technique which does not suffer from the aforementioned drawback of MIN/MAX because it does not create and then defuzzify a solution fuzzy set. Instead, it calculates the output as the transformation G i (F(input)), where "input" is the average of the weighted sum of the contributions reaching the current node from the set of its parents. methodology which the domain experts can utilize in order to detect the most important factors affecting a crisis problem.</p><p>The three elements of a crisis are (i) the participant which threatens, (ii) the participant which is being threatened, and (iii) the cost (or benefit) of the crisis on both participants. The first step is therefore to identify these three elements. Once these are identified a procedure must be followed with which the experts decompose them in a repetitive manner until simple, measurable, elementary factors are identified.</p><p>The next step is the creation of the FID using the factors derived previously. We start with a minimal FID, which consists of a decision node and a value node. Subsequently, the factors derived in the first step are added starting from the value node V and ending at the decision node D as dictated by the goal directed technique. The experts are also guided to identify which factors are more important than others and for each of them a value weight is being assigned. It is noted that during this stage and with the aid of the diagram being generated thus far, some more factors may be discovered. The value node V in an FID represents the total cost of any action that is being taken under specific circumstances. After the completion of the FID we determine the fuzzy sets with which each node will be characterized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Determine the fuzzy sets of the factors</head><p>Following the construction of the FID, the experts must construct F-type fuzzy sets and select and adjust G-type sets. In this stage, the experts are asked to work with plots similar to those shown in figures 2 (F-type) and 3-5 (G-type).</p><p>The domain of the F-type fuzzy set varies between 0 and 100, while its range is between 0 and 1. Conversely, the domain of the G-type fuzzy set is between 0 and 1 and its range is between -0.5 to +0.5 (which may then be transformed to a larger range, as in our case where the range 0 and 100 was used).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Consulting with domain experts</head><p>In order to achieve the best representation of any crisis management decision problem we must incorporate the knowledge of experts in building the FID structure, as well as constructing the F fuzzy sets and selecting and adjusting, if necessary, the G i fuzzy sets.</p><p>Finding the factors that represent the problem is not an easy job. For that purpose we expound a <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: F-Type Fuzzy sets Graph While the F-type sets are constructed by the expert on the basis of the most accurate description of how the behavior of a node evolves, the G-type sets must be selected from a set of pre-defined functions. These are as follows:</p><p>(i) Sigmoid equation</p><p>The Gaussian graphs are used in situations where the influence of the parent node is significant only in the mid-range and insignificant when the input is low or high.  In every decision making problem each factor has its own importance in the FID. This is characterized by a set of scalars -the weights. In our example problem, the crisis at Imia, which was developed in three phases, there are different weights for each factor and for each phase. The values of these weights vary between 0.1 and 1.0. Our purpose is to characterize the influence of every factor on others from "least" to "enough" representing the way their values will be determined. A technique for transforming the fuzzy sets called hedges <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4]</ref> is used here so as to apply the weights to the factors. In general, the equation that represents the fuzzy set is multiplied by the associated factor weight to yield the corresponding membership value.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Determining the weights of influence for the factors</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">FID: How it works</head><p>The first thing we do before start running our FID is to initialize the values of each frontier node and set the weights of all nodes. After initialization the model is run and the values of each node are computed sequentially corresponding to the activation of the factors modelled for a certain point in time.   We use the sigmoid and hyperbolic graphs in cases where the parent node increases the value of the child node and the mirrored plots if it decreases that value.</p><p>More specifically, after assigning the values of the frontier nodes and their associated weights, the values of the direct children nodes are calculated using the scalable monotonic chaining. For example, the F-Type Graph which represents the Fuzzy Set for an individual node is combined with one of the G-Type graphs in order to estimate the values of the children nodes. Each node is represented as a pair of an F-Type and a GType graph. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> shows an example of the scalable monotonic methodology proposed in this paper. Alternatively to known Fuzzification and Defuzzification techniques [e.g. 1], monotonic chaining uses the membership value on the F-Type graph and maps it to the corresponding function of the G-Type graph to estimate the value of the term in the latter fuzzy set (i.e., in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">figure 6</ref> the term 65 is mapped to the value 0.01). This is executed repeatedly until the value node is reached. The value node gives us the total cost of our action taken at the decision node and under the current circumstances (i.e. behavior of factors represented by the frontier nodes). By changing the values in the frontier nodes, which reflect the mutually exclusive available actions/decisions, we may simulate any possible decision scenario and calculate the relevant given cost of a potential action.</p><p>response, or the EU and the USA had adopted a different attitude towards Greece and Turkey. The two Imia rocky and uninhabited islets lie in the Southeast Aegean Sea, at a distance of 10 Km from the Greek island of Kalymnos and 7 Km from the Turkish coast. The larger of the two islets has an area of approximately 2.5 hectares, while the smaller and more eastern has an area of 1.5 hectares. Following a naval incident on December 25, 1995, Turkey claimed for the first time in more than half a century that Imia constitute part of the Turkish territory, thus challenging the Greek sovereignty on the islands. Meanwhile, in Greece there was a shift in the leadership of the ruling party of the country, having as result the election of a new Prime Minister on January 18, 1996 and the appointment of a new government four days later. Arguably, the Greek political developments in the beginning of 1996 had an immediate impact on the Greek-Turkish crisis, a dimension of the issue which will be examined. The incident soon escalated to a crisis as a major naval build up developed around the Imia in the end of the month. At this very critical moment the U.S. Government mediated between Greece and Turkey in order to avert an armed conflict between the two states. The mediation proved successful and within 24 hours an understanding between the two sides had been reached. Both sides agreed to gradually withdraw their forces from the area of Imia. Studying the crisis at Imia with the help of knowledge experts we reached to the development of the FID depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">figure 7</ref>. The nodes of the model are explained in table 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Empirical validation: FID model for the Imia Crisis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">The Imia crisis</head><p>The purpose here is to use scenario analysis in order to follow the development of the crisis and investigate what would have happened if the Greek side had taken different actions compared to its actual</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Case Study</head><p>The Imia crisis simulation was split into three phases and each phase was executed with the same conditions that prevailed during the actual event. After a few modifications the initial model accomplished to react the same way as the actual crisis events, that is, using the parameters of the problem the model resulted answers that could easily be verified against the real facts. Thus, after confirming that our model reflected well the circumstances of the real situation, we used it to simulate various hypothetical scenarios of the Imia crisis.</p><p>The three phases identified to express the real situation during the Imia crisis were classified according to their relevant cost as listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. According to the decision taken at the decision node and using the intermediate node weights the total cost is calculated at the value node and compared to the cost of the three phases of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. Thus, a decision maker is able to assess the cost of his/her decision using this hypothetical scenario execution and plan his further actions.</p><p>The first scenario in this phase is related with USA being more actively involved from the beginning of the crisis, (e.g. USA=75) and whether things would be different in this case. More specifically, if the USA have taken sides with Greece, according to the results of the model, Turkey would have retreated and the crisis would deescalate (V=27). On the other hand, if no reaction was made by the USA and the readiness level of the Hellenic Army was high enough (e.g. ET=75), as the model suggested, the Turkish side would have been discouraged to take any further aggressive actions (AT=25). None of the above scenarios actually took place, thus we move to the second phase of the crisis (i.e. escalation).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Second Phase -Escalation of the crisis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">First Phase -Start of the crisis</head><p>During the first phase the external factors were estimated by the experts on a scale from 1 to 100 as previously mentioned. For example, the USA position was estimated at USA=55 indicating a neutral position on this issue. The stability of the Turkish Government was STK=65 indicating low stability and the Turkish European perspective even lower at EP=40 showing that in 1995 the negotiations for accession of Turkey to the EU was far away from reality. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> reflects the starting phase of the crisis indicating the changes of some important factors during this phase and how these factors affect the Cost (V). The estimated cost for the Greek government is calculated using the Scalable Monotonic Chaining methodology described in section 3. The Cost, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7</ref>, is analyzed to three sub-costs: Military, Social and Political Cost.</p><p>In the first phase, the USA (USA=55) and EU, through the pressure associated with Turkey's European perspective (EP=40), had no involvement in the crisis. Even though the Greek side at the beginning of the crisis was trying to lower the heat (D=5), later on the USA became more actively involved in the incident aiming at helping the two sides to reduce the tension in the area (USA=75). The model suggested that the Turkish side was trying to involve the Greek Government (D=35) in the crisis with stimulatory actions (AT=45). When the involvement of Greece (D=35) became more active the cost was considerably increased (V=85).</p><p>In the second phase, as shown in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>, the reactions of the two parts are more aggressive than before (D=55 and AT=55), while the involvement of the USA at this moment is assumed not beneficiary to the Greek side (USA=35). On the contrary, the Turkish side is encouraged to take more aggressive actions (AT=65). The results of the model in this phase are also consistent with what really happened. The cost was raised to 59 indicating the escalation of the crisis. Like in the previous phase, the scenarios of interest are those corresponding to varying the values of the factors USA and EP.</p><p>gradually from the area, leading to a decrease of the relevant cost (V=38). prevailing during this crisis and this enabled the development and executions of various hypothetical scenarios, where the cost of a decision was assessed based on the simulated behavior of the participating factors. Concluding, the proposed approach proved its efficiency and effectiveness on a real case problem, and thus it will constitute a reliable decision making tool able to forecast future tactics and moves.</p><p>The scenarios examined in this phase were the following: If the Greek side did not agree with the suggestions of the USA and reacted more aggressively against Turkey, then the latter, with the support of the USA, would also react strongly with catastrophic results for both sides, especially for Greece as the model indicated (AT=70, V=85). On the other hand, if the USA supported strongly the Greek side (USA=75) then Greece would have to face a limited action cost (V=38). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">References</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusions</head><p>[2] G.F. Cooper, "A methodology for using belief networks as influence <ref type="bibr">Diagrams," Proc. 4</ref> th Workshop Uncertainty Artificial Intelligent, <ref type="bibr">MM, 1998, pp. 55-63.</ref> Decision trees offer a good way of representing decision making problems. However, as the complexity of the problem grows and the number of factors increases, decision trees are inefficient and unpractical. This is due to the fact that they do not allow independent relations to be exploited as they are highly symmetric structures and take little or no advantage of independence among variables. Large decision problems usually require a highly redundant tree representation, introducing asymmetries to correct this inefficiency, something which finally leads to significant loss of information.</p><p>A new structure was proposed in the present work, which offers a combination of Fuzzy Logic and Influence Diagrams (ID) so as to create hybrid models that emulate reasoning and decision making using fuzzy causal relationships. The benefits of the proposed Fuzzy Influence Diagram (FID) can be summarized as follows: Firstly, the need to calculate the cross product of all problem parameters is eliminated, thus the combinatorial explosion associated with an ID is avoided. Secondly, the experts are allowed to estimate parameters using a more finelygraded scale than the usual 2 or 3-level scale of IDs. Thirdly, the experts can explicitly control the influence a parent node exerts to its child by adjusting the F-and G-type functions and setting the weights. The increased ability of incorporating expert knowledge easily into FID using graphical means adds more value to this structure.</p><p>As a proof of concept, we have presented the empirical results of simulating the 1996 crisis at Imia between Greece and Turkey using a dedicated FID. The model captured the dynamics of the conditions</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Decision and Value nodes of an ID</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>where the constants ? and b specifies the gradient of graph. In the example of figure 3 the graph for ? = 8, b = 0.02 and its mirror graph are depicted.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: G-Type Sigmoid Equation Graph (ii) Gaussian equation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: G-Type Gaussian equation Graph (iii) Hyperbolic equation b ax x f c + = ) ( (3) where the constant ? takes values from -0.5 to 0.5, c takes only even values and b=0.5.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Scalable Monotonic chaining example</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: G-Type Hyperbolic equation Graph</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: The Imia crisis Influence Diagram</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>[ 1 ]</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A.S. Andreou, N.H. Mateou and G.A. Zombanakis, "Soft Computing for Crisis Management and Political Decision Making: The Use of Genetically Evolved Fuzzy Cognitive Maps", Soft Computing, Springer, ISSN: 1433-7479 (Online), Online First, Issue 1, 2004, and Vol.9, Issue 3, 2005, pp.194-210.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>TABLE 1 . Description of ID Nodes</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Node 
Description 
D 
Possible decisions of the Greek government 
ET 
Hellenic Army level of readiness 
EK 
Hellenic Army level of military training 
EM 
Possibility of military conflict 
MME 
Role of mass media 
APA 
Loss of human life 
APE 
Loss of national territory 
KG 
Public opinion in Greece 
AT 
Reaction of Turkey 
USA 
USA attitude 
MAT 
Future reactions 
AKG 
Disorientation of local public opinion 
EP 
European perspective of Turkey 
STK 
Stability of the Turkish government 
DI 
Diplomatic accomplishments of the Greek government 
IS 
Level of collaboration among the two sides 
SEK 
Stability of the Greek government 
S 
Military cost 
K 
Social cost 
P 
Political cost 
V 
Total cost (value node) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>TABLE 2 . Categorization of three phases according to cost</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Phases 
Cost (V) 
First -Start of the crisis 
1 to 40 
Second -Escalation of the crisis 
41 to 60 
Third -Peak of the crisis 
61 to 100 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>TABLE5. Important factors for Phase 3</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>D 
AT USA STK AKG ?P IS MAT 
Cost 
(V) 
70 
70 
25 
25 
55 
20 
40 
75 
85 
55 
60 
75 
35 
55 
20 
40 
75 
38 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot">Proceedings of the 2005 International Conference on Computational Intelligence for Modelling, Control and Automation, and International Conference on Intelligent Agents, Web Technologies and Internet Commerce (CIMCA-IAWTIC&apos;05) 0-7695-2504-0/05 $20.00 ? 2005 IEEE</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.3">Third Phase -Peak of the crisis</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intelligent Decision Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Holtzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>AddisonWesley Publishing Company, INC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Principles and Applications of Decision Analysis, Decision Group</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Matheson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<pubPlace>Menlo Park, CA, Volume I &amp; II</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Influence Diagrams to junction trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dittmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceeding of 10 th Conf. Uncertainty Artificial Intelligent</title>
		<meeting>eeding of 10 th Conf. Uncertainty Artificial Intelligent<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufman Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fuzzy Thinking, the New Science of Fuzzy Logic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kosko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Harper Collins</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edn</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning Bayesian Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Neopolitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>Pearson Prentice Hall</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representation and Analysis of Medical Decision Problems with Influence Diagrams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Owens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Nease</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shachter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="262" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating Influence diagrams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shachter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Operational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="882" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuation-based systems for Bayesian Decisionanalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Shenory</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
