<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:55+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Influence Maximization in Social Networks: An Ising-model-based Approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shihuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Ying</surname></persName>
							<email>leiying@iastate.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Shakkottai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Texas A&amp;M University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Iowa State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Influence Maximization in Social Networks: An Ising-model-based Approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The past few years have seen increasing interest in understanding social networks as a medium for community interaction. A major challenge has been to understand various fundamental properties of social networks that form the basis for the formation and propagation of opinions across such networks. The main hurdle has been the absence of plausible models that specify the correlations between different members of a social network, which could then be used for algorithm design. This paper studies an influence maximization problem using an Ising-model-based approach. We first validate the credibility of the ferromagnetic Ising model in predicting opinion formation in social networks using cosponsorship data from the US Senate proceedings. We then develop a greedy placement algorithm that can efficiently find an appropriate subset of network members, &quot;bribing&quot; whom can efficiently propagate a particular opinion in the network. We use simulations to confirm the effectiveness of the greedy placement algorithm.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>The rapid and global emergence of online social networks over the past few years, and their meteoric adoption by millions of Internet users has seen renewed interest in the study of the properties of social networks as a whole. Indeed, one can envision a future society in which communication, reputation, marketing and the very molding of societal opinions transpire on online social networking platforms. A major challenge has been to understand the properties of social networks that might allow for the harnessing of this new medium to attain desirable outcomes. A basic question is related to the propagation of influence in a social network, i.e., how does a person's opinion change the opinions of other people in the network? Also, if there are two possible views on a particular issue, which is the dominant one? This is a problem with important practical applications, especially for firms or organizations who want to promote their products or philosophies. The solution could help such firms or organizations decide the most effective places to advertise their products/philosophies.</p><p>In this paper, we consider an influence maximization problem. Specifically, suppose there is a particular issue about which members of a social network could have two possible opinions, and assume that we can "bribe" a fixed number of members, the question is whom should we bribe to cause the dominance of the opinion of our choice? Problems relating to such influence maximization were first formulated in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, and have been studied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. These results, however, are established based on the independent cascade model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> wherein a member is activated (convinced by the opinion) with a probability depending on the state of her/his neighbors. Further, the models usually assume that the members either have a particular opinion or are neutral, but not that they might be trying to propagate opposite opinions.</p><p>In this paper, we consider a social network and assume there are two competing opinions on a specific subject. We define the value of a member's opinion to be "+1" if the member is in favor of the subject and "-1" if the member is against that subject. In order to represent the correlation of opinions between friends and acquaintances, we adopt the ferromagnetic Ising model <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, which was first proposed in statistical physics. In particular, we adopt the concept that the ground state (the configuration that emerges when the temperature goes to zero) of the network is the most likely opinion formed because the ground state minimizes the magnitude of conflicts in the social network (in physical systems, the ground state is the state with minimum energy). This model was shown to be effective in identifying community structure in social networks <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref>. Note that the Ising-based model differs from the independent cascade model in two aspects: (i) the Ising-modelbased approach allows both positive and negative influences so can be used to model two completing opinions while the independent cascade model (except the one in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>) only allows one opinion in the network; and (ii) the "concept" of ground state models the "self-optimizing" nature of the social network. In other words, the network tries to minimize the degree of conflict and settles down in the minimum conflict state, which does not exist in the independent cascade model.</p><p>We develop an Ising-model-based approach wherein linkweights between nodes model their degree of correlation. We assume that subsets of nodes are irretrievably fixed with a positive or negative opinion, while others' opinions are caused due to the propagation of influence of these seed nodes. In order to validate this model we use data from the records of bill cosponsorship in the US Senate, wherein we fix link weights between senators (nodes) based on the number of bills that they cosponsored <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>. We fix some nodes as known to be "Democrat" or "Republican", and show that ground state of the system automatically and correctly identifies the party affiliations of the remaining nodes. We then attempt to answer the general question of how to identify the most appropriate nodes to "bribe" in order to cause a particular opinion to dominate. Thus, we are given a budget of nodes whose opinions we can fix, and must decide which nodes should be chosen. We develop a greedy algorithm to choose nodes, and show that it outperforms an algorithm that makes choices solely based on the degree of nodes.</p><p>The paper is organized as follows. In Section II, we introduce the Ising model based on a Markovian random field, and then describe the connection between the ground state of the Ising model and the min-cut of the corresponding graph. This connection allows us to compute the ground state in an efficient way. We then validate the Ising model and the ground state concept on a Senate network in Section III. We propose a greedy placement algorithm in Section IV that finds m positive seeds that can maximize the number of positive nodes at the ground state. We then present simulation results in Section V to compare the performance of the greedy algorithm with a degree-based placement algorithm. We conclude in Section VI.</p><p>i.e., N + is the expected number of +1 in the network, and N ? is the expected number of ?1s in the networks, and the randomness arises due to probabilistic correlations between opinions of neighbors.</p><p>Now, assume that m extra positive seeds can be placed in the network. For example, a company is willing to pay m extra users on the online social networks to express a positive opinion. The question is where should these extra positive seeds be placed? Mathematically, the problem can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">max ? ? ди + :| ? ди + |=m N + ( ? ди + , ди + , ди ? ) = E 1 Oi=+1?ди Oi=+1? Oi=+1?ди + , ди + , ди . iА╩N (1)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. PROBLEM DESCRIPTION AND BACKGROUND</head><p>Note that to solve the placement problem (1), we first need to define the function F i that defines the relationship between the opinions of neighboring nodes. In this paper, we adopt a Markovian Random Field Model, the Ising model, to represent such relationships. We will validate the model using Senate voting data in Section III and then propose a placement algorithm for influence maximizing based on the Ising model.</p><p>We consider a social network represented by an undirected graph G = (N , L), where N is the set of nodes, and L is the set of links. Denote by W А╩ R</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Markovian Random Field and Ising Model</head><p>The probability that the opinion formed o is assumed to be N А┴N + the link weight matrix, where W ij АП 0 is the weight of link l ij . The value of W ij represents the strength of the social connection between node i and node j. Larger values of W ij , represent stronger social connections between node i and node j.</p><p>In this paper, we study opinion formation in a social network and propose a placement algorithm that will be defined rigorously in Section IV, to maximize influence of a desired opinion in the social network. We define O i to be the opinion of node i on a specific subject, and O i = +1 if the node is in favor of the subject and O i = ?1 otherwise. We denote by O = [O 1 , . . . , O n ] and o to be a realization of O. We assume that an opinion of node i is a function of the opinions of the neighbors of node i, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">? ? Pr(o) = 1 Z exp ? W ij T o i o j ? , ijА╩L</formula><p>where W ij is a parameter indicating the correlation between i and j, T is a parameter that indicates the time remaining for a decision to be made; when T = 0 opinions get fixed, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Z = o exp( Wij ijА╩L T o i o j ) is the normalizing factor. Therefore, ? ? exp ? W ij o i o j T ? Pr (o i |o\{o i }) = j:ijА╩L ? ? ? ? . exp ? W ij o j T ? + exp ? ? W ij o j T ? O i = F i ({O j } j:ijА╩L ) . j:ijА╩L j:ijА╩L</formula><p>Further, we assume that the network contains nodes with pre-determined opinions, whose opinions are not affected by their neighbors' opinions. We name a node with predetermined positive opinion, i.e., O i = +1, as a positive seed, and a node with pre-determined negative opinion, i.e., O i = ?1, as a negative seed. The subset of positive seeds is denoted by ди + and the subset of negative seeds is denoted by ди ? . Now, given ди + , ди ? and the functions F i , we can compute the following two quantities: So this graphical model is a Markovian random field (MRF). This graphic model in exponential form is the Ising model from statistical physics <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. In statistical physics, the ferromagnetic Ising model represents atoms that form a network, and every atom i is associated with a spin variable O i = А└1. The energy of the Ising model (the Hamiltonian) is defined to be</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">H(O) = ? 1 2 W ij O i O j . ijА╩L N + (ди + , ди ? ) = E 1 Oi=+1 ди + , ди ?</formula><p>The ground state of the Ising model is defined to be the lowest energy configuration, i.e., a configuration o g such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">iА╩N o g А╩ arg min H(o),<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">o N ? (ди + , ди ? ) = E 1 Oi=?1 ди + , ди ? ,</formula><p>which in statistical physics, is the configuration at zero temperature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>iА╩N</head><p>From the perspective of MRF, the ground state configuration is the configuration that emerges with probability one when T АЩ 0 (assuming that the ground state is unique). Considering the question of identification of "Democrats" versus "Republicans" in Section III, value T can be viewed as the remaining time to decide party affiliations given one's social network. When T is large, the final decision of a member is probabilistic, but he/she has to make a decision when T = 0. If two neighbors i and j have different party affiliations, W ij can be viewed as the amount of energy created by the conflict between i and j.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Senator network construction</head><p>We construct a network amongst US Senators based on data for the year 2004 <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref> as follows. The senator network consists of 100 nodes (senators). The network is constructed based on the cosponsorship of bills as defined in <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>. Every bill is sponsored by one senator and can be cosponsored by multiple other senators. For a bill l, let n l denote the number of cosponsors of the bill. Define a ijl А╩ {0, 1} to be a binary function such that a ijl = 1 if and only if bill l is sponsored by senator i and cosponsored by senator j, and a ijl = 0 otherwise. The weight of link (i, j) is defined to be</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">W ij =</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Ground State and Min-Cut</head><formula xml:id="formula_7">a ijl n l + a jil n l . l</formula><p>The Ising model can be used to understand social networks because of the following two reasons: (i) The Ising model defines a Markovian random field, which is consistent with our assumption that in social networks, the opinion of a node is a function of the neighboring nodes, and (ii) In physical systems, the ground state is the state with minimum energy. In a social network, the ground state can be viewed as the opinion formation that minimizes the magnitude of conflicts.</p><p>Given an opinion configuration o, </p><formula xml:id="formula_8">H(o) = ? ? 1 2 W ij ? + W ij . ijА╩L ij:oi =oj Since ? 1 2 ijА╩L W ij</formula><p>is a constant independent of o, the optimization (2) can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">o g А╩ arg min W ij .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>o ij:oi =oj Given o, define the source set to be the set of nodes with o i = +1, and the sink set to be the set of nodes with o i = ?1. From (3), it is not difficult to verify that the ground-state configuration o g of a social network with positive and negative seeds is the minimum cut of graph G such that the source and sink nodes are on opposite sides of the cut. From the discussions above, (i) we hypothesize that the ground state of the Ising model indicates the most likely opinion formed in the given social network, and (ii) the ground state can be found by computing the mincut of the graph. Therefore, the Ising model could potentially be used as a quantitative tool for predicting opinion formation in social networks, and to study the influence maximization problem (1). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Opinion formation in the senator network</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. SENATOR NETWORK: AN EXAMPLE</head><p>The Ising model has earlier been used to identify community structure of social networks, e.g., Karate club network, and coauthor network <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref>. We now validate the Ising model in the network of US Senators, and show that it can correctly predict their party affiliations.</p><p>After constructing the social network, we then applied the Ising model to predict the party affiliations of senators. We choose "+1" to represent Democratic (or independent) affiliation and a "-1" to represent Republican affiliation. We randomly selected m nodes known to be Democrats as positive seeds, and m nodes known to be Republican as negative seeds. For given ди + and ди ? , we found the min-cut of the graph, which specifies the ground state of the system. In other words, we found the ground state labels of all senators given m known Republicans and Democrats, and compared the labels thus obtained with the actual party affiliations of the senators. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> shows the number of prediction errors (label a Democratic senator as a Republican or vice versa) as Proof: To prove this lemma, we first define L (ди + , ди ? ) to be the min-cut-set of links given ди + and ди ? , i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">40 35 L ди + , ди ? = (ij) : i А╩ N + (ди + , ди ? ) and j А╩ N ? (ди + , ди ? ) .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>30</head><p>We further define the weight of the min-cut as </p><formula xml:id="formula_11">25 W L ди + , ди ? = 20 W ij . 15 ij:ijА╩L(ди + ,ди ? )<label>10 5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">if i А╩ N + (ди + , ди ? ) , then L (ди + , ди ? )</formula><p>remains a cut-set for given ди + А╚ {i} and ди ? , which implies that On the other hand, L (ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? ) is a cut-set for given ди + and ди ? , which implies that</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">W L ди + , ди ? АП W L ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">W L ди + , ди ? А▄ W L ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? .</formula><p>a function of m. We see that ground state of the Ising model matches real party affiliations well. Given twenty known Republicans and Democrats, the number of prediction errors is only ten (recall that we have 100 senates in the network).</p><p>These results along with the earlier results of <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref> indicate that the Ising model is an accurate method of representing the correlation of opinions in a social network.</p><p>Hence, we have that</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">W L ди + , ди ? = W L ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? ,</formula><p>and equality (4) holds under the assumption that the min-cut is unique.</p><p>We next prove result (5) by contradiction. We assume that</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. MAXIMIZING INFLUENCE IN SOCIAL NETWORKS</head><formula xml:id="formula_16">N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? ? N + ди + , ди ? .<label>(6)</label></formula><p>In this section, we study efficient algorithms that solve the placement problem (1) based on the Ising model. The straightforward approach is to consider all subsets?диsubsets? subsets?ди + such that | ? ди + | = m and?диand? and?ди + А╔ (ди + А╚ ди ? ) = ?, and compute the ground state. Then, we can set the?диthe? the?ди + yielding the largest N + . This algorithm however requires us to consider n ? |ди + | ? |ди ? | m Then we define the following four sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">S E = N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? N + ди + , ди ? S A = N ? ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? N + ди + , ди ? combinations</formula><p>, and is very computa-</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">S B = N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? N ? ди + , ди ? tionally intensive.</formula><p>We therefore consider a greedy algorithm that places the extra positive seeds one by one. For each positive seed, we check all possible positions and compute N + using the Ising model, and the select the position yielding the largest N + . We then repeat this process until all m positive seeds are placed. This sequential placement computes the min-cut mn times</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">S C = N ? ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? N ? ди + , ди ? .</formula><p>Then it is easy to see that S E S A S B S C = N . We further define the following link sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">L a = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S E , u А╩ S A } L b = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S A , u А╩ S C } instead of n ? |ди + | ? |ди ? | m</formula><p>times. Further, we have the</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">L c = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S E , u А╩ S B } L d = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S B , u А╩ S C }</formula><p>following proposition which states that it is sufficient to search the sink set instead of all nodes to place a positive seed. We define N + (ди + , ди ? ) to be the source set under the min-cut given positive seeds ди + and negative seeds ди ? . We then have the following proposition.</p><p>Proposition 1: Assume that the graph G has a unique mincut for any given ди + and</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">ди ? . If i А╩ N + (ди + , ди ? ) , then L e = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S E , u А╩ S C } L f = {(v, u) А╩ L : v А╩ S A , u А╩ S B }</formula><p>Under the assumption (6), we have that S A = ?, which implies that L a = ? and L b = ?. According to the definitions of L Ац , we know</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? = N + ди + , ди ? ,<label>(4)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_24">N + ди + , ди ? = S E А╚ S A N ? ди + , ди ? = S B А╚ S C .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>and otherwise</head><p>Therefore, the weight of the min-cut given ди + and ди</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">? N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? ? N + ди + , ди ? .<label>(5)</label></formula><p>satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">W L ди + , ди ? = W (L b ) + W (L e ) + W (L c ) + W (L f ).</formula><p>Furthermore, it is easy to verify that L a L e L c is a cut-set given ди + and ди ? . Under the assumption that the graph has a unique mini-cut, we then conclude that</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">Algorithm 1 Greedy Placement Algorithm ди + 0 = ди + W (L b ) + W (L e ) + W (L c ) + W (L f ) &lt; W (L a ) + W (L e ) + W (L c ) for j = 1 to m do Combine all nodes in N + ди + j?1 , ди ?</formula><p>as a super node, named node дМ j?1 , and form a new graph G j?1 ; Find a node which implies that</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">i * = arg max N + ({дМ j?1 } А╚ {i}, ди ? ); W (L b ) + W (L f ) &lt; W (L a ). i А╩{дМj?1}А╚ди ? and Let ди + j = ди + j?1 W (L b ) &lt; W (L a ). (7) {i * }; end for return ди + m \ ди + .</formula><p>Next, according to the definitions, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">N + ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? = S E А╚ S B N ? ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? = S A А╚ S C V. SIMULATION</formula><p>Therefore, the min-cut given ди + А╚ {i} and ди ? satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">W L ди + А╚ {i}, ди ? = W (L e )+W (L d )+W (L a )+W (L f ). Further, L e А╚ L d А╚ L b is a cut-set given ди + А╚ {i} and ди ? .</formula><p>Under the assumption that the min-cut is unique, we have that</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">W (L e ) + W (L d ) + W (L a ) + W (L f ) &lt; W (L e ) + W (L d ) + W (L b ) which implies that W (L a ) + W (L f ) &lt; W (L b ). and W (L a ) &lt; W (L b ).,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>which contradicts (7). Therefore, the assumption (6) does not hold, which leads to result (5). From Proposition 1, we have the following two observations:</p><p>? Observation 1: To place one (and only one) extra positive seed given ди + and ди ? , we only need to check the nodes in</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">N ? (ди + , ди ? ) \ ди ? .</formula><p>We now use simulations to evaluate the performance of the greedy algorithm. In social network, basically, nodes with large degrees can be considered as "influential nodes", since they have more connections with other nodes and as a result have more influence on the opinion configuration of the network. Therefore, a natural approach to our problem is to choose those large-degree nodes as extra positive seeds. Specifically, we can sort all free nodes (nodes that are not seeds) in decreasing order of their degrees, and choose the first m nodes as extra positive seeds. We call this approach the Degree-based Placement Algorithm. In contrast to Degreebased placement, the Greedy algorithm that we developed in this paper implicitly takes multi-hop influence propagation into account while placing extra positive seeds. We expect, therefore, that it would perform better at the goal of maximizing the number of positive opinions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Simulation settings</head><p>? Observation 2: If a node is in source set in the ground state of the graph given ди + and ди ? , then the node remains in the source set when extra positive seeds are placed. From the observations above, we can see the complexity of the sequential placement algorithm can be further reduced. In the sequential placement algorithm, suppose ди + k is the set of positive seeds after k extra positive seeds are placed. We can combine all nodes in N + ди + Previous research has shown that most social networks are small-world networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11]</ref>. Hence, we construct a small world network to imitate a social network based on the method in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12]</ref>. Specifically, we first generate a 10 А┴ 10 grid network. Then, we add 1 long link to each node according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12]</ref>, where r = 1. By doing this we obtain a small world network. Note that the network is undirected. We randomly place 20 negative seeds, and 10 positive seeds on this network. Now, suppose that a firm is willing to place at most 10 extra positive seeds on this network. The objective of the firm is to maximize the expected number of +1 in the ground state of the network. </p><formula xml:id="formula_33">k , ди</formula><formula xml:id="formula_34">j * А╩ arg max j:jА╩N ? (ди + ? + N ди + k {j}, ди . k ,ди ? )\ди ?</formula><p>Therefore, we not only reduce the set of candidate nodes but also reduce the size of the network. The algorithm is formally defined as follows.</p><p>In order to compare the performance of two algorithms, we vary the number of extra positive seeds from 0 to 10, and observe the number of +1 in the ground state of the network under two algorithms. The results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">figure  3</ref>. From the graph we see that under the Greedy Placement Algorithm, when we place 10 extra seeds, the number of +1 in the ground state almost reaches the maximum value (at most 80). However, under the Degree-based algorithm, the number of +1 is only 33 when we place 10 extra positive seeds. Thus, the Greedy Placement Algorithm outperforms the Degree-based algorithm significantly. In particular, we present the situation where we can place 10 extra positive seeds. The seed distributions under two algorithms are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>(a) and 4(b). In these two figures, red circles are positive seeds, blue triangles are negative seeds, and black squares are non-seed nodes. The ground state configuration in this setting are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>(a) and 5(b). In the figure, red circles represent +1 nodes, and blue triangles represent ?1 nodes. Black links represent the links between two +1 nodes or ?1 nodes, and green links represent the links between a +1 and a ?1 node (i.e. the cut of the network). From these two graphs, it is easy to see that the Greedy Algorithm gives better results than the Degree-based Algorithm.</p><p>(b) Degree-based Algorithm As we know, exhaustive search is a way to find the optimal placement solution. However, due to its high computational complexity, the exhaustive search algorithm is not a practical algorithm. In this part of simulation, we use exhaustive search to find the optimal solution, and compare the result with our Greedy Algorithm. Here we assume that we can place at most 3 extra positive seeds, otherwise the computational complexity is unacceptably high.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Greedy placement versus exhaustive search</head><p>The results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>. We see from the figure that the Greedy Algorithm performs slightly worse than the optimal solution. Specifically, when we are allowed 3 extra positive nodes, the +1 in the ground state under the Greedy Algorithm is 19, while the optimal number is 25. desired opinion in the network. Our simulations confirmed the effectiveness of the greedy placement algorithm over one that purely makes use of node-degree information.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We adopt this approach because the cosponsorship reflects social connection between two senators. The network we obtained is shown in Figure 1. In the figure, blue nodes represent Democratic (or independent) senators, red node represent Republican senators. Blue links are the links between Democratic senators, red links are links between Republican senators, and green links are links across party lines. The number of links between Democratic senators is 201, between Republican senators is 180, and between a Democratic senator and a Republican senator is 196.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. The US Senator network. Links indicate cosponsorship of bills by senators, while the link colors indicate party affiliations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. The number of incorrect labels in the ground state versus the number of seeds of each type m. We see that the Ising model is a good predictor of party affiliations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Comparison between two algorithms: We observe that the Greedy Algorithm is more successful than the Degree-based Algorithm in maximizing the desired opinion.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Seed distribution under the Greedy and Degree-based Algorithms</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>#</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5. The ground state configuration under the Greedy and Degree-based Algorithms</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6. Comparison between the Greedy Algorithm and exhaustive search</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining the network value of customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the seventh ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the seventh ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence in a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influential nodes in a diffusion model for social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Automata, Languages and Programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1127" to="1138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the submodularity of influence in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mossel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Roch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the thirty-ninth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing</title>
		<meeting>the thirty-ninth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page">134</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bharathi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Salek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internet and Network Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="311" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Talk of the network: A complex systems look at the underlying process of word-of-mouth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beitrag zur theorie des ferromagnetismus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ising</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Zeitschrift fе╣r Physik A Hadrons and Nuclei</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="465" />
			<date type="published" when="1925" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Social Networks</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Website Of Senate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.senate.gov/legislative/LIS/rollcalllists/votemenu1082.htm" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kochen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>De Sola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pool</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Milgram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Newcomb</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The small world. Ablex</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The small-world phenomenon: an algorithm perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the thirty-second annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing</title>
		<meeting>the thirty-second annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">170</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
