<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:55+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization in social networks under an independent cascade-based model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Elsevier BV</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiyao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuehui</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhen</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shiduan</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization in social networks under an independent cascade-based model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications</title>
						<title level="j" type="abbrev">Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">0378-4371</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="volume">444</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="34"/>
							<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.physa.2015.10.020</idno>
					<note type="submission">Article history: Received 19 April 2015 Received in revised form 23 July 2015</note>
					<note>Contents lists available at ScienceDirect journal homepage: www.elsevier.com/locate/physa</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Influence maximization Positive influence Independent cascade-based model Opinion change Social networks</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>h i g h l i g h t s ? A novel independent cascade model based on opinion change, called IC-OC, was proposed for information spreading. ? Two probabilities were introduced to predict opinion change when users are exposed to bilateral opinions. ? The IMIC-OC model was proposed for influence maximization. ? Experiments were conducted on three real networks to verify that the IMIC-OC model has larger influence than two baseline methods. a r t i c l e i n f o a b s t r a c t The rapid growth of online social networks is important for viral marketing. Influence maximization refers to the process of finding influential users who make the most of information or product adoption. An independent cascade-based model for influence maxi-mization, called IMIC-OC, was proposed to calculate positive influence. We assumed that influential users spread positive opinions. At the beginning, users held positive or negative opinions as their initial opinions. When more users became involved in the discussions, users balanced their own opinions and those of their neighbors. The number of users who did not change positive opinions was used to determine positive influence. Corresponding influential users who had maximum positive influence were then obtained. Experiments were conducted on three real networks, namely, Facebook, HEP-PH and Epinions, to calculate maximum positive influence based on the IMIC-OC model and two other baseline methods. The proposed model resulted in larger positive influence, thus indicating better performance compared with the baseline methods.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Online social networks (OSNs) are beneficial for researchers and companies that study user behaviors and make profits, respectively. For example, advertisers found a subset of users to maximize the adoption of products <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, which is a way of using influence maximization. The goal of influence maximization is to maximize the number of users involved in discussions or adopt products in the network. The independent cascade-based model for influence maximization is proposed in this study to handle this problem.</p><p>In recent years, many researchers have focused on influence maximization. Kempe et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> first used greedy algorithm to study influence maximization based on two models, namely, Independent Cascade (IC) and Linear Threshold (LT). Chen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> calculated positive influence amidst the existence of negative opinions within a network. However, the authors assumed that if users adopted one opinion, they would never change their opinions. As time passes, users are probably influenced by others to adopt opposite opinions. Thus, when users are exposed to different attitudes, probabilities are introduced to predict whether such users would change their minds until no neighbor changes opinions.</p><p>To better understand the proposed model for influence maximization, a novel IC model based on opinion change, called IC-OC, is proposed to show the process through which users build opinions. In the beginning of information spreading, the IC model is used to predict the initial opinions of the user. As several users become involved in the discussion, a transforming probability is introduced to predict whether users would change their initial opinions. The proposed model is verified by the dataset culled from Facebook.</p><p>1 Then, the IMIC-OC model is used to calculate maximum positive influence in three real networks.</p><p>We model social network as a directed influence graph. Nodes denote individuals and edges denote ''who influences whom''. In some social networks, such as Twitter <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> and Sina Weibo, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> user relations are unidirectional, such that the structure of network is directly used as influence graphs. Other social networks provide bidirectional relations, such as Facebook and the co-author's network. In these networks, an undirected edge is divided into two directed edges to obtain the influence graph.</p><p>In the current study, the IC-OC model is proposed to explain how users build opinions during the process of information spreading. The IMIC-OC model is proposed to find influential users who have maximum positive influence. The following items summarize our contributions to the literature.</p><p>? Transforming probability is introduced to predict whether users change their initial opinions when bilateral opinions exist in the network.</p><p>? The IC-OC model for information spreading is proposed to gain a better explanation for opinion formation.</p><p>? The IMIC-OC model is proposed to tackle the influence maximization problem; the properties of the proposed model are also analyzed.</p><p>Experiments were conducted on a real network. First, the IC-OC model was verified for information spreading. Experimental results indicated that the proposed model had better performance than the baseline methods. Maximum positive influence was calculated by applying the IMIC-OC model on three real datasets. The findings showed that the proposed model had better performance compared with the baseline methods. Further explanations were given.</p><p>The reminder of this study is organized into sections. Prior works on influence maximization and opinion formation are discussed in Section 2. Section 3 presents the problem statement. Section 4 introduces the IC-OC model for information spreading and the IMIC-OC model for influence maximization. Section 5 shows the experimental results. Finally, Section 6 presents the conclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related works</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Influence maximization</head><p>Many researchers have attempted to tackle the influence maximization problem. Kempe et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> proposed two basic information diffusion models, namely, IC and LT. An algorithm was used to obtain an approximate solution for this NP-hard problem. Chen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> categorized the solutions to the problem of influence maximization into two classes: reducing running time of algorithms and using new methods to calculate influence.</p><p>Many studies have focused on improving the efficiency of algorithms on influence maximization <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Zhang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, for example, reduced running time and memory consumption by mapping several networks into one network. Goyal et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> proposed CELF++, a novel CELF algorithm, to reduce running time. <ref type="bibr">Heidari et al. [10]</ref> used Monte-Carlo simulation to improve time complexity, whereas Li et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> considered wide influence spread to tackle location-aware influence maximization.</p><p>Other studies proposed new algorithms to calculate influence <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>. Zhou et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> employed the voter model to handle the situation wherein different users activate the same user. Wu et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> used core users in the forefront of a network to calculate influence, and Li et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> proposed a novel conformity-aware cascade model, which used conformity theory to calculate influence. Meanwhile, Zhu et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> combined continuous-time Markov chain and IC model for influence maximization. Guo et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> proposed personal influence maximization, which aimed to find users who can activate targeted users. Lee et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref> maximized influence on specific users by query processing. In sum, the problem of influence maximization is based on information spreading. Researchers have proposed new models to exploit the structure of network or user relations so as to improve the performance of information spreading. Based on these models, the authors proposed corresponding models for influence maximization to find influential users.</p><p>Some researchers have also attempted to calculate influence when different opinions exist in a network. For instance, Chen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> proposed the IC-N model to calculate influence when negative opinions were present in a given network. They assumed that users never change opinions once activated. However, in reality, users could change their opinions, that is, the accumulation of opposite opinions in the network could possibly make users change their minds. Thus, we introduce transforming probability to predict whether users would change opinions when they are exposed to different views. Li et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> introduced broadcast and current attitude in studying user attitude modification. Based on the above method, the authors proposed the IMLT-IOA model for influence maximization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Opinion formation</head><p>In real life, people may actually change their initial opinions when their neighbors, who have a profound impact on them, hold opposite opinions. Some researchers have studied the problem of opinion formation <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. Das et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref> categorized models for opinion formation into three models, namely, averaging, flocking and voter. In averaging models, users update their opinions by using the average of neighbors. In flocking models <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>, conformity bias exists. In voter models <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref>, users randomly pick up the opinions of their neighbors at each time step. Meanwhile, Wang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref> introduced a freezing period in the voter model. During the freezing period, users have a high probability to change their minds. After that time, users could easily reach consensus in the network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Problem statement</head><p>Various definitions of social networks are available. First, the influence graph is introduced, which is a directed graph expressed as G = (V , E). Definition 1. An influence graph G = (V , E) is a directed graph that shows the relation of ''who influences whom''. Here, V = {v 1 , . . . , v n } denotes a set of users, while E = {e 1 , . . . , e m } denotes a set of edges.</p><p>Definition 2. Neighbors N(v) denote entire neighbors of user v. <ref type="bibr">Here, N in (v)</ref> and N out (v) denote in-and out-neighbors, respectively. If user v j is an out-neighbor of user v i , v j ¡Ê N out (v i ), user v i has an impact on user v j . Meanwhile, if user v j is an in-neighbor of user v i , v j ¡Ê N in (v i ), user v j influences user v i .</p><p>For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> shows that edge e 1 connects users v 1 and v 2 . Edge e 1 denotes that user v 1 influences user v 2 . User v 1 is an in-neighbor of user v 2 , that is, v 1 ¡Ê N in (v 2 ), and user v 2 is an out-neighbor of user v 1 , that is, v 2 ¡Ê N out (v 1 ).</p><p>Definition 3. Users are categorized into three classes, namely, inactive (I), positive (P), and negative (N). Here, I users are not activated in the network. P users hold positive opinions in the network, and N users hold negative opinions in the network.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>, only user v 6 is inactive, I = {v 6 }. Five users are positive, P = {v 1 , v 2 , v 3 , v 4 , v 7 }, whereas one user is negative, N = {v 5 }.</p><p>Three classes of users can be expressed as |V | = |I| + |P| + |N|, </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">|N in (v)| = |N i p n in (v)| + |N in (v)| + |N in (v)|. (3) Definition 4. Ego network G e = (V e , E e )</formula><p>is a network that indicates relations between a specific user v i and neighbors</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">N(v i ), V e = v i ¡È N(v i ). Edges connecting users are included, E e ? E.</formula><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>, ego network G e (v 2 ) of user v 2 shows relations between user v 2 and neighbors, N(v 2 ) = {v 1 , v 4 , v 5 , v 7 }. The ego network of user v 2 includes five users, V e = {v 1 , v 2 , v 4 , v 5 , v 7 }, and four edges, E e = {e 1 , e 3 , e 4 , e 6 }. </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">¦Õ(S) = {v j |s j * s i &gt; 0, v i ¡Ê S},<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where user v i ¡Ê S is an influential user, s i is the sentiment of user v i , and user v j is activated in the network and holds positive opinions. Definition 8. Negative influence denotes a set of users with negative opinions when influential users S spreads negative opinions. Owing to the asymmetry between positive and negative influence, we mainly study positive influence. Further explanations are given in Section 4.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>, the network has seven users V = {v 1 , . . . , v 7 }, and six edges E = {e 1 , . . . , e 6 }. If user v 1 is an influential user, S 1 = {v 1 }, we set user v 1 to spread a positive message. Users v 2 , v 3 , v 4 , v 5 adopt this information and only user v 5 holds a negative opinion. Thus, positive influence is ¦Õ(S 1 ) = {v 2 , v 3 , v 4 } and |¦Õ(S 1 )| = 3. If user v 2 is an influential user, S 2 = {v 2 }, positive influence is ¦Õ(S 2 ) = {v 4 } and |¦Õ(S 2 )| = 1. If user v 3 is an influential user, S 3 = {v 3 }, positive influence is ¦Õ(S 3 ) = ? and |¦Õ(S 3 )| = 0. Definition 9. Maximum positive influence ¦Õ m (S) denotes the maximum number of users who are activated by influential users S when the number of influential users is given as |S| = k. Maximum positive influence is defined as ¦Õ m (S) = max{|¦Õ(S)|}.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(5)</head><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>, if the cardinality of influential users is 1, |S| = 1, many users can be influential users, S 1 = {v 1 }, S 2 = {v 2 }, and S 3 = {v 3 }. In addition, the maximization positive influence is ¦Õ m (S) = {v 2 , v 3 , v 4 } and S = S 1 .</p><p>Problem Definition: Given number k, we aim to find a set of influential users S * who activate the maximum positive influence ¦Õ(S). Hence,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">S * = argmax |¦Õ(S)|,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where the cardinality of influential users S is k.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">IC-OC model</head><p>We introduce the IC-OC model in this section. Information spreading is initiated when some users spread information within the network. Out-neighbors are activated by adoption probability and hold the same opinion by conforming probability. Explicit definitions of probabilities are given in Section 4.2.1. As time passes, bilateral opinions emerge in the network. When in-neighbors hold different opinions, users change opinions by transforming probability while keeping their opinions by stubborn probability. The explicit definitions of these probabilities are provided in Section 4.2.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">IMIC-OC model</head><p>The IMIC-OC model aims to find a set of users who have maximum positive influence. This section analyzes properties of the IMIC-OC model. Therefore, we mainly analyze positive influence in the following sub-sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1.">Introduction of IMIC-OC model</head><p>In the IMIC-OC model, we first propose how influential users utilize paths to reach a user. Second, some probabilities are introduced to explain how users build opinions in the process of information spreading. Third, probabilities are introduced to calculate positive influence in the IMIC-OC model. Path(S, v i ) = {path 1 , . . . , path n } denotes a set of paths from influential users S to user v i , whereas L = {l 1 , . . . , l n } denotes corresponding lengths of paths, Path(S, v i ) = {path 1 , . . . , path n }. Many influential users can reach user v i . Thus, the shortest path, path min (S, v i ), from influential users S to user v i , is calculated to obtain the initial opinion of user v i . In addition, l min (S, v i ) is the corresponding length, path i = ?v 1 , v 2 , . . . , v i ? denotes entire users in path i , and path min (S, v i ) = ?v 1 , v 2 , . . . , v l min , v i ? shows the entire users in path min (S, v i ).</p><p>Probabilities are introduced to describe the spread of information from one user to another as well as the changing of opinions during the process of information spreading. The explicit explanations are given below. Definition 10. Adoption probability p a is the probability of adopting information. If user v i has an influence on user v j , adoption probability p a can be expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">p a = n n N 1 * N 2 , (7)</formula><p>where N 1 is the number of posts that are published by user v i , N 2 is the number of posts that are adopted by user v j , and n is the number of posts adopted by v j from user v i . Definition 11. Conforming probability p c is the probability that represents how user v j conforms to user v i when user v j adopts a piece of information from user v i . Conforming probability is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p c = n c n , (8)</formula><p>where n c is the number of posts whose sentiment is consistent with the sentiment expressed by user v i , and n is the number of posts adopted by v j from user v i . Definition 12. Positive propagation probability pp is the probability that user v j adopts information from user v i and user v j holds the same opinion as user v i . Positive propagation probability is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">pp ij = p a * p c = n c * n N 1 * N 2 ,<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where pp ij denotes the positive propagation probability between users v i and user v j , p a denotes adoption probability, p c denotes conforming probability, N 1 is the number of posts that are published by user v i , N 2 is the number of posts adopted by user v j , n is the number of posts adopted by v j from user v i , and n c is the number of posts whose sentiment is consistent with the sentiment expressed by user v i .</p><p>Definition 13. Negative propagation probability np is the probability that user v j adopts the information from user v i , and user v j holds the opposite opinion against user v i . Negative propagation probability is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">np ij = p a * (1 ? p c ) = ? 1 ? n c (10) n ? * n * n N 1 * N 2 = (n ? n c ) * n N 1 * N 2 ,</formula><p>where np ij denotes negative propagation probability between user v i and user v j , p a denotes the adoption probability, p c denotes the conforming probability, N 1 is the number of posts published by user v i , N 2 is the number of posts adopted by user v j , n is the number of posts adopted by v j from user v i , and n c is the number of posts whose sentiment is consistent with the sentiment expressed by user v i .</p><p>When more users become involved in discussions, other users may begin to hold different opinions in the network. Some users could change their minds when some in-neighbors hold opposite opinions. Transforming and stubborn probabilities are introduced to predict whether users change their minds. Prior to the introduction of probabilities, two weights, stubborn w ii and influential w ji , are introduced in the ego network to calculate these two probabilities. The definitions of stubborn weight w ii and influential weight w ji are expressed below. Given user v i , the sum of stubborn weight w ii and influential weight w ji is equal to 1, and is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">w ii + ? w ji = 1. (11) v j ¡ÊN in (v i )</formula><p>Here, w ii = 0 indicates that users are not insistent on their initial opinions and are easily influenced by neighbors. In this case, the proposed model is close to the IC model. In addition, w ii = 1 indicates that users are insistent and are not about to change their initial opinions. In this case, the proposed model is close to the IC-N model <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr">Das et al. [23]</ref>, stubborn weight is </p><formula xml:id="formula_9">w ii ¡Ý c * ? v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) w ji</formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">w ¡ä ji = p c ji .<label>(13)</label></formula><p>Temporary stubborn weight and temporary influential weight are satisfied in Eq. (12). Thus, temporary stubborn weight </p><formula xml:id="formula_11">ii + ? w v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) ji ¡ä w ji = w ji (c + 1) * ? w ¡ä v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) ji = p c ji (c + 1) * ? .<label>(15)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) p c ji<label>(16)</label></formula><p>Owing to the asymmetry between positive and negative influences, stubborn weight w p ii and negative stubborn weight w n ii are expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">w p ? n ? ii = c p * w ji and w ii = c n * w ji ,<label>(17)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) v j ¡ÊN in (v i )</formula><p>where c p denotes parameter c for positive influence, and c n denotes parameter c for negative influence.</p><p>Based on stubborn weight w ii and influential weight w ji , the sentiment of user v i at time t + 1 balances neighbors v j ¡Ê N in (v i ) and the sentiment of user v i at time t. We multiply stubborn weight w ii and the sentiment s i (t) of user v i at time t, influential weight w ji and neighbor sentiment s j (t). The equation is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">s i (t + 1) = f (s i (t), s j (t)) ? ? = sgn ? (18) ? w ii * s i (t) + w ji * s j (t) ? , v j ¡ÊN in (v i )</formula><p>where sgn( * ) is a sign function, w ii denotes the stubborn weight of user v i , and w ji denotes the influential weight when user v j ¡Ê N in (v i ) has an impact on user v i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Definition 16. Transforming probability p t represents how users change their opinions from one sentiment to another.</head><p>Here, p t1 denotes the transforming probability from positive to negative, whereas p t2 denotes the transforming probability from negative to positive.</p><p>Definition 17. Stubborn probability p s indicates that users keep their opinions even when neighbors hold different opinions. Similarly, we obtain two corresponding stubborn probabilities: p s1 denotes the probability that users keep positive opinions, and p s2 denotes the probability that users keep negative opinions.</p><p>Given user v i , the sum of transforming probability p t and stubborn probability p s is equal to 1, and is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">p t + p s = 1.<label>(19)</label></formula><p>Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">(19)</ref> is rewritten for the positive and the negative situations, which are expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">p t1 + p s1 = 1 or p t2 + p s2 = 1.<label>(20)</label></formula><p>Transforming probability p t1 from positive to negative is the sum of influential weights from negative in-neighbors, and is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">p t1 = ? w ji ,<label>(21)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_19">v j ¡ÊN n in (v i )</formula><p>where w ji is the influential weight from user v j to user v i , and v j ¡Ê N n in (v i ) denotes that user v j is a negative in-neighbor of user v i .</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr">Eq. (19)</ref>, stubborn probability p s1 is the sum of positive stubborn weight and influential weights from positive in-neighbors, and is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">p s1 = w p ? ii + w ji ,<label>(22)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_21">v j ¡ÊN p in (v i )</formula><p>where w p p ii is the stubborn weight for the positive, w ji is the influential weight from user v j to user v i , and v j ¡Ê N in (v i ) denotes that user v j is a positive in-neighbor of user v i .</p><p>Similarly, transforming probability p t2 from the negative to the positive requires the sum of influential weights of positive in-neighbors N p in (v i ). Stubborn probability p s2 for the negative is the sum of negative stubborn weight and influential weights from negative in-neighbors. These relations are respectively expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">p t2 = ? w ji ,<label>(23)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_23">v j ¡ÊN p in (v i ) p s2 = w n ? ii + w ji . (24) v j ¡ÊN n in (v i )</formula><p>In conclusion, the process of information spreading follows a certain procedure discussed here. First, within a network, users are categorized into three classes, namely, inactive (I), positive (P), and negative (N). Users transfer from one class to another based on probabilities. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 2</ref>  When the in-neighbors N in (v j ) of user v j hold opposite opinions, and they have a profound impact on user v j , user v j could change his initial opinion. If user v j is positive at time t, he keeps a positive opinion at time t + 1 with stubborn probability p s1 and changes to negative opinion with transforming probability p t1 . However, if user v j is negative at time t, he keeps a negative opinion with stubborn probability p s2 and holds a positive opinion at time t + 1 with transforming probability p t2 .</p><p>Probabilities are introduced to calculate positive influence. The shortest path from path min (S, v i ) is introduced to calculate initial opinions. The probability P(s 0 = 1) that the initial opinion of user v i is positive depends on probabilities among users path min (v i ) = ?v 1 , v 2 , . . . , v lmin , v i ? in the shortest path. This path is defined as where pp l min ,i denotes positive propagation probability between users v l min and v i , and pp j,j+1 denotes positive propagation probability between users v j and v j+1 .</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">l min ?1 P(s 0 = 1) = pp l min ,i * ? pp j,j+1 , (25) j=1</formula><p>The probability P(s 0 = ?1) that the initial opinion of user v i is negative is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">l min ?1 P(s 0 = ?1) = np l min ,i * ? pp j,j+1 ,<label>(26)</label></formula><p>j=1 where np l min ,i denotes the negative propagation probability between users v l min and v i , and pp j,j+1 denotes the positive propagation probability between users v j and v j+1 .</p><p>After user v i obtains an initial opinion, user v i updates this opinion when his in-neighbors update their views. We calculate probability P(s t+1 = 1), in which user v i holds positive opinion at time step t + 1 after he forms an initial opinion. Two cases lead to this situation. First, user v i holds positive opinion at time step t and still keeps positive at time step t + 1. Second, user v i holds negative opinion at time step t and changes to be positive at time step t + 1. This process is explained by</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">P(s t+1 = 1) = ? P(s t = 1) * p s1 , s t = 1 P(s t = ?1) * p t2 , s t = ?1,<label>(27)</label></formula><p>where P(s t = 1) denotes the probability that user v i holds a positive opinion at time step t, P(s t = ?1) denotes the probability that user v i holds a negative opinion at time step t, p s1 denotes the stubborn probability for positive opinions, and p t2 denotes the transforming probability from negative to positive.</p><p>Similarly, we calculate probability P(s t+1 = ?1) that the opinion of user v i is negative at time step t + 1. Two cases lead to this situation. First, user v i holds negative opinion and retains the negative view at time step t + 1. Second, user v i holds positive opinion at time step t, but changes to be negative at time step t + 1. Specifically, this probability is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">P(s t+1 = ?1) = ? P(s t = 1) * p t1 , s t = 1 P(s t = ?1) * p s2 , s t = ?1,<label>(28)</label></formula><p>where P(s t = ?1) and P(s t = 1) denote the probability that user v i holds negative and positive opinions at time step t, respectively, p s2 denotes the stubborn probability that user v i keeps the negative opinion, and p t1 denotes the transforming probability that user v i changes the opinion from positive to negative opinion. The algorithm is presented as Algorithm 1. Based on influence graph G = (V , E), the number of influential users is given as k. The number of influential users who have maximum positive influence is then calculated. Based on the class to which user v belongs, we could now predict the class to which user v will belong at the next time step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2.">Properties of the IMIC-OC model</head><p>The IMIC-OC model for influence maximization is NP-hard. Here, we mainly describe some properties of IMIC-OC model, such as monotonicity and submodularity. Theorem 1. Given influence graph G = (V , E), the maximum positive influence ¦Õ m (S) is monotone, and is expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡Ý 0. (29)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 IMIC-OC</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Input: G = (V , E), an expected number k of influential users S</head><p>Output: Influential users S 1: Let S = ?, S * = ? 2: for iter=1:k do 3:</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">for each u ¡Ê V \ S do 4: set S * = S ? {u} 5:</formula><p>for each v ¡Ê N out (u) do <ref type="bibr">6:</ref> if v ¡Ê I then <ref type="bibr">7:</ref> calculate path min <ref type="bibr">(S, v)</ref> 8:</p><p>generate random value r 1 9:</p><p>if r 1 &lt; P(s 0 = 1) then 10:   </p><formula xml:id="formula_30">P = P ? {v} 11: ¦Õ(S * ) = ¦Õ(S * ) ?</formula><formula xml:id="formula_31">P = P \ {v}, N = N ? {v} 23: ¦Õ(S * ) = ¦Õ(S * ) \</formula><formula xml:id="formula_32">P = P ? {v}, N = N \ {v} 30: ¦Õ(S * ) = ¦Õ(S * ) ?</formula><formula xml:id="formula_33">S = S ? {argmax u¡ÊV \S |¦Õ(S * )|}, S * = S 36: end for</formula><p>Proof. We obtain a set of influential users S and user u ¡Ê V \ S. We calculate ¦Õ m (S) at step 1 and ¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) at step 2. Here, v s1 denotes the state of user v at step 1 and v s2 denotes the state of user v at step 2. With such information, we</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">obtain ¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) = |{v|v s1 ¡Ê I, v s2 ¡Ê P}| + |{v|v s1 ¡Ê N, v s2 ¡Ê P}| ? ?? ? ,<label>(30)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_35">1 ? |{v|v s1 ¡Ê P, v s2 ¡Ê N}| ? ?? ? 2</formula><p>where v ¡Ê I denotes that user v is inactive, v ¡Ê P denotes that user v holds a positive opinion, and v ¡Ê N denotes user v holds a negative opinion.</p><p>The result of Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">(30)</ref> is based on which part is larger in the right side of this equation. During information spreading, the most important function is to activate neighbors. Stubborn weight adds difficulty to changing minds from negative to positive than to activating inactive neighbors. Thus, the number of users who change opinions is smaller than the number of users who are activated. In other words, part 1 is larger than part 2, that is, ¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡Ý 0. Hence, if we enlarge the number of influential users S, positive influence increases in the network. In conclusion, ¦Õ m (S) is monotone.</p><p>Theorem 2. Given any influence graph G = (V , E), the maximum positive influence ¦Õ m (S) is submodular, and is expressed as Statistical data of the three real-world networks.</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡Ý ¦Õ m (T ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (T ) if S ? T ? V and u ¡Ê V \ T .<label>(31)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dataset</head><p>Facebook <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">HEP-PH  Epinions   Number of nodes  14,980  34,546  75,879  Number of edges  14,359</ref> 421,578 508,837 Average degree 4.58 13.11 8.43</p><p>Proof. We obtain two sets of influential users, S and T , S ? T ? V , and user u ¡Ê V \ T . Maximum positive influence ¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) and ¦Õ m (T ¡È {u}) are expressed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) = ¦Õ m (S) + ¦Õ m ({u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}), (32) ¦Õ m (T ¡È {u}) = ¦Õ m (T ) + ¦Õ m ({u}) ? ¦Õ m (T ) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}).<label>(33)</label></formula><p>According to Eqs. <ref type="formula">(32)</ref> and <ref type="formula" target="#formula_37">(33)</ref>, we could obtain</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) = ¦Õ m ({u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}) and ¦Õ m (T ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (T ) = ¦Õ m ({u}) ? ¦Õ m (T ) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}). Thus, the result depends on which is larger, ¦Õ m (S) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}) or ¦Õ m (T ) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}). According to Theorem 1, ¦Õ m (S) is monotone, such that ¦Õ m (T ) ¡Ý ¦Õ m (S) if S ? T ? V . We obtain ¦Õ m (S) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}) ¡Ü ¦Õ m (T ) ¡É ¦Õ m ({u}). Thus, ¦Õ m (S ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (S) ¡Ý ¦Õ m (T ¡È {u}) ? ¦Õ m (T ) if S ? T ? V and u ¡Ê V \ T .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Datasets</head><p>We crawled the data in Facebook from March 18th to March 28th, 2014 on a specific topic. Our dataset includes 14,980 users, 1,955 posts, 9,721 comments, and 22,078 likes. We assume that if users like a post, then they have the same opinions as the authors of the original posts. We utilize the dataset from Facebook to validate the IC-OC model, and to find influential users S. We also use two other real networks to find influential users S. First, HEP-PH, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> which is an undirected graph, is the co-authorship graph from the ''high energy physics phenomenology'' section in the e-print, arXiv.</p><p>5 Second, the dataset of Epinions, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> which is a directed graph, is a who-trust-whom online social network of a general consumer review site, Epinions.</p><p>7 <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 1</ref> illustrates the basic information of the three real networks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Parameter estimation</head><p>The probabilities in the process of information spreading are estimated in this section. <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref> exhibits the distribution of adoption probability p a , which follows power-law distribution. <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref> indicates the distribution of conforming probability p c . Therefore, we obtain the distribution of positive propagation probability pp in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 5</ref>, which also follows power-law distribution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Validation of the IC-OC model</head><p>The comparison of the proposed model and baseline methods is made to prove that the proposed model performs better than the baseline methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.1.">Baseline methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IC-N:</head><p>Proposed by Chen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, this algorithm assumes that users would not change their opinions after they obtained initial opinions.</p><p>LT-IO: Proposed by Li et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>, this novel linear threshold model (LT) is used for modeling information spreading; it introduces broadcast and current attitude in considering user attitude modification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.2.">Performance of the IC-OC model</head><p>We examine the performances of adoption and positive cascades. Adoption cascades denote the number of users who adopt the information, while positive cascades indicate the number of users who hold positive opinions in the final state.</p><p>Coefficient of determination (R 2 ), sum of square for errors (SSE), and root-mean-square error (RMSE) are adopted to determine the performance for adoption cascades ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 2)</ref> and for positive cascades (  IC-OC model has better performance, compared with the baseline methods. Relative to adoption cascades, the IC-OC model has 10.5% and 11.6% improvements compared with the IC-N and LT-IO models, respectively. Relative to positive cascades, the IC-OC model has 3.1% and 20.8% improvements compared with the IC-N and LT-IO models, respectively. Performance metrics are defined as   where X is a series of values to be predicted, x i is the ith value in series X , ? x is the mean of series X , and?xand? and?x i is the predicted value of x i .</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">n ? (? x i ? ? x) 2 R 2 = i=0 n ,<label>(34)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_40">? (x i ? ? x) 2 i=0 n SSE = ? (x i ? ? x i ) 2 ,<label>(35)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_41">i=0 ? n ? ? 2 x i ? ? x i RMSE = ? ? ? ? ? i=0<label>(36)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.">Influence maximization</head><p>First, we investigate how parameter c affects positive influence. Second, influential users are found in three real networks, which are Facebook, HEP-PH, and Epinions. The results of maximum positive influence, which are obtained using different methods, are shown in this section. Experimental results manifest that the IMIC-OC model calculated the largest maximum positive influence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.1.">Parameter analysis</head><p>Parameter c has an impact on stubborn weight w ii , which represents how users keep their initial opinions. A greater parameter c value indicates that users have stronger willingness to keep their initial opinions. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Fig. 6</ref> illustrates maximum positive influence with respect to parameter c by varying the number of influential users from 1 to 50. This figure shows that positive influence increases as parameter c rises. Thus, increasing parameter c has greater positive influence and smaller marginal increments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.2.">Baseline methods</head><p>Random: An algorithm selects k influential users randomly from entire users V .</p><p>MaxDegree: An algorithm selects top-k users who have maximum out-degrees as influential users.</p><p>Greedy: An algorithm obtains approximate solution of influence maximization.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.3.">Comparisons among algorithms</head><p>The performances of the IMIC-OC model and baseline methods are discussed in this sub-section. Maximum positive influence ¦Õ m (S) is calculated by varying the number of influential users from 1 to 50. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Fig. 7</ref> shows that on Facebook, the maximum positive influence of the IMIC-OC model is close to the Greedy model. In addition, the Random model has the smallest maximum positive influence among these algorithms, and the positive influence of the MaxDegree model is smaller than the IMIC-OC model. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Fig. 8</ref> exhibits the maximum positive influence on NEP-PH. The result is similar with that from the Facebook dataset. On Epinions, the maximum positive influence of the MaxDegree model is close to the IMIC-OC model in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Fig. 9</ref>. This result depends on the structure of the network, suggesting that users who have higher degrees are more influential in this network.</p><p>In conclusion, the Random model has the worst performance among the three real networks; hence, this model is not feasible in calculating maximum positive influence. The result of the MaxDegree model depends on the structure of the network. If influential users have high degrees, the result of the MaxDegree model is close to the IMIC-OC model. The result of the IMIC-OC model is close to the Greedy model in all three networks, indicating that the IMIC-OC model is feasible in calculating maximum positive influence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>The proposed IMIC-OC model for influence maximization aims to find a set of users who maximize the adoption of information. Further, the IC-OC model for information spreading is proposed to explain how users build their opinions.</p><p>The IC-OC model introduces stubborn and transforming probabilities. These probabilities are used to predict whether users would change initial opinions when exposed to different opinions. At the beginning, information spreaders activate  their neighbors to adopt information based on adoption probability. Conforming probability denotes how neighbors keep the same opinions as the users who spread information. As time passes, different opinions emerge in the network. Users could then possibly change their minds by transforming probability or keep the same opinions by stubborn probability.</p><p>Next, we verify the IC-OC model on the Facebook dataset. Results show that the IC-OC model has better performance than the baseline methods. Relative to adoption cascades, the IC-OC model has 10.5% and 11.6% improvements compared with the IC-N and LT-IO models, respectively. Meanwhile, relative to positive cascades, the IC-OC model has 3.1% and 20.8% improvements compared with the same baseline methods, respectively.</p><p>The IMIC-OC model for influence maximization is proposed to find influential users. The minimum path to calculating initial opinions of users is obtained first. Then, we update user opinions at each step until no neighbor changes opinion. Ultimately, users who activate maximum positive influence are selected as influential users. Positive influence is calculated based on three real networks. The analyses of Facebook and NET-PH data yield similar results. Meanwhile, the Random model has the worst performance, while the IMIC-OC model has the largest maximum positive influence. The IMIC-OC model is close to the Greedy model, which proves that the IMIC-OC model is a feasible method in calculating positive influence. However, results from Epinions exhibit a difference. The MaxDegree model is close to the IMIC-OC model, indicating that more influential users have more degrees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Universities of China (Grant No. 2014RC0501), Natural Science Foundation of China (No. 61402045), and Specialized</head><p>Research Fund for Doctoral <ref type="bibr">Program of Higher Education (No. 20130005110011)</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Structure of the influence graph.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>denotes the cardinality of *. In Eq. (2), N i p n out (v), N out (v), and N out (v) denote inactive, positive and negative out-neighbors, respectively. The term is expressed as |N out (v)| = |N i p n out (v)| + |N out (v)| + |N out (v)|. (2) In Eq. (3), N i p n in (v), N in (v), and N in (v) denote inactive, positive and negative in-neighbors, respectively. We then obtain</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Definition 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Sentiment s i (t) denotes the sentiment of user v i at time t. Here, s i (t) ¡Ê {?1, 1} represents negative and positive sentiments, respectively. Definition 6. Influential users S refers to a set of users that has a profound impact on activating other users. The number of influential users is given as |S| = k. Definition 7. Positive influence ¦Õ(S) denotes a set of users with positive opinions, which are the same as influential users S. Positive influence is defined as</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>According to Chen et al. [3], negative and positive influences are not symmetric. If the initial opinion of user v i is positive, users easily change to negative opinions. If user v i initially holds a negative opinion, user v i hardly changes to a positive one.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Definition 14.</head><label></label><figDesc>Stubborn weight w ii represents how user v i adheres to his opinion. Definition 15. Influential weight w ji represents how user v j ¡Ê N in (v i ) influences user v i .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>w ¡ä ii is calculated by w ¡ä ? ¡ä ii = c * w ji . (14) v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) Stubborn weight w ii and influential weight w ji are the normalizations of w ¡ä ¡ä ii and w ji , respectively, and are expressed as ¡ä w ii = w ii c w ¡ä ¡ä = c + 1 ,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Probabilities used in information spreading.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Fig. 3 .Fig. 4 .</head><label>34</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Distribution of adoption probability p a .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. Distribution of positive propagation probability pp.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Fig. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6. How positive influence changes with different parameter c.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Fig. 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Fig. 7. The positive influence in Facebook.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Fig. 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Fig. 8. The positive influence in HEP-PH.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Fig. 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Fig. 9. The positive influence in Epinions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>where parameter c ¡Ý 0.25. We discuss the case w ii = c * ? w ji where c ¡Ý 0.25. (12) v j ¡ÊN in (v i ) w ¡ä ¡ä ii and w ji denote temporary stubborn and temporary influential weights, respectively, to calculate w ii and w ji . Temporary influential weight w ¡ä ji is equal to conforming probability p c ji , as shown in Eq. (13)</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>shows entire probabilities used in the process of information spreading. At time t, user v i publishes a positive post, which is visible to out-neighbors N out (v i ) of user v i . User v j ¡Ê N out (v i ) adopts this information with adoption probability p a . Then, user v j holds positive opinion with conforming probability p c after user v i adopts this information. Thus, user v j ¡Ê N p out (v i ) adopts a positive opinion with positive propagation probability pp. Meanwhile, user v j ¡Ê N n i out (v i ) holds a negative opinion with negative propagation probability np. User v j ¡Ê N out (v i ) remains inactive with probability (1 ? p a ). As time passes, more users become involved in discussions, and some users present different opinions.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>3 &lt; p t1 then 22:</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>{v} 

12: 

else 

13: 

generate random value r 2 

14: 

if r 2 &lt; P(s 0 = ?1) then 

15: 

N = N 
? 
{v} 

16: 

end if 

17: 

end if 

18: 

end if 

19: 

if v ¡Ê P then 

20: 

generate random value r 3 

21: 

if r </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>3 &lt; p t2 then 29:</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>{v} 

24: 

end if 

25: 

end if 

26: 

if v ¡Ê N then 

27: 

generate random value r 4 

28: 

if r </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 3 ). The IC-OC model has greater R 2 values as well as smaller SSE and RMSE values for both adoption and positive cascades. These results indicate that the</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>4 http://snap.stanford.edu/data/cit-HepPh.html. 

5 http://www.arXiv.org. 

6 http://snap.stanford.edu/data/soc-Epinions1.html. 

7 http://www.epinions.com. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 2 Performance for adoption cascades.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 
R 

2 

SSE 
RMSE 

LT-IO 
0.5923 
163,502 
11.8467 
IC-N 
0.6035 
159,045 
11.6841 
IC-OC 
0.7086 
116,864 
10.0156 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 3 Performance for positive cascades.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 
R 

2 

SSE 
RMSE 

LT-IO 
0.5231 
142,056 
11.0425 
IC-N 
0.7000 
89,380 
8.7591 
IC-OC 
0.7311 
80,110 
8.2924 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.facebook.com. 2 http://www.twitter.com. 3 http://www.weibo.com.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing product adoption in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bhagat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lakhmanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="603" to="612" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cummings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rincon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 15th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization in social networks when negative opinions may emerge and propagate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th SIAM International Conference on Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 11th SIAM International Conference on Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization: Near-optimal time complexity meets practical efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to influence people with partial incentives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Demaine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hajiaghayi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Mahini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Malec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R A</forename><surname>Sawant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zadimoghadam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="937" to="948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sketch-based influence maximization and computation: Scaling up with guarantees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Delling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pajor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Werneck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd ACM International Conference on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd ACM International Conference on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="638" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Least cost influence maximization across multiple social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Thai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Celf++: Optimizing the greedy algorithm for influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lakshmanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th International Conference Companion on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 20th International Conference Companion on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smg: Fast scalable greedy algorithm for influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Heidari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Asadpour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Faili</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physica A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">420</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient location-aware influence maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influential nodes selection: a data reconstruction perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research &amp; Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research &amp; Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="879" to="882" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imrank: Influence maximization via finding self-consistent ranking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="484" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the long-term integral influence in social networks under the voter model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Companion Publication of the 23rd International Conference on World Wide Web Companion</title>
		<meeting>the Companion Publication of the 23rd International Conference on World Wide Web Companion</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="424" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coritivity-based influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physica A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">416</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="480" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformity-aware influence maximization in online social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bhowmick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">VLDB J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="141" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence ranking in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="535" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personalized influence maximization on social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd ACM International Conference on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd ACM International Conference on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A query approach for influence maximization on specific users in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-R</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-W</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="340" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization in social networks with user attitude modification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Conference on Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3913" to="3918" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of selective attention on continuous opinions and discrete decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Si</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physica A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">389</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3711" to="3719" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical analysis of interpersonal interacting behavior in virtual community</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Si</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Phys. Sin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">78903</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling opinion dynamics in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gollapudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Munagala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural algorithms and influence systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chazelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model for spatial conflict</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Sudbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="588" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ergodic theorems for weakly interacting infinite systems and the voter model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liggett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Probab</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="663" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Freezing period strongly impacts the emergence of a global consensus in the voter model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3597</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
