<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Link Analysis Algorithm for Web Structure Mining</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-08">August 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Assistant Professor,</roleName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nithya</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dr. N G P Arts and Science College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Coimbatore</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Link Analysis Algorithm for Web Structure Mining</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer and Communication Engineering</title>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
							<date type="published" when="2013-08">August 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>ISSN (Print) : 2319-5940 ISSN (Online) : 2278-1021</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Web Mining</term>
					<term>Web Structure</term>
					<term>PageRank</term>
					<term>Weighted PageRank and Hyper-link Induced Topic Search</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>As the web is growing rapidly, the users get easily lost in the web&apos;s rich hyper structure. The primary goal of the web site owner is to provide the relevant information to the users to fulfill their needs. Web mining technique is used to categorize users and pages by analyzing users behavior, the content of pages and order of URLs accessed. Web Structure Mining plays an important role in this approach. In this paper gives an introduction to Web mining, then describes Web Structure mining in detail, and explores the data structure used by the Web. This paper also explores different algorithms and compares those algorithms used for Information Retrieval.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>The World Wide Web is a rich source of information and continues to expand in size and complexity. Retrieving of the required web page on the web, efficiently and effectively, is becoming a Challenge. Whenever a user wants to search the relevant pages, he/she prefers those relevant pages to be at hand. The bulk amount of information becomes very difficult for the users to find, extract, filter or evaluate the relevant information. This issue raises the necessity of some technique that can solve these challenges. Web mining can be easily executed with the help of other areas like Database (DB), Information retrieval (IR), Natural Language Processing (NLP), and Machine Learning etc. The following challenges <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> in Web Mining are:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Web Mining Process</head><p>The complete process of extracting knowledge from Web data is follows in <ref type="figure">Fig.1</ref> The World Wide Web has grown in the past few years from a small research community to the biggest and most popular way of communication and information dissemination. Every day, the WWW grows by roughly a million electronic pages, adding to the hundreds of millions already on-line. WWW serves as a platform for exchanging various kinds of information, ranging from research papers, and educational content, to multimedia content and software. The continuous growth in the size and the use of the WWW imposes new methods for processing these huge amounts of data. Moreover, the content is published in various diverse formats. Due to this fact, users are feeling sometimes disoriented, lost in that information overload that continues to expand. Web mining is a very broad research area emerging to solve the issues that arise due to the WWW phenomenon. The challenge for Web structure mining is to deal with the structure of the hyperlinks within the Web itself. Link analysis is an old area of research. However, with the growing interest in Web mining, the research of structure analysis had increased and these efforts had resulted in a newly emerging research area called Link Mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, which is located at the intersection of the work in link analysis, hypertext and web mining, relational learning and inductive logic programming, and graph mining. There is a potentially wide range of application areas for this new area of research, including Internet. The Web contains a variety of objects with almost no unifying structure, with differences in the authoring style and content much greater than in traditional collections of text documents. The objects in the WWW are web pages, and links are in-, out-and cocitation (two pages that are both linked to by the same page). Attributes include HTML tags, word appearances and anchor texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. This diversity of objects creates new problems and challenges, since is not possible to directly made use of existing techniques such as from database management or information retrieval. Link mining had produced some agitation on some of the traditional data mining tasks. Some of the following possible tasks of link mining applicable in Web structure mining. 1.Link-based Classification. Link-based classification is the most recent upgrade of a classic data mining task to linked domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The task is to focus on the prediction of the category of a web page, based on words that occur on the page, links between pages, anchor text, html tags and other possible attributes found on the web page. 2.Link-based Cluster Analysis. The goal in cluster analysis is to find naturally occurring sub-classes. The data is segmented into groups, where similar objects are grouped together, and dissimilar objects are grouped into different groups. Different than the previous task, linkbased cluster analysis is unsupervised and can be used to discover hidden patterns from data. 3.Link Type. There are a wide range of tasks concerning the prediction of the existence of links, such as Predicting the type of link between two entities, or predicting the purpose of a link. 4.Link Strength. Links could be associated with weights. 5.Link Cardinality. The main task here is to predict the number of links between objects. There are many ways to use the link structure of the Web to create notions of authority. The main goal in developing applications for link mining is to made good use of the understanding of these intrinsic social organization of the Web.</p><p>overlaps substantially with other areas, including data mining, text mining, information retrieval, and Web retrieval. The classification is based on two aspects: the purpose and the data sources. Retrieval research focuses on retrieving relevant, existing data or documents from a large database or document repository, while mining research focuses on discovering new information or knowledge in the data. On the basis of this, Web mining can be classified into web structure mining, web content mining, and web usage mining as shown in  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Web Content Mining</head><p>Web content mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>[6] aims to extract/mine useful information or knowledge from web page contents. Web content mining is related but different from data mining and text mining. It is related to data mining because many data mining techniques can be applied in Web content mining. It is related to text mining because much of the web contents are texts. However, it is also quite different from data mining because Web data are mainly semistructured and/or unstructured, while data mining deals primarily with structured data. Web content mining is also different from text mining because of the semi-structure nature of the Web, while text mining focuses on unstructured texts. Web content mining thus requires creative applications of data mining and/or text mining techniques and also its own unique approaches. The technologies that are normally used in web content mining are NLP (Natural language processing) and IR (Information retrieval).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Web Structure Mining</head><p>It is the process by which we discover the model of link Structure of the web pages. We catalog the links, generate the information such as the similarity and relations among them by taking the advantage of hyperlink topology. PageRank and hyperlink analysis also fall in this category. The goal of Web Structure Mining is to generate structured summary about the website and web page. It tries to discover the link structure of hyper links at inter document level. As it is very common that the web documents contain links and they use both the real or primary data on the web so it can be concluded that Web Structure Mining has a relation with Web Content Mining.</p><p>It is quite often to combine these two mining tasks in an application.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C.Web Usage Mining</head><p>Web Usage Mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> is the process by which we identify the browsing patterns by analyzing the navigational behavior of user. It focuses on techniques that can be used to predict the user behavior while the user interacts with the web. It uses the secondary data on the web. This activity involves the automatic discovery of user access patterns from one or more web servers. Through this mining technique we can ascertain what users are looking for on Internet. It consists of three phases, namely preprocessing, pattern discovery, and pattern analysis. Web servers, proxies, and client applications can quite easily capture data about Web usage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V.LINK ANALYSIS ALGORITHMS</head><p>Web mining technique provides the additional information through hyperlinks where different documents are connected. We can view the web as a directed labeled graph whose nodes are the documents or pages and edges are the hyperlinks between them .This directed graph structure is known as web graph. There are number of algorithms proposed based on link analysis. Four important algorithms PageRank, Weighted PageRank and HITS are discussed below: V(A)PageRank This algorithm was developed by Brin and Page at Stanford University which extends the idea of citation analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. In citation analysis the incoming links are treated as citations but this technique could not provide fruitful results because this gives some approximation of importance of page. So PageRank <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> provides a better approach that can compute the importance of web page by simply counting the number of pages that are linking to it. These links are called as backlinks.If a backlink comes from an important page than this link is given higher weightage than those which are coming from nonimportant pages. The link from one page to another is considered as a vote. Not only the number of votes that a page receives is important but the importance of pages that casts the vote is also important. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V(B) Weighted PageRank</head><p>Extended PageRank algorithm-Weighted PageRank assigns large rank value to more important pages instead of dividing the rank value of a page evenly among its outlink pages. The importance is assigned in terms of weight values to incoming and outgoing links denoted as and respectively. It is calculated on the basis of number of incoming links to page n and the number of incoming links to all reference pages of page m¡­¡­ <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> In is number of incoming links of page n, Ip is number of incoming links of page p, R(m) is the reference page list of page m. is calculated on the basis of the number of outgoing links of page n and the number of outgoing links of all the reference pages of page m¡­..</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(3) On is number of outgoing links of page n, Op is number of outgoing links of page p, Then the weighted PageRank is given by following formula WPR (n) = (1-d) +d¡­¡­ (4) V (C) Hyper-link Induced Topic Search (HITS)</head><p>Klienberg gives two forms of web pages called as hubs and authorities. Hubs are the pages that act as resource lists. Authorities are pages having important contents. A good hub page is a page which is pointing to many authoritative pages on that content and a good authority page is a page which is pointed by many good hub pages on the same content. A page may be a good hub and a good authority at the same time <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>[13] <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. The HITS algorithm treats WWW as directed graph G(V,E), where V is a set of vertices representing pages and E is set of edges corresponds to link. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows the hubs and authorities in web </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hp =¦² Aq</head><p>A p =¦² Hq</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">q ¦Å I ( p) q ¦Å B ( p)</formula><p>Here Hq is Hub Score of a page, Aq is authority score of a page, I(p) is set of reference pages of page p and B(p) is set of referrer pages of page p, the authority weight of a page is proportional to the sum of hub weights of pages that link to it. Similarly a hub of a page is proportional to the sum of authority weights of pages that it links to.</p><p>Constraints with HITS algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> Hubs and authorities: It is not easy to distinguish between hubs and authorities because many sites are hubs as well as authorities.</p><p>Topic drift: Sometime HITS may not produce the most relevant documents to the user queries because of equivalent weights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer and Communication Engineering Vol. 2, Issue 8, August 2013</head><p>Automatically generated links: HITS gives equal importance for automatically generated links which May not have relevant topics for the user query Efficiency: HITS algorithm is not efficient in real-time. HITS was used in a prototype search engine called Clever for an IBM research project. Because of the above constraints HITS could not be implemented in a real time searchengine.</p><p>distributes rank scores based on the popularity of the pages. HITS helps to rating Web pages also known as Hubs and authorities .it also performs a series of iterations, each consisting of two basic steps such as Authority pages and hub pages but PageRank only focus on the authoritative pages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>REFERENCES</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Search Engine</head><p>Google Google Clever</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VII. RESULTS</head><p>The PageRank is calculated depend on numerous factors such as content, back links, anchor text, site structure, external links, images, alt tags, optimization of the website, traffic of the website etc. If a website having PageRank of more than 3 then it is said to be good website. But if a website having PageRank of more than 5 than the website is getting great traffic and the overall performance or the structure of website is good enough.PageRank is good but sometimes it leaves a bad thoughts in the mind of people because if search on google most of the website are having low PageRank i.e 2 or 3 or sometimes 0 and it is coming on top of the page of google. Weighted PageRank is an extension to the PageRank algorithm.it takes into account the importance of both the inlinks and the outlinks of the pages and</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: Web Mining Categories</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Page and Brin proposed a formula to calculate the PageRankof a page A as stated below- PR(A)= (1-d)+d(PR(T1)/C(T1)+¡­..+PR(Tn/C(Tn)) .....(1) Here PR(Ti) is the PageRank of the Pages Ti which links to page A, C(Ti) is number of outlinks on page Ti and d is damping factor. It is used to stop other pages having too much influence. The PageRank forms a probability distribution over the web pages so the sum of PageRanks of all web pages will be one. The PageRank of a page can be calculated without knowing the final value of PageRank of other pages. It is an iterative algorithm which follows the principle of normalized link matrix of web. PageRank of a page depends on the number of pages pointing to a page.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Hubs Authorities Fig. 3: Hubs and Authorities Following expressions are used to calculate the weight of Hub (Hp) and the weight of Authority (Ap).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>:</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Mining 
Representation 
Tools 
&amp;Visualization 

Raw 
data 

Patterns 
Knowle 
dge 

Fig. 1: Web Mining Process 

1) Web is huge. 
2) Web pages are semi structured. 
3) Web information stands to be diversity in meaning. 
4) Degree of quality of the information extracted. 
5) Conclusion of knowledge from information extracted. 

This paper is organized as follows-Web Mining is 
introduced in Section II. The related works are discussed 
in section III.The areas of Web Mining i.e. Web Content 
Mining, Web Structure Mining and Web Usage Mining 
are discussed in Section IV. Section V describes the 
various Link analysis algorithms. Section VI provides the 
comparison of various Link Analysis Algorithms and 
section VII discussed results and conclusion. 

To clarify the confusion of what forms Web mining. 
Kosala and Blockeel [3] had suggested a decomposition of 
Web mining in the following tasks: 
1. Resource finding: It is the task of retrieving intended 
web documents. 
2.Information selection and pre-processing: Automatically 
selecting and pre-processing specific from information 
retrieved Web resources. 
3.Generalization: Automatically discovers general 
patterns at individual Web site as well as multiple sites. 
4. Analysis: Validation and interpretation of the mined 
patterns. 

III.RELATED WORK 

II. WEB MINING 
Web mining is the Data Mining technique that 
automatically discovers or extracts the information from 
web documents. It is the extraction of interesting and 
potentially useful patterns and implicit information from 
artifacts or activity related to the World Wide Web. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot">Copyright to IJARCCE www.ijarcce.com</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Da Gomes</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Web Structure Mining:An Introduction, Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Information Acquisition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Comparative Study of PageRanking Algorithms for Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashutosh Kumar</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ravi</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International journal of electrical and computer engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web Mining Research: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Kosala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hendrik</forename><surname>Blockeel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGKDD Explorations Newsletter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Issue 1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PagNing Tan,Web Usage Mining: Discovery and Applications of Usage Patterns from Web Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaideep</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Cooley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mukund</forename><surname>Deshpande</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGKDD Explorations Newsletter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Issue 2</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Link Mining: A New Data Mining Challenge. SIGKDD Explorations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web mining: Knowledge discovery on the Web Systems&quot;, Man and Cybernetics 1999 IEEE SMC 99 conference Proceedings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huang</forename><surname>Wang Jicheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wu</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename><surname>Gangshan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fuyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE International conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Link-based classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICML-03</title>
		<meeting>ICML-03</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PageRanking Algorithms for Web Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rekha</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Dr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Purohit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computer application</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weighted Page Content Rank For Ordering Web Search Result</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pooja</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawan</forename><surname>Bhadana</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Engineering Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-Sensitive PageRank: A ContextSensitive Ranking Algorithms for Web Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Taher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Haveliwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Duhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">PageRanking Algorithms: A Survey, Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Advance Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-Sensitive PageRank: A ContextSensitive Ranking Algorithms for Web Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Taher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Haveliwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Duhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">PageRanking Algorithms: A Survey, Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Advance Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Husbands</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Link analysis: Hubs and authorities on the world</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">47847</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web Structure Mining Exploring Hyperlinks and Algorithms for Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P Ravi</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Singh Ashutosh</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of applied sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="840" to="845" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Authoritative sources in a hyperlinked environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Klienberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="604" to="632" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chakrabarti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining the Link Structure of the World Wide Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rajagopalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tomkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
