<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-16T23:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the Spread of Influence through a Social Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
							<email>kempe@cs.cornell.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ithaca</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
							<email>kleinber@cs.cornell.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ithaca</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cornell University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ithaca</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the Spread of Influence through a Social Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Keywords Models for the processes by which ideas and influence propagate through a social network have been studied in a number of domains , including the diffusion of medical and technological innovations , the sudden and widespread adoption of various strategies in game-theoretic settings, and the effects of &quot;word of mouth&quot; in the promotion of new products. Recently, motivated by the design of viral marketing strategies, Domingos and Richardson posed a fundamental algorithmic problem for such social network processes: if we can try to convince a subset of individuals to adopt a new product or innovation, and the goal is to trigger a large cascade of further adoptions, which set of individuals should we target? We consider this problem in several of the most widely studied models in social network analysis. The optimization problem of selecting the most influential nodes is NP-hard here, and we provide the first provable approximation guarantees for efficient algorithms. Using an analysis framework based on submodular functions , we show that a natural greedy strategy obtains a solution that is provably within 63% of optimal for several classes of models; our framework suggests a general approach for reasoning about the performance guarantees of algorithms for these types of influence problems in social networks. We also provide computational experiments on large collaboration networks, showing that in addition to their provable guarantees , our approximation algorithms significantly out-perform node-selection heuristics based on the well-studied notions of degree centrality and distance centrality from the field of social networks. approximation algorithms, social networks, viral marketing, diffusion of innovations</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">APPROXIMATION GUARANTEES IN THE INDEPENDENT CASCADE AND LINEAR THRESHOLD MODELS</head><p>The overall approach. We begin by describing our strategy for proving approximation guarantees. Consider an arbitrary function f (﹞) that maps subsets of a finite ground set U to non-negative real numbers. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> We say that f is submodular if it satisfies a natural "diminishing returns" property: the marginal gain from adding an element to a set S is at least as high as the marginal gain from adding Due to its generality, this result has found applications in a number of areas of discrete optimization (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>); the only direct use of it that we are aware of in the databases and data mining literature is in a context very different from ours, for the problem of selecting database views to materialize <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>.</p><p>Our strategy will be to show that for the models we are considering, the resulting influence function 考(﹞) is submodular. A subtle difficulty lies in the fact that the result of Nemhauser et al. assumes that the greedy algorithm can evaluate the underlying function exactly, which may not be the case for the influence function 考(A). However, by simulating the diffusion process and sampling the resulting active sets, we are able to obtain arbitrarily close approximations to 考(A), with high probability. Furthermore, one can extend the result of Nemhauser et al. to show that for any 汍 &gt; 0, there is a 污 &gt; 0 such that by using (1 + 污)-approximate values for the function to be optimized, we obtain a (1 ? 1/e ? 汍)-approximation.</p><p>As mentioned in the introduction, we can extend this analysis to a general model with more complex marketing actions that can have a probabilistic effect on the initial activation of nodes. We show in Section 6 how, with a more careful hill-climbing algorithm and a generalization of Theorem 2.1, we can obtain comparable approximation guarantees in this setting.</p><p>A further extension is to assume that each node v has an associated non-negative weight wv, capturing how important it is that v be activated in the final outcome. (For instance, if we are marketing textbooks to college teachers, then the weight could be the number of students in the teacher's class, resulting in a larger or smaller number of sales.) If we let B denote the (random) set activated by the process with initial activation A, then we can define the weighted influence function 考w(A) to be the expected value over outcomes B of the quantity v﹋B wv. The influence function studied above is the special case obtained by setting wv = 1 for all nodes v. The objective function with weights is submodular whenever the unweighted version is, so we can still use the greedy algorithm for obtaining a (1 ? 1/e ? 汍)-approximation. Note, however, that a sampling algorithm to approximately choose the next element may need time that depends on the sizes of the weights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Independent Cascade</head><p>In view of the above discussion, an approximation guarantee for influence maximization in the Independent Cascade Model will be a consequence of the following THEOREM 2.2. For an arbitrary instance of the Independent Cascade Model, the resulting influence function 考(﹞) is submodular.</p><p>T be two sets of nodes such that S ? T , and consider the quantity 考X (S ﹍ {v})?考X(S). This is the number of elements in R(v, X) that are not already in the union ﹍u﹋SR(u, X); it is at least as large as the number of elements in R(v, X) that are not in the (bigger) union ﹍u﹋T R(u, X). It follows that 考X (S ﹍ {v}) ? 考X (S) ≡ 考X (T ﹍ {v}) ? 考X (T ), which is the defining inequality for submodularity. Finally, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">考(A) = Prob[X] ﹞ 考X (A),</formula><p>In order to establish this result, we need to look, implicitly or explicitly, at the expression 考(A ﹍ {v}) ? 考(A), for arbitrary sets A and elements v. In other words, what increase do we get in the expected number of overall activations when we add v to the set A? This increase is very difficult to analyze directly, because it is hard to work with quantities of the form 考(A). For example, the Independent Cascade process is underspecified, since we have not prescribed the order in which newly activated nodes in a given step t will attempt to activate their neighbors. Thus, it is not initially obvious that the process is even well-defined, in the sense that it yields the same distribution over outcomes regardless of how we schedule the attempted activations.</p><p>Our proof deals with these difficulties by formulating an equivalent view of the process, which makes it easier to see that there is an order-independent outcome, and which provides an alternate way to reason about the submodularity property.</p><p>Consider a point in the cascade process when node v has just become active, and it attempts to activate its neighbor w, succeeding with probability pv,w. We can view the outcome of this random event as being determined by flipping a coin of bias pv,w. From the point of view of the process, it clearly does not matter whether the coin was flipped at the moment that v became active, or whether it was flipped at the very beginning of the whole process and is only being revealed now. Continuing this reasoning, we can in fact assume that for each pair of neighbors (v, w) in the graph, a coin of bias pv,w is flipped at the very beginning of the process (independently of the coins for all other pairs of neighbors), and the result is stored so that it can be later checked in the event that v is activated while w is still inactive.</p><p>With all the coins flipped in advance, the process can be viewed as follows. The edges in G for which the coin flip indicated an activation will be successful are declared to be live; the remaining edges are declared to be blocked. If we fix the outcomes of the coin flips and then initially activate a set A, it is clear how to determine the full set of active nodes at the end of the cascade process:</p><p>outcomes X since the expected number of nodes activated is just the weighted average over all outcomes. But a non-negative linear combination of submodular functions is also submodular, and hence 考(﹞) is submodular, which concludes the proof.</p><p>Next we show the hardness of influence maximization. THEOREM 2.4. The influence maximization problem is NP-hard for the Independent Cascade model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Proof.</head><p>Consider an instance of the NP-complete Set Cover problem, defined by a collection of subsets S1, S2, . . . , Sm of a ground set U = {u1, u2, . . . , un}; we wish to know whether there exist k of the subsets whose union is equal to U . (We can assume that k &lt; n &lt; m.) We show that this can be viewed as a special case of the influence maximization problem.</p><p>Given an arbitrary instance of the Set Cover problem, we define a corresponding directed bipartite graph with n + m nodes: there is a node i corresponding to each set Si, a node j corresponding to each element uj, and a directed edge (i, j) with activation probability pi,j = 1 whenever uj ﹋ Si. The Set Cover problem is equivalent to deciding if there is a set A of k nodes in this graph with 考(A) ≡ n + k. Note that for the instance we have defined, activation is a deterministic process, as all probabilities are 0 or 1. Initially activating the k nodes corresponding to sets in a Set Cover solution results in activating all n nodes corresponding to the ground set U , and if any set A of k nodes has 考(A) ≡ n + k, then the Set Cover problem must be solvable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Linear Thresholds</head><p>We now prove an analogous result for the Linear Threshold Model. THEOREM 2.5. For an arbitrary instance of the Linear Threshold Model, the resulting influence function 考(﹞) is submodular. CLAIM 2.3. A node x ends up active if and only if there is a path from some node in A to x consisting entirely of live edges. (We will call such a path a live-edge path.)</p><p>Consider the probability space in which each sample point specifies one possible set of outcomes for all the coin flips on the edges. Let X denote one sample point in this space, and define 考X (A) to be the total number of nodes activated by the process when A is the set initially targeted, and X is the set of outcomes of all coin flips on edges. Because we have fixed a choice for X, 考X (A) is in fact a deterministic quantity, and there is a natural way to express its value, as follows. Let R(v, X) denote the set of all nodes that can be reached from v on a path consisting entirely of live edges. By Claim 2.3, 考X(A) is the number of nodes that can be reached on live-edge paths from any node in A, and so it is equal to the cardinality of the union ﹍v﹋AR(v, X).</p><p>Proof of Theorem 2.2. First, we claim that for each fixed outcome X, the function 考X (﹞) is submodular. To see this, let S and Proof. The analysis is a bit more intricate than in the proof of Theorem 2.2, but the overall argument has a similar structure. In the proof of Theorem 2.2, we constructed an equivalent process by initially resolving the outcomes of some random choices, considering each outcome in isolation, and then averaging over all outcomes. For the Linear Threshold Model, the simplest analogue would be to consider the behavior of the process after all node thresholds have been chosen. Unfortunately, for a fixed choice of thresholds, the number of activated nodes is not in general a submodular function of the targeted set; this fact necessitates a more subtle analysis.</p><p>Recall that each node v has an influence weight bv,w ≡ 0 from each of its neighbors w, subject to the constraint that w bv,w ≒ 1. (We can extend the notation by writing bv,w = 0 when w is not a neighbor of v.) Suppose that v picks at most one of its incoming edges at random, selecting the edge from w with probability bv,w and selecting no edge with probability 1 ? w bv,w. The selected edge is declared to be "live," and all other edges are declared to be "blocked." (Note the contrast with the proof of Theorem 2.2: there, we determined whether an edge was live independently of the decision for each other edge; here, we negatively correlate the decisions so that at most one live edge enters each node.)</p><p>The crux of the proof lies in establishing Claim 2.6 below, which asserts that the Linear Threshold model is equivalent to reachability via live-edge paths as defined above. Once that equivalence is established, submodularity follows exactly as in the proof of Theorem 2.2. We can define R(v, X) as before to be the set of all nodes reachable from v on live-edge paths, subject to a choice X of live/blocked designations for all edges; it follows that 考X(A) is the cardinality of the union ﹍v﹋AR(v, X), and hence a submodular function of A; finally, the function 考(﹞) is a non-negative linear combination of the functions 考X (﹞) and hence also submodular. same as in the Linear Threshold process of the previous paragraph. Thus, by induction over these stages, we see that the live-edge process produces the same distribution over active sets as the Linear Threshold process.</p><p>Influence maximization is hard in this model as well. Proof. Consider an instance of the NP-complete Vertex Cover problem defined by an undirected n-node graph G = (V, E) and an integer k; we want to know if there is a set S of k nodes in G so that every edge has at least one endpoint in S. We show that this can be viewed as a special case of the influence maximization problem. Given an instance of the Vertex Cover problem involving a graph G, we define a corresponding instance of the influence maximization problem by directing all edges of G in both directions. If there is a vertex cover S of size k in G, then one can deterministically make 考(A) = n by targeting the nodes in the set A = S; conversely, this is the only way to get a set A with 考(A) = n.</p><p>Proof. We need to prove that reachability under our random choice of live and blocked edges defines a process equivalent to that of the Linear Threshold Model. To obtain intuition about this equivalence, it is useful to first analyze the special case in which the underlying graph G is directed and acyclic. In this case, we can fix a topological ordering of the nodes v1, v2, . . . , vn (so that all edges go from earlier nodes to later nodes in the order), and build up the distribution of active sets by following this order. For each node vi, suppose we already have determined the distribution over active subsets of its neighbors. Then under the Linear Threshold process, the probability that vi will become active, given that a subset Si of its neighbors is active, is</p><p>In the proofs of both the approximation theorems in this section, we established submodularity by considering an equivalent process in which each node "hard-wired" certain of its incident edges as transmitting influence from neighbors. This turns out to be a proof technique that can be formulated in general terms, and directly applied to give approximability results for other models as well. We discuss this further in the context of the general framework presented in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EXPERIMENTS</head><p>w﹋S i bv i ,w . This is precisely the probability that the live incoming edge selected by vi lies in Si, and so inductively we see that the two processes define the same distribution over active sets.</p><p>To prove the claim generally, consider a graph G that is not acyclic. It becomes trickier to show the equivalence, because there is no natural ordering of the nodes over which to perform induction. Instead, we argue by induction over the iterations of the Linear Threshold process. We define At to be the set of active nodes at the end of iteration t, for t = 0, 1, 2, . . . (note that A0 is the set initially targeted). If node v has not become active by the end of iteration t, then the probability that it becomes active in iteration t + 1 is equal to the chance that the influence weights in At \ At?1 push it over its threshold, given that its threshold was not exceeded In addition to obtaining worst-case guarantees on the performance of our approximation algorithm, we are interested in understanding its behavior in practice, and comparing its performance to other heuristics for identifying influential individuals. We find that our greedy algorithm achieves significant performance gains over several widely-used structural measures of influence in social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>bv,u</head><p>already; this probability is</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">u﹋At\A t?1 1 ? bv,u . u﹋A t?1</formula><p>On the other hand, we can run the live-edge process by revealing the identities of the live edges gradually as follows. We start with the targeted set A. For each node v with at least one edge from the set A, we determine whether v's live edge comes from A. If so, then v is reachable; but if not, we keep the source of v's live edge unknown, subject to the condition that it comes from outside A. Having now exposed a new set of reachable nodes A The Network Data. For evaluation, it is desirable to use a network dataset that exhibits many of the structural features of large-scale social networks. At the same time, we do not address the issue of inferring actual influence parameters from network observations (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref>). Thus, for our testbed, we employ a collaboration graph obtained from co-authorships in physics publications, with simple settings of the influence parameters. It has been argued extensively that co-authorship networks capture many of the key features of social networks more generally <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>. The co-authorship data was compiled from the complete list of papers in the highenergy physics theory section of the e-print arXiv (www.arxiv.org).</p><p>2 1 in the first stage, we proceed to identify further reachable nodes by performing the same process on edges from A 1 , and in this way produce sets A 2 , A 3 , . . .. If node v has not been determined to be reachable by the end of stage t, then the probability that it is determined to be reachable in stage t + 1 is equal to the chance that its live edge comes from At \ At?1, given that its live edge has not come from</p><p>The collaboration graph contains a node for each researcher who has at least one paper with co-author(s) in the arXiv database. For each paper with two or more authors, we inserted an edge for each pair of authors (single-author papers were ignored). Notice that this results in parallel edges when two researchers have co-authored multiple papers -we kept these parallel edges as they can be interpreted to indicate stronger social ties between the researchers involved. The resulting graph has 10748 nodes, and edges between about 53000 pairs of nodes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>bv,u</head><p>any of the earlier sets. But this is</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">u﹋At\A t?1 1 ? bv,u</formula><p>, which is the While processing the data, we corrected many common types of mistakes automatically or manually. In order to deal with aliasing problems at least partially, we abbreviated first names, and unified spellings for foreign characters. We believe that the resulting graph is a good approximation to the actual collaboration graph (the sheer volume of data prohibits a complete manual cleaning pass).</p><p>ically, we simulate the process 10000 times for each targeted set, re-choosing thresholds or edge outcomes pseudo-randomly from [0, 1] every time. Previous runs indicate that the quality of approximation after 10000 iterations is comparable to that after 300000 or more iterations.</p><p>The Influence Models. We compared the algorithms in three different models of influence. In the linear threshold model, we treated the multiplicity of edges as weights. If nodes u, v have cu,v parallel edges between them, and degrees du and dv, then the edge (u, v) has weight cu,v dv , and the edge (v, u) has weight cu,v du .</p><p>In the independent cascade model, we assigned a uniform probability of p to each edge of the graph, choosing p to be 1% and 10% in separate trials. If nodes u and v have cu,v parallel edges, then we assume that for each of those cu,v edges, u has a chance of p to activate v, i.e. u has a total probability of 1 ? <ref type="figure">(1 ? p)</ref> cu,v of activating v once it becomes active.</p><p>The independent cascade model with uniform probabilities p on the edges has the property that high-degree nodes not only have a chance to influence many other nodes, but also to be influenced by them. Whether or not this is a desirable interpretation of the influence data is an application-specific issue. Motivated by this, we chose to also consider an alternative interpretation, where edges into high-degree nodes are assigned smaller probabilities. We study a special case of the Independent Cascade Model that we term "weighted cascade", in which each edge from node u to v is assigned probability 1/dv of activating v. The weighted cascade model resembles the linear threshold model in that the expected number of neighbors who would succeed in activating a node v is 1 in both models.</p><p>The results. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the performance of the algorithms in the linear threshold model. The greedy algorithm outperforms the high-degree node heuristic by about 18%, and the central node heuristic by over 40%. (As expected, choosing random nodes is not a good idea.) This shows that significantly better marketing results can be obtained by explicitly considering the dynamics of information in a network, rather than relying solely on structural properties of the graph. The algorithms and implementation. We compare our greedy algorithm with heuristics based on nodes' degrees and centrality within the network, as well as the crude baseline of choosing random nodes to target. The degree and centrality-based heuristics are commonly used in the sociology literature as estimates of a node's influence <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. The high-degree heuristic chooses nodes v in order of decreasing degrees dv. Considering high-degree nodes as influential has long been a standard approach for social and other networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1]</ref>, and is known in the sociology literature as "degree centrality". "Distance centrality" is another commonly used influence measure in sociology, building on the assumption that a node with short paths to other nodes in a network will have a higher chance of influencing them. Hence, we select nodes in order of increasing average distance to other nodes in the network. As the arXiv collaboration graph is not connected, we assigned a distance of n -the number of nodes in the graph -for any pair of unconnected nodes. This value is significantly larger than any actual distance, and thus can be considered to play the role of an infinite distance. In particular, nodes in the largest connected component will have smallest average distance.</p><p>Finally, we consider, as a baseline, the result of choosing nodes uniformly at random. Notice that because the optimization problem is NP-hard, and the collaboration graph is prohibitively large, we cannot compute the optimum value to verify the actual quality of approximations.</p><p>Both in choosing the nodes to target with the greedy algorithm, and in evaluating the performance of the algorithms, we need to compute the value 考(A).</p><p>It is an open question to compute this quantity exactly by an efficient method, but very good estimates can be obtained by simulating the random process. More specif-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Results for the linear threshold model</head><p>When investigating the reason why the high-degree and centrality heuristics do not perform as well, one sees that they ignore such network effects. In particular, neither of the heuristics incorporates the fact that many of the most central (or highest-degree) nodes may be clustered, so that targeting all of them is unnecessary. In fact, the uneven nature of these curves suggests that the network influence of many nodes is not accurately reflected by their degree or centrality. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the results for the weighted cascade model. Notice the striking similarity to the linear threshold model. The scale is slightly different (all values are about 25% smaller), but the behavior is qualitatively the same, even with respect to the exact nodes whose network influence is not reflected accurately by their degree or centrality. The reason is that in expectation, each node is influenced by the same number of other nodes in both models (see Section 2), and the degrees are relatively concentrated around their expectation of 1.</p><p>The graph for the independent cascade model with probability 1%, given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, seems very similar to the previous two at first glance. Notice, however, the very different scale: on average, each targeted node only activates three additional nodes. Hence, the network effects in the independent cascade model with very small probabilities are much weaker than in the other models. Several nodes have degrees well exceeding 100, so the probabilities on their incoming edges are even smaller than 1% in the weighted cascade model. This suggests that the network effects observed for the linear threshold and weighted cascade models rely heavily on low-degree nodes as multipliers, even though targeting high-degree nodes is a reasonable heuristic. Also notice that in the independent cascade model, the heuristic of choosing random nodes performs significantly better than in the previous two models. marginal gain afterwards. Hence, its active set keeps growing, although at a much smaller slope than in other models.</p><p>The random heuristic does not do as well initially as the other heuristics, but with sufficiently many attempts, it eventually hits some highly influential nodes and becomes competitive with the centrality-based node choices. Because it does not focus exclusively on central nodes, it eventually targets nodes with additional marginal gain, and surpasses the two centrality-based heuristics. The improvement in performance of the "random nodes" heuristic is even more pronounced for the independent cascade model with probabilities equal to 10%, depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. In that model, it starts to outperform both the high-degree and the central nodes heuristics when more than 12 nodes are targeted. It is initially surprising that random targeting for this model should lead to more activations than centrality-based targeting, but in fact there is a natural underlying reason that we explore now.</p><p>The first targeted node, if chosen somewhat judiciously, will activate a large fraction of the network, in our case almost 25%. However, any additional nodes will only reach a small additional fraction of the network. In particular, other central or high-degree nodes are very likely to be activated by the initially chosen one, and thus have hardly any marginal gain. This explains the shapes of the curves for the high-degree and centrality heuristics, which leap up to about 2415 activated nodes, but make virtually no progress afterwards. The greedy algorithm, on the other hand, takes the effect of the first chosen node into account, and targets nodes with smaller General Threshold and Cascade Models. We have thus far been considering two specific, widely studied models for the diffusion of influence. We now propose a broader framework that simultaneously generalizes these two models, and allows us to explore the limits of models in which strong approximation guarantees can be obtained. Our general framework has equivalent formulations in terms of thresholds and cascades, thereby unifying these two views of diffusion through a social network.</p><p>? A general threshold model. We would like to be able to express the notion that a node v's decision to become active can be based on an arbitrary monotone function of the set of neighbors of v that are already active. Thus, associated with v is a monotone threshold function fv that maps subsets of v's neighbor set to real numbers in <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1]</ref>, subject to the condition that fv(?) = 0. The diffusion process follows the general structure of the Linear Threshold Model. Each node v initially chooses 牟v uniformly at random from the interval <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1]</ref>. Now, however, v becomes active in step t if fv(S) ≡ 牟v, where S is the set of neighbors of v that are active in step t ? 1. Note that the Linear Threshold Model is the special case in which each threshold function has the form fv(S) = u﹋S bv,u for parameters bv,u such that bv,u ≒ 1.</p><p>u neighbor of v</p><p>? A general cascade model. We generalize the cascade model to allow the probability that u succeeds in activating a neighbor v to depend on the set of v's neighbors that have already tried. Thus, we define an incremental function pv(u, S) ﹋ [0, 1], where S and {u} are disjoint subsets of v's neighbor set. A general cascade process works by analogy with the independent case: in the general case, when u attempts to activate v, it succeeds with probability pv(u, S), where S is the set of neighbors that have already tried (and failed) to activate v. The Independent Cascade Model is the special case where pv(u, S) is a constant pu,v, independent of S. We will only be interested in cascade models defined by incremental functions that are order-independent in the following sense: if neighbors u1, u2, . . . , u try to activate v, then the probability that v is activated at the end of these attempts does not depend on the order in which the attempts are made. These two models are equivalent, and we give a method to convert between them. First, consider an instance of the general threshold model with threshold functions fv. To define an equivalent cascade model, we need to understand the probability that an additional neighbor u can activate v, given that the nodes in a set S have already tried and failed. If the nodes in S have failed, then node v's threshold 牟v must be in the range 牟v ﹋ (fv(S), 1]. However, subject to this constraint, it is uniformly distributed.Thus, the probability that a neighbor u / ﹋ S succeeds in activating v, given that the nodes in S have failed, is fewer than n + k are. But this would solve the underlying instance of Set Cover, and therefore is impossible assuming P = NP.</p><p>Note that our inapproximability result holds in a very simple model, in which each node is "hard-wired" with a fixed threshold.</p><p>Exploring the Boundaries of Approximability. Thus, the general threshold and cascade models are too broad to allow for nontrivial approximation guarantees in their full generality. At the same time, we have seen that the greedy algorithm achieves strong guarantees for some of the main special cases in the social networks literature. How far can we extend these approximability results?</p><p>We can generalize the proof technique used in Theorems 2.2 and 2.5 to a model that is less general (and also less natural) than the general threshold and cascade models; however, it includes our special cases from Section 2, and every instance of this model will have a submodular influence function. The model is as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">pv(u, S) = fv(S ﹍ {u}) ? fv(S) 1 ? fv(S) .</formula><p>It is not difficult to show that the cascade process with these functions is equivalent to the original threshold process. Conversely, consider a node v in the cascade model, and a set S = {u1, . . . , u k } of its neighbors. Assume that the nodes in S try to activate v in the order u1, . . . , u k , and let Si = {u1, . . . , ui}. Then the probability that v is not activated by this process is by def-</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">inition k i=1 (1 ? pv(ui, Si?1)).</formula><p>Recall that we assumed that the order in which the ui try to activate v does not affect their overall success probability. Hence, this value depends on the set S only, and we can define fv(S) = 1 ? k i=1 (1 ? pv(ui, Si?1)). Analogously, one can show that this instance of the threshold model is equivalent to the original cascade process.</p><p>? The Triggering Model. Each node v independently chooses a random "triggering set" Tv according to some distribution over subsets of its neighbors. To start the process, we target a set A for initial activation. After this initial iteration, an inactive node v becomes active in step t if it has a neighbor in its chosen triggering set Tv that is active at time t ? 1.</p><p>(Thus, v's threshold has been replaced by a latent subset of Tv of neighbors whose behavior actually affects v.)</p><p>It is useful to think of the triggering sets in terms of "live" and "blocked" edges: if node u belongs to the triggering set Tv of v, then we declare the edge (u, v) to be live, and otherwise we declare it to be blocked. As in the proofs of Theorems 2.2 and 2.5, a node v is activated in an instance of the Triggering Model if and only if there is a live-edge path from the initially targeted set A to v. Following the arguments in these proofs, we obtain the following THEOREM 4.2. In every instance of the Triggering Model, the influence function 考(﹞) is submodular.</p><p>An Inapproximability Result. The general model proposed above includes large families of instances for which the influence function 考(﹞) is not submodular. Indeed, it may become NP-hard to approximate the optimization problem to within any non-trivial factor. THEOREM 4.1. In general, it is NP-hard to approximate the influence maximization problem to within a factor of n 1?汍 , for any 汍 &gt; 0.</p><p>Proof. To prove this result, we reduce from the Set Cover problem. We start with the construction from the proof of Theorem 2.4, letting u1, . . . , un denote the nodes corresponding to the n elements; i.e. ui becomes active when at least one of the nodes corresponding to sets containing ui is active. Next, for an arbitrarily large constant c, we add N = n c more nodes x1, . . . , xN ; each xj is connected to all of the nodes ui, and it becomes active only when all of the ui are.</p><p>If there are at most k sets that cover all elements, then activating the nodes corresponding to these k sets will activate all of the nodes ui, and thus also all of the xj. In total, at least N + n + k nodes will be active. Conversely, if there is no set cover of size k, then no targeted set will activate all of the ui, and hence none of the xj will become active (unless targeted). In particular, fewer than n+k nodes are active in the end. If an algorithm could approximate the problem within n 1?汍 for any 汍, it could distinguish between the cases where N + n + k nodes are active in the end, and where Beyond the Independent Cascade and Linear Threshold, there are other natural special cases of the Triggering Model. One example is the "Only-Listen-Once" Model. Here, each node v has a parameter pv so that the first neighbor of v to be activated causes v to become active with probability pv, and all subsequent attempts to activate v deterministically fail. (In other words, v only listens to the first neighbor that tries to activate it.) This process has an equivalent formulation in the Triggering Set Model, with an edge distribution defined as follows: for any node v, the triggering set Tv is either the entire neighbor set of v (with probability pv), or the empty set otherwise. As a result, the influence function in the Only-Listen-Once Model is also submodular, and we can obtain a (1 ? 1/e ? 汍)-approximation here as well.</p><p>However, we can show that there exist models with submodular influence functions that do not have equivalent formulations in terms of triggering sets, so it makes sense to seek further models in which submodularity holds.</p><p>One tractable special case of the cascade model is based on the natural restriction that the probability of a node u influencing v is non-increasing as a function of the set of nodes that have previously tried to influence v. In terms of the cascade model, this means that pv(u, S) ≡ pv(u, T ) whenever S ? T . We say that a process satisfying these conditions is an instance of the Decreasing Cascade Model. Although there are natural Decreasing Cascade instances that have no equivalent formulation in terms of triggering sets, we can show by a more intricate analysis that every instance of the Decreasing Cascade Model has a submodular influence function. We will include details of this proof in the full version of the paper.</p><p>A Conjecture. Finally, we state an appealing conjecture that would include all the approximability results above as special cases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONJECTURE 4.3. Whenever the threshold functions fv at every node are monotone and submodular, the resulting influence function 考(﹞) is monotone and submodular as well.</head><p>It is not difficult to show that every instance of the Triggering Model has an equivalent formulation with submodular node thresholds. Every instance of the Decreasing Cascade Model has such an equivalent formulation as well; in fact, the Decreasing Cascade condition stands as a very natural special case of the conjecture, given that it too is based on a type of "diminishing returns." When translated into the language of threshold functions, we find that the Decreasing Cascade condition corresponds to the following natural requirement:</p><p>Note that the non-progressive model discussed here differs from the model of Domingos and Richardson <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref> in two ways. We are concerned with the sum over all time steps t ≒ 而 of the expected number of active nodes at time t, for a given a time limit 而 , while <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref> study the limit of this process: the expected number of nodes active at time t as t goes to infinity. Further, we consider interventions for a particular node v, at a particular time t ≒ 而 , while the interventions considered by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref> permanently affect the activation probability function of the targeted nodes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">GENERAL MARKETING STRATEGIES</head><formula xml:id="formula_8">fv(S ﹍ {u}) ? fv(S) 1 ? fv(S) ≡ fv(T ﹍ {u}) ? fv(T ) 1 ? fv(T ) ,</formula><p>whenever S ? T and u / ﹋ T . This is in a sense a "normalized submodularity" property; it is stronger than submodularity, which would consist of the same inequality on just the numerators. (Note that by monotonicity, the denominator on the left is larger.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">NON-PROGRESSIVE PROCESSES</head><p>We have thus far been concerned with the progressive case, in which nodes only go from inactivity to activity, but not vice versa. The non-progressive case, in which nodes can switch in both directions, can in fact be reduced to the progressive case.</p><p>The non-progressive threshold process is analogous to the progressive model, except that at each step t, each node v chooses a new value 牟</p><p>In the formulation of the problem, we have so far assumed that for one unit of budget, we can deterministically target any node v for activation. This is clearly a highly simplified view. In a more realistic scenario, we may have a number m of different marketing actions Mi available, each of which may affect some subset of nodes by increasing their probabilities of becoming active, without necessarily making them active deterministically. The more we spend on any one action the stronger its effect will be; however, different nodes may respond to marketing actions in different ways, In a general model, we choose investments xi into marketing actions Mi, such that the total investments do not exceed the budget. A marketing strategy is then an m-dimensional vector x of investments. The probability that node v will become active is determined by the strategy, and denoted by hv(x). We assume that this function is non-decreasing and satisfies the following "diminishing returns" property for all x ≡ y and a ≡ 0 (where we write x ≡ y or a ≡ 0 to denote that the inequalities hold in all coordinates):</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">hv(x + a) ? hv(x) ≒ hv(y + a) ? hv(y) (1) (t)</formula><p>v uniformly at random from the interval <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1]</ref>. Node v will be active in step t if fv(S) ≡ 牟 (t) v , where S is the set of neighbors of v that are active in step t ? 1.</p><p>From the perspective of influence maximization, we can ask the following question. Suppose we have a non-progressive model that is going to run for 而 steps, and during this process, we are allowed to make up to k interventions: for a particular node v, at a particular time t ≒ 而 , we can target v for activation at time t. (v itself may quickly de-activate, but we hope to create a large "ripple effect.") Which k interventions should we perform? Simple examples show that to maximize influence, one should not necessarily perform all k interventions at time 0; e.g., G may not even have k nodes.</p><p>Let A be a set of k interventions. The influence of these k interventions 考(A) is the sum, over all nodes v, of the number of time steps that v is active. The influence maximization problem in the non-progressive threshold model is to find the k interventions with maximum influence.</p><p>We can show that the non-progressive influence maximization problem reduces to the progressive case in a different graph. Given a graph G = (V, E) and a time limit 而 , we build a layered graph G 而 on 而 ﹞ |V | nodes: there is a copy vt for each node v in G, and each time-step t ≒ 而 . We connect each node in this graph with its neighbors in G indexed by the previous time step.</p><p>Intuitively, Inequality (1) states that any marketing action is more effective when the targeted individual is less "marketing-saturated" at that point.</p><p>We are trying to maximize the expected size of the final active set. As a function of the marketing strategy x, each node v becomes active independently with probability hv(x), resulting in a (random) set of initial active nodes A. Given the initial set A, the expected size of the final active set is 考(A). The expected revenue of the marketing strategy x is therefore g(x) = A?V 考(A) ﹞ u﹋A hu(x) ﹞ v / ﹋A (1 ? hv(x)). In order to (approximately) maximize g, we assume that we can evaluate the function at any point x approximately, and find a direction i with approximately maximal gradient. Specifically, let ei denote the unit vector along the i th coordinate axis, and 汛 be some constant. We assume that there exists some 污 ≒ 1 such that we can find an i with g(x + 汛 ﹞ ei)?g(x) ≡ 污 ﹞(g(x + 汛 ﹞ ej)?g(x)) for each j. We divide each unit of the total budget k into equal parts of size 汛. Starting with an all-0 investment, we perform an approximate gradient ascent, by repeatedly (a total of k 汛 THEOREM 5.1. The non-progressive influence maximization problem on G over a time horizon 而 is equivalent to the progressive influence maximization problem on the layered graph G 而 . Node v is active at time t in the non-progressive process if and only if vt is activated in the progressive process. times) adding 汛 units of budget to the investment in the action Mi that approximately maximizes the gradient.</p><p>The proof that this algorithm gives a good approximation consists of two steps. First, we show that the function g we are trying to optimize is non-negative, non-decreasing, and satisfies the "diminishing returns" condition (1). Second, we show that the hillclimbing algorithm gives a constant-factor approximation for any function g with these properties. The latter part is captured by the following theorem.</p><p>Thus, models where we have approximation algorithms for the progressive case carry over. Theorem 5.1 also implies approximation results for certain non-progressive models used by Asavathiratham et al. to model cascading failures in power grids <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>. THEOREM 6.1. When the hill-climbing algorithm finishes with k﹞污 strategy x, it guarantees that g(x) ≡ (1 ? e ? k+汛﹞n ) ﹞ g(? x), wher那wher那 x denotes the optimal solution subject to i ? xi ≒ k.</p><p>The proof of this theorem builds on the analysis used by Nemhauser et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>, and we defer it to the full version of this paper.</p><p>With Theorem 6.1 in hand, it remains to show that g is nonnegative, monotone, and satisfies condition (1). The first two are clear, so we only sketch the proof of the third. Fix an arbitary ordering of vertices. We then use the fact that for any ai, bi, bj, hj (x + a) ﹞ j&lt;u,j / ﹋A</p><p>(1 ? hj (x)) .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>j&gt;u,j﹋A</head><p>hj (x) ﹞ j&gt;u,j / ﹋A To show that this difference is non-increasing, we consider y ≒ x. From the diminishing returns property of hu(﹞), we obtain that hu(x + a) ? hu(x) ≒ hu(y + a) ? hu(y). Then, applying again equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">(2)</ref>, changing the order of summation, and performing some tedious calculations, writing ?(v, x, y) = hv(x + a) ? hv(y + a) if v &lt; u, and ?(v, x, y) = hv(x) ? hv(y) if v &gt; u, we obtain that hj (y) ﹞ j&gt;max(u,v),j / ﹋A In this expression, all terms are non-negative (by monotonicity of the hv(﹞)), with the exception of 考(A + {u, v}) ? 考(A + u) ? 考(A + v) + 考(A), which is non-positive because 考 is submodular. Hence, the above difference is always non-positive, so g satisfies the diminishing returns condition (1).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 : Results for the weighted cascade model Figure 4 :</head><label>24</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Results for the weighted cascade model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Independent cascade model with probability 1%</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(ai ? bi) ﹞ j&lt;i aj ﹞ j&gt;i and change the order of summation, to rewrite the difference g(x + a) ? g(x) = (考(A + u) ? 考(A)) ﹞ u (hu(x + a) ? hu(x)) ﹞ A:u / ﹋A (1 ? hj (x + a)) ﹞ j&lt;u,j﹋A</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>? hu(y)) ﹞ ?(v, x, y) ﹞ u,v:u =v 考(A + {u, v}) ? 考(A + v) ? 考(A + u) + 考(A) ﹞ A:u,v / ﹋A (1 ? hj (x + a)) ﹞ j&lt;min(u,v),j﹋A hj (x + a) ﹞ j&lt;min(u,v),j / ﹋A (1 ? hj(x)) ﹞ u&lt;j&lt;v,j﹋A hj (x) ﹞ u&lt;j&lt;v,j / ﹋A (1 ? hj(y + a)) ﹞ v&lt;j&lt;u,j﹋A hj (y + a) ﹞ v&lt;j&lt;u,j / ﹋A (1 ? hj (y)) j&gt;max(u,v),j﹋A</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>THEOREM 2 .7. The influence maximization problem is NP-hard for the Linear Threshold model. CLAIM 2.6. For a given targeted set A</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>, the following two dis-
tributions over sets of nodes are the same: 

(i) The distribution over active sets obtained by running the Lin-
ear Threshold process to completion starting from A; and 
(ii) The distribution over sets reachable from A via live-edge paths, 
under the random selection of live edges defined above. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Note that the influence function 考(﹞) defined above has this form; it maps each subset A of the nodes of the social network to a real number denoting the expected size of the activated set if A is targeted for initial activation.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> We also ran experiments on the co-authorship graphs induced by theoretical computer science papers. We do not report on the results here, as they are very similar to the ones for high-energy physics. u﹋A t?1</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Error and attack tolerance of complex networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Albert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Barabasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">406</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="382" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Influence Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Asavathiratham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lesieutre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Verghese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Control Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Influence Model: A Tractable Representation for the Dynamics of Networked Markov Chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Asavathiratham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. Thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new product growth model for consumer durables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic Monopolies of Constant Size</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Combinatorial Theory Series B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Statistical Mechanics of Strategic Interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Blume</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social ties and word-of-mouth referral behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Reinegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Menzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Medical Innovations: A Diffusion Study Bobbs Merrill</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Location of Bank Accounts to Optimize Float</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cornuejols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nemhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">23</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining the Network Value of Customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Seventh International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lecture Notes on Particle Systems and Percolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Durrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Wadsworth Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning, Local Interaction, and Coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1047" to="1071" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Talk of the Network: A Complex Systems Look at the Underlying Process of Word-of-Mouth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using Complex Systems Analysis to Advance Marketing Theory Development. Academy of Marketing Science Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Libai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threshold models of collective behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1420" to="1443" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementing Data Cubes Efficiently</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Harinarayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rajaraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ullman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACM SIGMOD</title>
		<meeting>ACM SIGMOD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Interacting Particle Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liggett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chains of Cooperation: Threshold Effects in Collective Action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Macy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Sociological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Factors to Actors: Computational Sociology and Agent-Based Modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Macy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Willer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Rev. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New Product Diffusion Models in Marketing: A Review and Directions for Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bass</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Contagion. Review of Economic Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Integer and Combinatorial Optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nemhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wolsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>John Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of the approximations for maximizing submodular set functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nemhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wolsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The structure of scientific collaboration networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Local Majority Voting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Peleg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Small Coalitions, and Controlling Monopolies in Graphs: A Review. 3rd Colloq. on Structural Information and Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Knowledge-Sharing Sites for Viral Marketing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eighth Intl. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Diffusion of innovations Free Press</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Micromotives and Macrobehavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schelling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<pubPlace>Norton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Network Models of the Diffusion of Innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Valente</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Hampton Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social Network Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wasserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Faust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Simple Model of Global Cascades in Random Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5766" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Diffusion of Innovations in Social Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peyton</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>02-04-018</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Santa Fe Institute Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Individual Strategy and Social Structure: An Evolutionary Theory of Institutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peyton</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<pubPlace>Princeton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
