<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-17T00:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Late-Breaking Developments in the Field of Artificial Intelligence Papers Presented at the Twenty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence Negative Influence Minimizing by Blocking Nodes in Social Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Senzhang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>szwang@cse</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100191</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojian</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100191</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>chenyan@cse.buaa.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100191</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhoujun</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100191</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiali</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100191</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Software and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>330013</postCode>
									<settlement>Nanchang</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Late-Breaking Developments in the Field of Artificial Intelligence Papers Presented at the Twenty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence Negative Influence Minimizing by Blocking Nodes in Social Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Social networks are becoming vital platforms for the spread of positive information such as innovations and negative information propagation like malicious rumors. In this paper, we address the problem of minimizing the influence of negative information. When negative information such as a rumor emerges in the social network and part of users have already adopted it, our goal is to minimize the size of ultimately contaminated users by discovering and blocking k uninfected users. A greedy method for efficiently finding a good approximate solution to this problem is proposed. The comparison experimental results on the Enron email network dataset demonstrate our proposed method is more effective than centrality based methods, such as degree centrality, betweenness centrality and PageRank.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Online social networks are becoming vital platforms for information propagation. It not only includes positive information such as innovations and hot topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chen et al. 2012</ref>), but also negative information like malicious rumors and disinformation. The research on maximizing the influence of positive information, namely Influence Maximization Problem, has attracted remarkable attention recently due to its novel idea of leveraging some social network users to propagate the awareness of products <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Kempe, Kleinberg, and Tardos 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chen, Wang, and Wang 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Shirazipourazad et al. 2012</ref>). However, the problem of reduction the influence of negative information or undesirable things gets less attention, although it is an important research issue. Take the rumor for example, even with a small number of its initial adopters, the quantity of the ultimately infected users can be large due to triggering a "word-of-mouth" cascade in the network. Therefore, it is an urgent research issue to design effective strategies for reducing the influence coverage of the negative information and minimizing the spread of the undesirable things.</p><p>Some related research work has been made on minimizing the influence of negative information. Baumgartner et al. proposed a links blocking method to minimize the expected contamination area of the network <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baumgartner, Gottlob, and Flesca 2008)</ref>. However, the fact of some nodes infected is not considered. Habiba et al. addressed the problem of finding spread blockers in dynamic networks, and they found good blockers are simply those nodes with high degree ( <ref type="bibr">Habiba et al. 2010</ref>). Budak et al. investigated the problem of influence limitation where a "bad" campaign starts propagation from a certain node in the network and use the notion of limiting campaigns to counteract the effect of misinformation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Budak, Agrawal, and Abbadi 2011)</ref>. Different from previous work, our research concerns more about a specific contamination scenario in the network, and how to minimize the negative influence by blocking a small set of uninfected nodes.</p><p>We formally define the Negative Influence Minimization Problem as follows. Given a network represented as a directed graph G = (V, E), we define V and E ? V ℅ V as the sets of nodes and edges in G, respectively. Assume negative information spreads in the network and some nodes I ? V are infected, our goal here is minimizing the number of ultimately infected nodes by blocking k uninfected nodes S ? {V \I}, where k is a given const. It can be represented as the following optimization problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Minimize S?{V \I} 考{I|V \S} (1) Subject to : |S| ≒ k.</formula><p>where 考{I|V \S} denotes the influence (number of ultimately infected nodes) of I when the node set S is blocked.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methodology</head><p>Copyright c 2013, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (www.aaai.org). All rights reserved.</p><p>In this section, we propose a greedy algorithm based on maximum marginal gain rule for this problem. To demonstrate the effectiveness of it, we compare it against three classical centrality based influence evaluation methods.</p><p>As the basis for all methods, Independent Cascade (IC) Model is adopted as the information diffusion model in this paper. In IC model, each edge is given a probability value p u,v (≒ 1), which corresponds to the probability that node u influences node v. The diffusion proceeds from a given initial active set S 0 in the following way: at each diffusion step t, each node which first becomes active at the step t ? 1 has exactly one chance of activating each of its inactive neighbors according to edge probabilities. The propagation process will be finished when no new nodes become active.  number of blocked nodes number of infected nodes number of blocked nodes number of infected nodes number of blocked nodes number of infected nodes number of blocked nodes number of infected nodes</p><note type="other">2, |I|=100 P=0.4, |I|=200 500 P=0.2,|I|=200 P=0.4,|I|=100</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Experimental results</head><p>Proposed Method. The proposed method is described as Algorithm 1. We first starts with the empty set S 0 = ?, then add node x t with the maximum marginal gain in the step t iteratively, until k nodes are selected. Here, we define the maximum marginal gain rule as the node selection rule which maximizes the decrement of ultimately infected nodes number when the selected node is added to the blocking node set S. We formally represent it as follow:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">x t = argmax 考{I|V \S t?1 } ? 考{I|V \S t?1 ﹍ {x}} x﹋V \{I﹍St?1} (2) Algorithm 1. ConMinGreedy(G = (V, E), I, k) 1: initial S 0 = ?,忖 v = 0 2: for i=1 to k do 3:</formula><p>for each vertex v ﹋ {V \{S i ﹍ I}} do 4:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">忖 v = 考{I|V \ S i } ? 考{I|V \ S i ﹍ {v}} 5:</formula><p>end for 6:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">S i = S i ﹍ {v * : max v * ﹋{V \{Si﹍I}} 忖 v * } 7: end for 8:output S k</formula><p>Three classical centrality based methods are used as baselines and described as follows:</p><p>? Out-Degree. The out-degree d(v i ) of a node v i is the number of outgoing links from the node v i . Kempe et al. showed high degree nodes may outperform other centrality-based heuristics in terms of influential identification(Kempe, Kleinberg, and Tardos 2003).</p><p>? Betweenness Centrality. A node's betweenness is equal to the number of shortest paths from all nodes to all others that pass through that node. Recently, Betweenness centrality has become an important centrality measure in social network <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Brandes 2008</ref>).</p><p>? PageRank. PageRank method is a representative eigenvector centrality method. For its excellent performance in the web pages ranking, we also use it as a baseline( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Page et al. 1999</ref>). In the comparison experiment, we select and block top-k uninfected users according to their out-degree, betweenness and PageRank authority, respectively.</p><p>proach. Enron email communication network covers all the email communication within a dataset of around half million emails from Enron corpus <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Nodes of the network are email addresses and if an address i sent at least one email to address j, the graph contains an undirected edge from i to j. This network contains 36,692 nodes and 367,662 edges.</p><p>In the IC Model, we assign a uniform probability to each edge of the graph. Two propagation probabilities, p = 0.2 and p = 0.4, are used in our experiment. To further investigate the effectiveness of our method, we also conduct experiment on different number of initial contaminated nodes |I|. In addition, besides the three centrality based methods, random selection method is also used as comparison. <ref type="figure">Figure  1</ref>  The results show that the proposed approach outperforms all the other methods on all the four groups of experiment. The performance of PageRank is slightly better than that of betweenness centrality and degree centrality. However, it is inferior to our proposed method. It is probably that these methods ignore the initial infected nodes, which result in ineffective in some scenario, especially when the selected nodes are far from the nodes in I.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>In this paper we investigated the problem of minimizing the spread of negative information by blocking nodes in social networks and proposed a greedy method for efficiently finding a good approximate solution. Comparison with three classical centrality based baseline methods, our method achieved a significant improvement on a real email communication network dataset. Ongoing work focuses on (a) the theory guarantee of the method (whether it is a matroid) and (b) how to extend it to a dynamic network where the number of infected nodes increases with time.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>p=0.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>shows the experimental results by varying the number of blocked nodes. Parameters are set to p = 0.2 |I| = 100, p = 0.2 |I| = 200, p = 0.4 |I| = 100 and p = 0.4 |I| = 200, respectively.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://snap.stanford.edu/data/email-Enron.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Results</head><p>This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China <ref type="bibr">[Grant No. 61170189, 61202239]</ref>, and the Fund of the State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment <ref type="bibr">[Grant No. SKLSDE-2013ZX-19]</ref>.</p><p>Utilizing the real email communication network, we experimentally evaluate the performance of our proposed ap-</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimizing the spread of contamination by blocking links in a network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baumgartner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gottlob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Flesca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1175" to="1180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On variants of shortest-path betweenness centrality and their genetic computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Brandes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="145" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limiting the spread of misinformation in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Budak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Abbadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th international world wide web conference</title>
		<meeting>the 20th international world wide web conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="665" to="674" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A semi-supervised Bayesian network model for microblog topic classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T.-S</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="561" to="576" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable influence maximization for prevalent viral marketing in large-scale social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1038" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Habiba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding spread blokers in dynamic networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Berger-Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Saia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd international conference on Advances in social network mining and analysis, SNAKDD&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd international conference on Advances in social network mining and analysis, SNAKDD&apos;08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 9th ACM SIGKDD Internatioanl Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1175" to="1180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The pagerank citation ranking: bringing order to the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Winograd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence propagation in adversarial setting: How to defeat competition with least amount of investment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shirazipourazad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bogard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Vachhani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of The 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>The 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
