<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-07-17T00:06+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Stigmergy in human practice: Coordination in construction work</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Elsevier BV</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Margery</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Learning and Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Aalborg University Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Meyers Vnge 15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2450</postCode>
									<settlement>K?benhavn S</settlement>
									<region>A. C</region>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leslie</forename><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Learning and Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Aalborg University Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Meyers Vnge 15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2450</postCode>
									<settlement>K?benhavn S</settlement>
									<region>A. C</region>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lars</forename><forename type="middle">Rune</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Learning and Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Aalborg University Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Meyers Vnge 15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2450</postCode>
									<settlement>K?benhavn S</settlement>
									<region>A. C</region>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Stigmergy in human practice: Coordination in construction work</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
						<title level="j" type="abbrev">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">1389-0417</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="51"/>
							<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cogsys.2012.06.004</idno>
					<note>Available online at Action editor:</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Stigmergy</term>
					<term>Human practice</term>
					<term>Coordination</term>
					<term>Articulation work</term>
					<term>Construction work</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Stigmergy is a concept of coordination that may be employed to analyse human practice in complex work settings such as the building process. However, the concept of stigmergy was not originally developed in order to describe human practice, rather it was developed within the field of entomology i.e. the study of social insects. Transposing the concept of stigmergy from the field of entomology to the study of human practice raises a central question: Does the concept of stigmergy add anything to our ability to account for the coordination of human cooperative work? We will argue that it does. We will (1) explicitly compare and delimit the concept of stigmergy to well-established concept describing human coordinative practices and show that it differs from these concepts, and we will (2) apply the concept of stigmergy to an analysis of the coordination of construction work in order to explore the utility of the concept in the analysis of human practice.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>When the concept of stigmergy was first introduced in 1959 by the French entomologist <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Grass¨¦ (1959)</ref>, an important step towards understanding the coordination of collective activities in social insects was made. Today, the concept of stigmergy is well established within the field of entomology <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Theraulaz &amp; Bonabeau, 1999</ref>).</p><p>Turning from the study of insect behaviour to the study of human practice we find the concept of stigmergy to be less well established. However, criteria for applying the concept of stigmergy to the study of human practice are in fact readily emerging and a series of interesting and illuminating studies of stigmergy in a human context has been published (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Christensen, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Marsh &amp; Onof, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Parunak, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ricci, Omicini, Viroli, Gardelli, &amp; Oliva, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Susi &amp; Ziemke, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Tummolini &amp; Castelfrananchi, 2007)</ref>. This paper aims to contribute to this body of literature.</p><p>Building on <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Grass¨¦ (1959)</ref>, we will argue that a coordinative effect can occur when human individuals act on the physical traces of work accomplished previously by others. That is, we will say that actors may coordinate and integrate their cooperative efforts by acting directly on the physical traces of work previously accomplished by others and that signs left or modifications made by individuals on artifacts may, given an appropriate context of practice, become meaningful to others and in turn inspire new actions on artifacts. This is how stigmergy may unfold in a human context.</p><p>However, in connection to the study of stigmergy in a human context we need to ask a fundamental question before we "get ahead of ourselves." The question is this: Does the concept of stigmergy add anything to our ability to account for the coordination of cooperative work in a human context? After all, stigmergy is a concept of coordination <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Theraulaz &amp; Bonabeau, 1999</ref>) and if we are to apply it to the study of human practice we have to ensure that it is not redundant in this context. That is, we have to make sure that there are no other concepts of coordination already having the analytical role that we are casting for the concept of stigmergy. This work has not been done so far (see Section 2), and we shall address this challenge here.</p><p>We shall proceed in the following manner. First we shall discuss related work. Secondly, we shall establish the nature of the concept of stigmergy in the study of human practice. Third, we shall compare the concept of stigmergy to three well-established concept of coordination in order to satisfy ourselves that stigmergy is not interchangeable with them. Fourth, we shall employ the concept of stigmergy in a study of construction work in order to explore the analytical utility of the concept in a human context. Finally, a conclusion and some perspectives will be offered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related work</head><p>As indicated above, Grass¨¦ (1959) developed the concept of stigmergy during his study of termites, and it has since been used and applied to other groups of social insects (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Wilson, 1975)</ref>, not least in the study of ants (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">H? lldobler &amp; Wilson, 1994)</ref>. Furthermore, over the last decade or so the concept of stigmergy has been introduced to the field of telecommunication especially in connection with the development of algorithms for network traffic (e.g. Dorigo, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Bonabeau, &amp; Theraulaz, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr">Schoon- derwoerd, Holland, Bruten, &amp; Rothkrantz, 1996)</ref>, these algorithms are sometimes termed "ant algorithms" (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Dorigo et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">White &amp; Pagurek, 1998)</ref>, and to the field of robotics (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Beckers, 1996)</ref>. In addition to studies in the above-mentioned areas, the notion of stigmergy has appeared in the study of human practice as well (including socio-technical studies). We shall be especially focused on these latter contributions in this section, as they are especially relevant for our topic, namely, the concept of stigmergy in the study of human practice. <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Susi and Ziemke (2001)</ref> draws attention to the concept of stigmergy in human practice. Susi and Ziemke reviews the theoretical positions of activity theory, distributed cognition and situated action and comes to the conclusion that all three theoretical positions have a something in common, in relation to how they describe the role of artifacts in collaborative activity. The common denominator, according to Susi and Ziemke, can be described in terms of the concept of stigmergy.</p><p>Van Dyke Parunak (2006) develops a schema for analysing stigmergy among human actors and find that humans regularly use marks or signs in the environment to coordinate distributed activities. He provides an overview or schema involving stigmergy in various settings, including market systems, elections, document editing, and viral marketing. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ricci et al. (2007)</ref> presents the notion of cognitive stigmergy placing the concept solidly in the realm of human activity. The authors are interested in producing an engineering framework for cognitive agents as a means of supporting knowledge based social activities. <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Tummolini and Castelfrananchi (2007)</ref> creates a taxonomy of stigmergy in different social situations. That is, the authors focus on how leaving traces in the environment (stigma) may give rise to a variety of interpretations and communicative situations across a range of human social contexts. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Marsh and Onof (2008)</ref> discuss the phenomenon of stigmergy at the intersection of individual action and the social corpora. The authors are especially interested in the stigmergic character of social epistemology as knowledge is conditioned, modified and disseminated within communities of competent actors. In addition, the article makes the proposition that, as modifiable environmental considerations, according to the extended mind thesis, must be factored into cognitive abilities, this kind of cognition is essentially stigmergic.</p><p>Originally <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Grass¨¦ (1959)</ref> coined the concept of stigmergy as a concept of coordination, and it is the position taken in this paper that we should treat it as such in the context of human practice as well.</p><p>None of the literature on stigmergy in human practice seems to deal with how the concept of stigmergy relate to other concepts of coordination. We shall deal with this gap in this paper. It seems prudent to ask: Does the concept of stigmergy differ from other already established concepts of coordination i.e. does it add anything new to the analysis of human practice? We shall address this question next by explicitly and systematically comparing the concept of stigmergy to well-established notions of coordination, including the concepts of articulation work, awareness and feed through. However, before we are ready to start with the comparison we have to establish a few fundamentals in regard to how we may perceive the concept of stigmergy in the context of human practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">From insect behaviour to human practice: stigmergy as a heed concept</head><p>As mentioned above, the concept of stigmergy emerged in the study of social insects. Moreover, we may note that <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Grass¨¦ (1959)</ref> and others (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Smith, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Wilson, 1975)</ref> used a stimuli-response model of action characteristic of the field of entomology in their work. Grass¨¦ found that when looking at a group of termites, they all seem to cooperate in building nests, etc., but when looking at single individuals, they seem to be working, as if they were alone and not involved in any collective behaviour. This appeared to be a paradox until Grass¨¦ introduced the concept of stigmergy. Grass¨¦ showed that the regulation of building activities among social insects does not depend so much on the workers themselves as on the nest structure. A stimulating configuration triggers a building action of a termite worker, transforming the configuration into another configuration that may in turn trigger another (possibly different) action performed by the same termite or any other worker in the colony <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Grass¨¦, 1959)</ref>. Thus, work in the termite colony is partly coordinated by virtue of the individual termites acting in a stimuli-response manner on evidence of work accomplished previously by themselves or others.</p><p>We must be careful not to transpose this model of action to the context of human practice. The stimuli-response mode of action is not characteristic of human practice in complex work domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bourdieu, 1977</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bourdieu, , 1992</ref><ref type="bibr">Christen- sen, 2007</ref><ref type="bibr">Christen- sen, , 2008</ref>). We must exorcise or disassociate the concept of stigmergy from any stimuli-response model of action that may linger from the concept's origin in the field of entomology if we are to apply the concept to the analysis of human practice.</p><p>Below, we will suggest that stigmergy may be understood as a "heed concept" when applied to human practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Stigmergy as a heed concept</head><p>In this section we will, based on the work of the eminent and influential <ref type="bibr">British philosopher Ryle (1955)</ref>, describe stigmergy as a "heed concept" in an effort to solidly place the concept within the realm of human practice and disassociate it from the stimuli-response model of its origin.</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr">Ryle (1955, p. 135)</ref>, the category of "heed concepts" includes: noticing, taking care, attending, minding, applying one's mind, concentrating, putting one's heart into something, thinking what one is doing, alertness, interest, intentness, studying, trying. Perhaps stigmergy could also be considered a heed concept. Let us elaborate.</p><p>When a person hums as he walks, he is doing two things at once, either of which he might interrupt without interrupting the other. But when we speak of a person minding what he is doing e.g. when he is reading (or for example designing) we are not saying that he is doing two things at once. He could not stop his reading while continuing his attention to it <ref type="bibr">(Ryle, 1955, p. 138)</ref>. In a similar vein, we may add that he could not stop e.g. his designing while continuing to be engaged in stigmergy (i.e. acting on physical traces of the design of others). He could of course continue to read but cease to attend <ref type="bibr">(Ryle, 1955, p. 138)</ref>, or continue to design but cease to engage in stigmergy. The use of pairs of words such as "read" and "attend" or "design" and "stigmergy" suggests that there are two synchronous or perhaps coupled processes going on whenever both words are properly used, but that is not the case. This is a feature in the use of heed concepts <ref type="bibr">(Ryle, 1955, p. 138)</ref>.</p><p>If we accept at least preliminarily the notion of stigmergy as a heed concept, we may say that performing a task engaged in stigmergy is one, rather than two coupled activities. The point is not least that stigmergy cannot take place prior to the performance of a task or afterwards for that matter. It is part of the task, or more precisely, it is a characteristic way of performing the task. In this manner stigmergy shares the quality of other heed concepts. However, there are a few features that set stigmergy apart from other more general heed concepts. For example, stigmergy is always part of cooperative work in the sense that stigmergy by definition is the integration of interdependent work task by virtue of individuals acting on the physical traces of work previously accomplished by others. In comparison, doing something attentively or doing it carefully (both general heed concepts) is obviously not necessarily part of cooperative work and its integration. In this manner stigmergy is a specialised heed concept to be used only in the context of describing the coordination of cooperative work.</p><p>Let us consider a short example of how stigmergy may be applied as a heed concept in the analysis of human practice. The example concerns the coordination of building design teamwork through practices of stigmergy. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Christensen (2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Christensen ( , 2008</ref> building design is a cooperative effort, involving e.g. architects, construction engineers, and a series of specialists on sanitation, ventilation, electrical instillations, etc., that partly coordinate their joint efforts of designing a building through practices of stigmergy where they pay heed to the physical evidence of work accomplished by other as a part of doing their own work, and this has a coordinative effect. Let us elaborate. Each member of the work ensemble all makes a distinct contribution in the form of representation of the building covering his or her respective areas of expertise. The architect creates the outline of the building. On that basis the construction engineer creates the geometry of the concrete structure in a separate construction model or representation. Subsequently, the sanitation specialist, for example, will pay heed to the representations of the concrete structure and seek to align the sanitation with it. In a similar manner, the electricity specialist, for example, will pay heed to the previously created representations and seek to align the wiring of the electricity with it. That is to say, the individual actor creates and changes the form of a visual representation of the building, not for the purpose of conveying a message, but simply as a part of designing a building; another actor pays heed to it and acts upon it. In this manner, components of the building such as concrete structure, sanitation, ventilation and electricity are brought into alignment with the overall design <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Christensen, 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Christensen, , 2008</ref>.</p><p>Of course actors in building design meet on a regular basis in meetings or over the telephone in order to discuss the "big picture," the overall progress of the project, who does what when, etc. However, when it comes to the coordination of the "small things" the multitude of details involved in designing a building, this is done not only in meetings or over the phone (there is no time), but also directly with the representations exchanged by the use of an online repository. That is, on the detail level of the representations of the building, design work is primarily coordinated through the work itself, i.e. through practices of stigmergy, rather than through e.g. meetings about it <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Christensen, 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Christensen, , 2008</ref>.</p><p>What we are implying, then, is that when actors coordinate their cooperative efforts by paying heed to the evidence of work previously accomplished by others we may describe them as engaged in practices of stigmergy. Stigmergy is a heed concept. However, it is important to note that before we are in a position to fully embrace this assertion, before we may be comfortable with it, we must as mentioned exorcise or disassociate the concept of stigmergy from any stimuli-response model of action that may linger from the concept's origin in the field of entomology. The stimuli-response mode of action is not characteristic of human practice in complex work domains such as the building process, including practices of stigmergy <ref type="bibr">(Bour- dieu, 1977</ref><ref type="bibr">(Bour- dieu, , 1992</ref>.</p><p>If not based on stimuli-response then what is the basis for practices of stigmergy in a human context? How does an individual actor know how to act in relation to the physical evidence of work previously accomplished by others in relation to a specific task in a given environment such as for example the building process?</p><p>In regard to these pertinent questions we may say that the ability to participate in practice in the building process and work with for example representational artifacts is grounded in skills and techniques that may be conceived of as acquired by the individual actor not least through apprenticeship as a "feel for the tasks." The habitus, using Bourdieu's (1992) concept, of for example an accomplished building engineer acts as a set of dispositions towards certain ways of doing and being, acting and interacting that are in accord with or reflects the nature of the field of building design. The habitus is and acts as a set of "pre-perceptive anticipations, a sort of practical induction based on previous experience" (Bourdieu, 1992, p. 80). The habitus amounts to a feel for the task or game: tain ways of doing and being, acting and interacting that are in accord with or reflects the nature of the building process. These dispositions are in play in practices of stigmergy as the actor pays heed to the evidence of design work previously accomplished by others when performing his or her own tasks. As such it is not simply a matter of stimuli-response.</p><p>Of course this does not contradict the assertion that termites for their part engage in what may be described in terms of a sequence of stimuli-response action. We are merely suggesting that the stimuli-response mode of action is not characteristic of human practice, including practices of stigmergy.</p><p>These considerations aside, the question is as mentioned this: does the concept of stigmergy add anything to our ability to account for the coordination of cooperative work in a human context? As mentioned we will explore this question by explicitly comparing the concept of stigmergy to well-established concepts of coordination, namely articulation work (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gerson &amp; Star, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Schmidt, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Schmidt &amp; Bannon, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Strauss, 1985</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Strauss, , 1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Strauss, Fagerhaugh, Suczek, &amp; Wiener, 1985)</ref> awareness (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heath &amp; Luff, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Heath, Svensson, Hindmarsh, Luff, &amp; Lehn, 2002</ref>) and feedthrough (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Dix, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dix &amp; Beale, 1996</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Stigmergy compared to articulation work</head><p>The actor, having deeply internalised the regularities of the game, does what he must do, at the moment it is necessary, without the need to ask <ref type="bibr">[himself]</ref> explicitly what needs to be done. He does not need consciously to know what he does in order to do it and even less to raise explicitly the question (except in some critical situations) of knowing explicitly what others might do in return <ref type="bibr">(Bourdieu, 1992, p. 98</ref>).</p><p>Actors acquire a feel for a given domain through training and experience that become embodied as a set of practical schemes of perception and action. For example, the skill to handle the task, including the complex perceptual field of the architectural plans, and to see for instance "where the roofing felt goes," is central to what it means to see the world through the eyes of a building engineer. Being able to highlight certain aspects of a representation of a building according to a specific task is part of what it means to be an accomplished building actor in this field. The relevant unit of analysis, then, is not limited to the individual as an isolated entity, rather it is the wider building process where a community of competent practitioners are engaged, most of whom have never meet each other, but who nonetheless expect each other to categorise and act in this field in ways that are relevant and predictable and pertain to the work, tools and artifacts that constitute the community of practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Christensen, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>The habitus, then, using Bourdieu's (1992) concept, of for example an accomplished architect, building engineer, craftsman or builder acts as a set of dispositions towards cerIn this section we shall compare the concept of stigmergy to the concept of articulation work in order to determine if they are interchangeable concepts or not.</p><p>The concept of articulation work has been used extensively in order to describe and analyse the coordination of cooperative work in a human context. A series of focused, in-depth field studies have been undertaken with the specific purpose of investigating how the distributed activities of cooperative work arrangements are articulated and, in particular, how prescribed artifacts are devised, appropriated and used for these purposes (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bardram &amp; Bossen, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Carstensen &amp; S?rensen, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Schmidt &amp; Bannon, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schmidt &amp; Simone, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr">Schmidt &amp; Wag- ner, 2004</ref>).</p><p>Articulation work often revolves around time schedules and meetings where the progress of work is discussed, dates are settled, responsibilities cleared up, and work tasks are distributed and redistributed (if need be). That is, articulation work often revolves around the question of who does what when? This question can be addressed in various ways, including in meetings, emails, phone conferences, etc. In the words of <ref type="bibr">Strauss (1985, p. 8)</ref>, articulation work is a kind of supra-type work in any division of labour, done by the various actors concerning the meshing and integration of interdependencies inherent in cooperative work. The prefix "supra" is of key importance here. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In the context of cooperative work this could entail that articulation work comes before or stands in a meta-relationship to a work task or a set of work tasks performed. We could suggest that the distinction between the articulation work and the cooperative work articulated is an inherent feature of the concept of articulation work. Schmidt describes articulation work as reflexive second order activities <ref type="bibr">(Schmidt, 2002, p. 464)</ref>. It is safe to say that the distinction between the articulation work and the cooperative work articulated is an inherent feature of the concept of articulation work. In comparison, using the concept of stigmergy does not entail making a distinction between the work and extra activities aimed solely at coordinating the work. That would be a contradiction in terms considering that stigmergy as we described it above is a heed concept. Recall that when we speak of someone performing a cooperative work task engaged in stigmergy we are not saying that he or she is doing two things at once. He or she could not stop the performance of the task and continue to be engaged in stigmergy. The usage of a heed concept such as stigmergy, and this is meant to reiterate a point made above, has the merits of suggesting that what is described is one activity with a special character, rather than two activities that are somehow interrelated in their execution (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Ryle, 1955)</ref>. In comparison, we may say that actors engaged in articulation work in relation to a set of cooperative work tasks, may stop performing the tasks and continue any articulation work in relation to their coordination. For example, two carpenters engaged in distributed cooperative work tasks on a rooftop may stop working on the roof and continue their conversation concerning how to coordinate their interdependent efforts -in fact this may often be the case. In this manner articulation work may be said to stand in a supra type relationship to the work tasks articulated, whereas stigmergy may not. That is, articulation work may be an activity separate from the performance of the cooperative work articulated, and in comparison stigmergy may not.</p><p>The point we are trying to make is that as stigmergy is a heed concept i.e. a characteristic way of performing a cooperative work task (to a coordinative effect) it does not qualify to be described as an effort that may be said to stand in a supra-type relationship to the tasks performed. In this manner the concept of stigmergy is not interchangeable with the concept of articulation work.</p><p>In sum, we have argued that the concept of stigmergy is not interchangeable with the concept of articulation work, although it may of course complement it.</p><p>on the London Underground as well as the studies of air traffic control work by the Lancaster group <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Harper &amp; Hughes, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Harper, Hughes, &amp; Shapiro, 1989a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">, 1989b</ref>. In these studies it was noted how collaborative activity in complex organizational environments rests on the individuals' abilities to create awareness through bodily conduct whilst engaged in their respective activities. That is, it was described how actors produce awareness by rendering a feature of their conduct or a feature in the environment selectively available to others. We shall elaborate.</p><p>According to Heath and associates <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Heath et al., 2002</ref>, p. 318), the ways in which actors produce awareness is inextricably embedded in the activities in which they are engaged, and the ways in which those activities unfold.</p><p>Simply put, what individuals are aware of depends upon the activities they and others are engaged in. Awareness, then, is a practical accomplishment that arises in and through action and activity. This feature of awareness is shared by stigmergy in the sense that both awareness and stigmergy are inextricably part of performing the work. However, there are also important differences between awareness and stigmergy, as we shall see.</p><p>In the course of their work performance actors may find that the activity in which they are engaged becomes potentially relevant for others within the domain and yet their colleagues are seemingly involved in something else. In such circumstances, an actor may modulate an activity (e.g. speak louder, stare in an obvious manner, or overtly move an object about), to enable others to gain awareness of some matter at hand, without demanding that anybody should respond. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heath and Luff (1992)</ref> give a fine example of this as they describe how the operators in a control room coordinate train traffic and movement of passengers on a particular line. The control room can house several staff, including the Line Controller who coordinates the dayto-day running of the railway and the Divisional Information Assistant (DIA) who, amongst other things, provides information to passengers and to Station Managers <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Heath &amp; Luff, 1992)</ref>. In this setting awareness is produced through very delicate bodily practices:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Stigmergy compared to awareness</head><p>In this section we will compare the concept of stigmergy to the concept of awareness in order to determine if they are interchangeable concepts or not.</p><p>The idea of awareness as a concept of coordination originally emerged in a number of work place studies by not least <ref type="bibr">Luff (1992, 1996)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>of Line Control Rooms</head><p>On occasions, it may be necessary for the Controller to draw the DIA's attention to particular events or activities, even as they emerge within the management of a certain task or problem. For example, as he is speaking to an operator or signalman, the Controller may laugh or produce an exclamation and thereby encourage the DIA to monitor the call more carefully. Or, as he turns to his timetable or glances at the fixed line diagram, the Controller will swear, feign momentary illness or even sing a couple of bars of a song to draw the DIA's attention to an emergent problem within the operation of the service. The various objects used by the Controller and DIA to gain a more explicit orientation from the other(s) towards a particular event or activity, are carefully designed to encourage a particular form of co-par-ticipation from a colleague, but rarely demand the other's attention. They allow the individual to continue with an activity in which they might be engaged, whilst simultaneously inviting them to carefully monitor a concurrent event <ref type="bibr">(Heath &amp; Luff, 1992, p. 81)</ref>.</p><p>In this manner actors in the underground control room create awareness of their activities through modulation of their activities with bodily conduct directed at co-located colleagues in an unobtrusive way. That is, as Heath and associates <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Heath et al., 2002</ref>, p. 321) express it "actors may render activities selectively available" to their colleagues. How does this feature of awareness compare to stigmergy? We could suggest that stigmergy does not involve individuals rendering activities deliberately or selectively available to others through bodily conduct (e.g. modulations in voice, gesture, pose, stance, gaze, glance, etc.). Stigmergy does not rely on this sort of selective rendering of activities in the sense that stigmergy merely refers to actors in cooperative work acting on the physical evidence of work previously accomplished by others to a coordinative effect.</p><p>Furthermore, unlike much production of awareness through bodily conduct, stigmergy does not rely on colocation, as we shall see now. Awareness practices are commonly associated with a particular type of workplace. In part, this association derives from the fieldwork settings of the studies that contributed to the recognition and understanding of the phenomenon in the first place. These settings have certain characteristics that make awareness pertinent and have been described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Suchman (1997)</ref> as "centres of coordination." These include such settings as subway control rooms, air traffic control rooms, newsrooms, trading rooms, and the like. According to Heath and associates <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Heath et al., 2002</ref>, p. 320), one of the important characteristics of such work places is that personnel is co-located in the "same" physical domain (through continually interact with others outside that domain). As indicated, co-location enables not least the production of awareness through bodily conduct such as modulations in voice, gesture, pose, stance, gaze and glance whereby actors render a feature in their actions or in the environment selectively available to others <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Heath et al., 2002</ref>). How does the notion of co-location relate to stigmergy? We could suggest that in contrast to awareness, colocation is irrelevant for stigmergy in the sense that for an individual acting of the physical evidence of work previously accomplished by others the co-presence of these "others" is irrelevant or unnecessary. That is, in respect to the notion of co-location awareness and stigmergy differ.</p><p>Compared to awareness, then, stigmergy does not involve rendering activities selectively available to colocated colleagues through bodily conduct or otherwise. That is, co-location is irrelevant in stigmergy just as there is no place or need in stigmergy for bodily gestures. Furthermore, stigmergy is in no way confined to specific domains such as centres of coordination in the sense that stigmergy may transgress several settings -think of how stigmergy with architectural representations transgress several physical settings (i.e. architectural office, static engineers office, building services office, etc.).</p><p>We could suggest that the difference between stigmergy and awareness is (partly) the difference between heeding the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others (stigmergy) and rendering activities selectively available to co-located others through bodily conduct that these others in turn may take heed of (awareness). Note that one of the differences is related to the object that is paid heed to. Acting stigmertively involves paying heed to the physical traces of work previously accomplished by others, whereas producing awareness involves bodily conduct that co-present others may take heed of subsequently. That is, in stigmergy it is the state of the material field of work that is heeded, and in awareness the heeded object is mainly bodily conduct.</p><p>In sum, we have argued that the concept of stigmergy is not interchangeable with the concept of awareness (although it may complement it).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Stigmergy compared to feedthrough</head><p>Leaving the distinctions between the concepts of articulation work, awareness and stigmergy for now, another concern appears. Perhaps another, more established concepts is already doing what stigmergy does. Are stigmergy and feedthrough, for example, interchangeable concepts? In addition to contrasting stigmergy with articulation work and awareness, perhaps it could also be helpful to contrast the concept of stigmergy with Dix's concept of feedthrough <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Dix, 1997)</ref>. We shall do so in this section.</p><p>According to Dix in some cases cooperative work is coordinated through the artifact rather than by direct face-to-face interaction or by other forms of verbal interaction. Dix states that:</p><p>In a cooperative setting not only is it important to see one's own updates, but also to see the effects of other people's actions. This is feedthrough. The presence of feedthrough effectively creates an additional channel of communication through the artefacts themselves <ref type="bibr">(Dix, 1997, p. 38</ref>).</p><p>According to Dix, this form of coordination is often more important than direct verbal communication. It is effective, partly because it is tied so closely to the work itself, and partly because it is implicit, unconsciously noted and acted upon. So far Dix is describing a coordinative practice akin to stigmergy. Consider, however, RamdunyEllis, 2002 in a discussion of awareness of user activity in a collaborative environment:</p><p>Delivering feedthrough at the wrong pace can be problematic. If it is too slow, users may have to act without up to-date knowledge of one another's actions. If it is too fast, users may be distracted by irrelevant changes. Some feedthrough is very goal-directed -information directly used by users in their tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Ramduny-Ellis, 2002</ref>, p. 122).</p><p>The notion that feedthrough can be delivered at the "wrong pace" seems to indicate that in some instances the "information" that feed through the artifacts is distinct from the efforts that are being coordinated. How else could it be delivered at the "wrong pace"? It seems that, at least in some instances, the concept of feedthrough is concerned with "meta-information" used to coordinate collaborative work.</p><p>Furthermore, the concept of feedthrough seems to rely on the notion that "people's actions" feed through the artifacts from actor A to actor B in the form of "information." Dix and Beale:</p><p>The sharing of information comes because of feedthrough, when people are aware of and respond to the effects of one another's actions. In the sales situation the information from the factory floor must be timely, that is feedthrough of the factory staff's actions to the sales force <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Dix, 1996)</ref>.</p><p>Perhaps a closer look at the concept of information is warranted. The scientific formulation of the concept of "information" can be traced back to the "mathematical theory of communication" developed shortly after WWII by Claude E. Shannon for the purpose of measuring the transportation capacities of communication networks <ref type="bibr">(Shannon, 1948, p. 379)</ref>. Of course, the word "information" was in common usage for many years before its scientific conceptualisation. It was recorded in print in 1390 to mean "communication" or "knowledge" or "news" of some fact or occurrence (Oxford English Dictionary). However, as a part of his mathematical theory of communication, Shannon coined a definition of information that transformed it into a physical parameter capable of quantification. He accomplished this by separating information and meaning. He applied "meaning" to the semantic part of a message and used "information" to refer to the quantity of different possible messages that could be carried along a channel of communication at any one time depending on the length of the message and on the number of choices of symbols for transmission at each point in time <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Aspray, 1986)</ref>. For his purpose, this was quite appropriate, because semantic aspects of communication are irrelevant to the engineering problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Shannon, 1948)</ref>. Shannon had coined a quantitative concept to be used for measuring and emphasised that "information" should not be confused with "meaning" <ref type="bibr">(Shannon &amp; Weaver, 1949, p. 8)</ref>.</p><p>In relation to the concept of feedthrough, does the term "information" refer to a quantitative measure, to meaning or both? Perhaps the very idea that information or some other fixed correlation between ideas and symbols migrate through the artifact is untenable. Is the concept of feedthrough associated with the notion of telementation? Perhaps, to the extent that it suggests that information is fed from actor A to actor B through the conduit of artifacts. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Harris (1981)</ref> holds that it is not tenable to maintain that meaning can take a fixed form (of for example information) and migrate from head to head via artifacts or other means. That is to say, there is no stable entity of for example information that may be propelled back and forth between actors like a tennis ball in a game of tennis. Consequently, in practice there is no semiological tennis ball that may be feed through form actor A to actor B. It seems that we have no other recourse but to suggest that the concept of feedthrough is associated with the notion of telementation. In addition, we could suggest that there is a kinship of sorts between Harris' (1981) notion of telementation and what <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Reddy (1979)</ref> has dubbed the conduit metaphor. Perhaps the concept of feedthrough is a form of the conduit metaphor.</p><p>According to Reddy, the English language alone hosts more than a hundred expressions based on what he calls "the conduit metaphor" <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Reddy, 1979)</ref>. Reddy calls it "the conduit metaphor," because it implies that thoughts are transferred from actor A to actor B through some conduit or other. Reddy argues that it is almost impossible for an English speaker to discuss communication without committing to some form or other of that metaphor. Is the concept of feedthrough a commitment to a form of conduit metaphor? Perhaps, to the extent that it suggests that information is fed from actor A to actor B through the conduit of artifacts (e.g. Ramduny-Ellis, 2002, p. 122). If we accept this, the analytical use of the concept of feedthrough is, in some instances, a commitment to a form of the conduit metaphor as well as the notion of telementation.</p><p>In contrast to the concept of feedthrough, the concept of stigmergy, as we are attempting to cast it, does not rely on the notion of information, does not commit to the idea of telementation and is not a form of the conduit metaphor (as far as I can see). That is, actors engaged in practices of stigmergy may have as a basis for their actions something quite different from e.g. telementation, namely, acquired dispositions to perceive, comprehend and act that could be interpreted as oriented towards one task or another (as mentioned above). In sum, the concept of stigmergy and the concept of feedthrough are not interchangeable concepts.</p><p>Having established that stigmergy is not interchangeable with the concepts of articulation work, awareness and feedthrough, we will now consider how these modes of coordination may be interconnected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Stigmergy, awareness and articulation work</head><p>For the sake of clarity, perhaps it would be prudent to pause at this juncture and briefly take stock. We shall do so not least in regard to the relationship between stigmergy, awareness and articulation work.</p><p>Above, the notion that cooperative work may be coordinated by virtue of individuals acting on the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others was conceptualised as stigmergy. We traced the origins of the concept of stigmergy to the field of entomology. In relation to this we noted that a stimuli-response model of action was associated with the use of the concept of stigmergy in this research field.</p><p>In relation to transposing the concept of stigmergy to the field of CSCW, i.e. to the analysis of the coordination of cooperative work, we found a need to supplant this stimuli-response model of action. We argued that stigmergy in a human context may be conceived of as practice based on acquired skills and techniques that may be described as embodied in the habitus of the individual actors, rather than in terms of stimuli-response.</p><p>Subsequently, we suggested that stigmergy could be described as a heed concept. The notion that stigmergy is a heed concept has the merit of suggesting that stigmergy is a characteristic manner in which cooperative work may be performed, rather than a separate activity. Following this, we asked if the concept of stigmergy would add anything to our ability to account for the coordination of cooperative work? In order to address this question we compared the concept of stigmergy to not least the concepts of articulation work and awareness. We found that none of these concept where interchangeable to the concept of stigmergy.</p><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bardram (1998)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">, and Gregory (1997)</ref>, it can be fruitful to consider the dynamics of cooperative work and explore how different modes of coordination are interrelated.</p><note type="other">drawing on Engestr? m, Brown, Christopher</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2</head><p>Above, we indicated that articulation work, stigmergy and awareness may act in concert as distinct yet interconnected modes of coordination in cooperative work. We will elaborate on this now.</p><p>The constitution and articulation of the cooperative work tasks in advance of their performance may be handled through articulation work with coordinative artifacts. For example, on a construction site planners partly constitute the schedule and distribution of tasks through articulation work with planning documents such as Gantt charts. When the distributed tasks in turn are to be actually performed and integrated on a concrete level, stigmergy may complement articulation work. For example, cooperative work tasks in the building process may be integrated stigmertively i.e. on the level of the concrete material performance of the tasks by virtue of actors acting on the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others (we will elaborate on this below). On par with stigmergy, awareness practices may also play their part in regard to the integration of cooperative work tasks in the concrete i.e. as they are performed. Recall the awareness practices described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Heath and Luff (1992)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Heath and associ- ates (2002)</ref> where coordination is partly achieved by virtue of actors rendering activities selectively available to colocated others through bodily conduct that these others in turn may take heed of. Finally, articulation work may take on the character of an evaluation or ordering process after the tasks have been performed. In the building process, for example, this sort of articulation work may take place in meetings where the schedule and the representations of the distributed tasks on the planning documents are calibrated to reflect the actual progress of the tasks on the building site.</p><p>It seems that articulation work may be performed prior, in parallel to, and after the performance of the tasks articulated (articulation work may be described as a "supratype" or "second order" activity precisely because it may be performed separately from the tasks -even in instances where articulation work is performed in parallel to the tasks, articulation work may as mentioned be considered a supra-type activity). Note also how stigmergy may not be performed prior, in parallel to, and after the performance of the tasks articulated in that stigmergy is a characteristic manner in which cooperative work may be performed to a coordinative effect, rather than a separate activity. As mentioned above, stigmergy (and possibly awareness) are heed concepts.</p><p>In sum, articulation work handles the initial high-level coordination concerned with stipulating the ensemble of task and their distribution among the cooperative work ensemble. Subsequently, practices of stigmergy are in play to a coordinative effect on the level of the physical performance of the tasks. In a related manner awareness practices may provide the integration of distributed tasks. Finally, articulation work comes into the picture as the status of the ensemble of distributed tasks are evaluated and in turn reconfigured and redistributed (if need be). Subsequently, the physical task performance can start over again from a different starting point. At a certain juncture the process is discontinued following the fulfilment of a given set of criteria associated with the satisfactory completion and integration of all tasks associated with a particular project or subset of one such project. In this manner articulation work, awareness and stigmergy may complement each other in a recursive way as distinct yet interconnected modes of coordination in cooperative work.</p><p>Having rendered the concept of stigmergy in relation to other complementary modes of coordination we are now in a position to proceed and apply the concept of stigmergy to a study of construction work. We will do so in order to explore the utility of the concept as an analytical tool in this context. Before commencing with the study, we shall briefly concern ourselves with the methods and the research setting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Methods and research setting</head><p>This study involves ethnographic fieldwork carried out in the course of 14 months on several building sites. In this period, construction work in relation to several building projects was studied. One of the building projects, the development of the new domicile for a publishing house, was a multi-storey building in glass, steel and concrete constructed at the edge of the city of Copenhagen's harbour (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>). A combination of observation and interviews was used. The fieldwork also included collecting (scanning, taking screenshots or photographs of) artifacts used and produced by the actors engaged in the building projects.</p><p>Constructing a large building is a highly complex cooperative work endeavour constituted by numerous distributed and interdependent tasks carried out by a diverse network of actors over a period of several years.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.">Practices of stigmergy in construction work</head><p>In construction work, as in building design <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Christensen, 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Christensen, , 2008</ref>, interdependent tasks may be partly integrated by virtue of individuals paying heed to the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others while performing their own tasks. Cooperative construction work tasks may be integrated through practices of stigmergy. As a case in point we shall consider the integration of cooperative work tasks pertaining to the construction of interior walls in a large building project.</p><p>In the interior construction stage of a large building project a considerable number of partition walls are constructed. Partition walls are what divide the building into for instance units of office space. The construction of these walls is a cooperative work process involving a number of different trades such as carpenters, electricians and painters (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref>).</p><p>The initial parts of a partition wall is constructed by a carpenter in the form of a frame made of light weight steel grinders fitted with plasterboards on the one side. At a later point in time, another actor, namely, an electrician will arrive and pay heed to the work carried out and seek to align the wiring of the electrical circuits with it. That is, the electrician will drill holes in the plasterboard to accommodate the electrical instillations and he or she will pull electrical cables through little holes in the vertical steel grinders of the frame and connect them to the electrical system as a whole. When the electrician is done and has left the scene, the carpenter returns to close the wall i.e. clad the second side of the wall in plasterboards in accordance with the previous work done. That is, the carpenter must take notice of the work previously performed by himself and the electrician as he seeks to put up the second round of plasterboards. Subsequently, the painter shows up to paint what the others have erected. At this point the wall in-the-making will have been worked onto consist of a steel frame, plasterboards on the first side, electrical instillations inside, and plasterboards on the second side. Finding the wall in this state the painter paints the wall with several coats of paint.</p><p>In this manner the work ensemble including carpenter, electrician and painter all make distinct contributions towards the construction of the wall in accordance with their respective areas of expertise. We could say that the individual actor creates and changes the form of the wall in-the-making, not for the purpose of conveying a message, but simply as part of performing their individually allotted tasks, in turn another actor pays heed to and acts upon the material evidence of the work of others. This is partly how the cooperative work tasks pertaining to the construction of partition walls are integrated through practice of stigmergy.</p><p>Perhaps to allow for full appreciation of the importance of this mode of coordination in building construction work, it would prudent to recall that no formal construct (e.g. architectural plan) exhaustively stipulates a concrete practice. Plans are underspecified with respect to that which is represented <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Suchman, 1987)</ref>, and architectural plans for the construction of for example partition walls are no exception. The actors have to "fill in the blanks" for themselves, so to speak, and acting on the evidence of work previously accomplished by others may be said to be one way of doing this. Furthermore, please bear in mind that architectural plans for specific building parts such as walls are not assembly manuals like those that come with for example IKEA furniture, rather architectural plans represent mainly how parts of the building it are supposed to look in the final state. Consequently, the assembly of for example partition walls is not covered in architectural plans.</p><p>In addition, the pace of contemporary construction work is such that as soon as one actor (e.g. carpenter) has completed a task, time does not allow for much standing around and talking to the next actor (e.g. electrician) even though their tasks are interdependent and there are numerous details that need to be integrated. Of course articulation work through talk on the building site or in weekly coordination meetings may contribute to the integration of cooperative construction work tasks, but so may acting on the material evidence of work previously accomplished.</p><p>The point is that in addition to various kinds of articulation work in meetings and with and without coordinative artifacts such as time schedules, cooperative construction work is coordinated by virtue of actors paying heed to the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others while performing their own tasks.</p><p>At this juncture we may ask if the physical "evidence" of work may be promoted by the way in which the work is performed making it more straightforward for others to act on in practice of stigmergy?</p><p>3 With reference to our case above, we may say that an electrician could for example install the electrical wiring and let a cable hang conspicuously visible in order to make the carpenter pay heed to it and afford it the required space as the wall is closed with the second layer of plasterboards (if the cables are completely hidden to the carpenters view he or she may accidentally put a nail through it with the nail gun as the second layer of plasterboards are mounted on the frame of the wall). This raises an interesting point: coordination through the material field of work may also be a matter of being mindful of the work that is to be performed by others looking forward in time, rather than only a matter of paying heed to work previously accomplished by others.</p><p>At this point we may remind ourselves "the economy of logic <ref type="bibr">[. . .]</ref> dictates that no more logic is mobilised than is required by the needs of practice" <ref type="bibr">(Bourdieu, 1992, p. 145)</ref>. Following Bourdieu, we may say that the individual actors will engage in no more physical and cognitive effort than is practically necessary. That is, unless an actor has practical reasons for considering the situation from the perspective of others such as for example subsequent actors that may follow in practices of stigmergy, he or she will retain his or her own perspective and just carry out the work without though for the perspectives of others. Note that it is of course an empirical matter, something that differs from case to case, exactly how this plays out in practice. It is important to note that stigmergy, as a coordinative practice, is in not dependant on such forward looking mindfulness although it may be part of the larger set of practices.</p><p>In sum, in construction work, cooperative work tasks are (partly) integrated through practices of stigmergy.</p><p>alone. Furthermore, the comments and opinions of Kristian Kreiner are also greatly appreciated. Finally, thanks to Morten Visby for proof reading.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10.">Conclusion and perspectives</head><p>The concept of stigmergy was not originally developed in order to describe human practice, rather it was developed within the field of entomology i.e. the study of social insects. This study has raised and addressed a question central to any attempt to introduce the concept of stigmergy to the study of human practice: Does the concept of stigmergy add anything to our ability to account for the coordination of human cooperative work or is it simply interchangeable to already existing concepts? We have argued that it does add a new analytical perspective.</p><p>Initially we suggested that in the context of human practice it is fruitful to understand stigmergy as a "heed" concept. That is, stigmergy refers to the phenomenon that distributed cooperative work tasks may be partly integrated by virtue of individuals paying heed to the material evidence of work previously accomplished by others while performing their own tasks. Based on this understanding of the concept of stigmergy in the context of human practice we explicitly compared and delimited the concept in relation to well-established concept describing human coordinative practices. We found that it differs from these concepts. We found that the concept of stigmergy is not interchangeable to well-established concepts of coordination such as articulation work, awareness and feedthrough. Finally, we explored the potential of the concept of stigmergy in an empirical study of coordinative practice in construction work in order to further investigate the utility of the notion of stigmergy as an analytical tool in the context of human practice.</p><p>In regard to perspectives for further research, we may note that the three concepts of stigmergy, articulation work and awareness could amount to a trinity in the analytical toolbox for the description and analysis of the coordination of cooperative work -each concept pertaining to a unique yet interconnected mode of coordination of cooperative work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. One of the building projects studied, a new domicile for a publishing house, nearing completion April 2009.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Interior wall in-the-making. The first and second frame shows the result of the carpenter's initial efforts. The third frame, including insert, shows the work of the electrician in progress. Finally, the fourth frame depicts the closed wall ready for painting.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> According to the Oxford dictionary &quot;supra&quot; designates a prefix used in describing a phenomenon that is transcending, before or above something else. It originates in the Latin supra &quot;above, beyond, before in time.&quot;</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Thank you to one of the anonymous reviewers for pointing this out.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Thank you to one of the anonymous reviewers for raising this question.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>I am indebted to the employees of PLH Arkitekter A/S. In addition, I am grateful to the staff of PHIL &amp; S?n A/Sespecially Louise Dyg. Moreover, Kjeld Schmidt's opinions and careful reading of the text is greatly appreciatedneedless to say, the responsibility for any errors is mine</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The scientific conceptualization of information: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Aspray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of the History of Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing for the dynamics of cooperative work activities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bardram</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1998 ACM conference on Computer supported cooperative work</title>
		<meeting>the 1998 ACM conference on Computer supported cooperative work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A web of coordinative artifacts: Collaborative work at a hospital ward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Bardram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2005 international ACM SIGGROUP conference on supporting group work</title>
		<meeting>the 2005 international ACM SIGGROUP conference on supporting group work<address><addrLine>Sanibel Island, Florida, USA; NY, Sanibel Island, FL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005-11-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From local actions to global tasks: Stigmergy and collective robotics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Beckers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Holland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Deneubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Artificial Life IV</title>
		<editor>R.A. Brooks, &amp; P. Maes</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Outline of a theory of practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bourdieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The logic of practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bourdieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>Polity Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From the social to the systematic: Mechanisms supporting coordination in design. Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Carstensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>S?rensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Collaborative Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practices of stigmergy in architectural work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2007 international ACM conference on supporting group work</title>
		<meeting>the 2007 international ACM conference on supporting group work<address><addrLine>Sanibel Island, Florida</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The logic of practices of stigmergy: Representational artifacts in architectural design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM 2008 conference on Computer supported cooperative work</title>
		<meeting>the ACM 2008 conference on Computer supported cooperative work<address><addrLine>San Diego, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="559" to="568" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coordinative practices in the building process: An ethnographic perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Challenges and perspectives for cooperative work on the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dix</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ERCIM workshop on CSCW and the Web</title>
		<meeting>the ERCIM workshop on CSCW and the Web<address><addrLine>Sankt Augustin, Germa</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Challenges for cooperative work on the web: An analytical approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dix</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Journal of Collaborative Computing: Computer-Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dix</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Beale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Remote cooperation: CSCW issues for mobile and tele-workers</title>
		<editor>A. J. Dix &amp; R. Beale</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ant algorithms and stigmergy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dorigo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonabeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Theraulaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Future Generation Computer Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="851" to="871" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Engestr? M</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gregory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordination, cooperation, and communication in the courts</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mind, culture, and activity</title>
		<editor>Y. O. Vasquez</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing due process in the workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Star</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Office Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">La reconstruction du nid et les coordinations interindividuelles chez Bellicositermes natalensis et Cubitermes sp. La th¨¦orie de la stigmergie: Essai d&apos;interpr¨¦tation des termites. constructeurs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Grass¨¦</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Insect Sociaux</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working in harmony: An examination of computer technology in air traffic control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H R</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the first European conference on computer supported cooperative work</title>
		<meeting>the first European conference on computer supported cooperative work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Gatwick</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1989-09" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The functionality of flight strips in ATC work. The report for the Civil Aviation Authority</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H R</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Lancaster Sociotechnics Group</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Sociology, Lancaster University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What a f-ing system! send &apos;em all to the same place and then expect us to stop them hitting: Making technology work in air traffic control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H R</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Technology in working order: Studies of work, interaction, and technology</title>
		<editor>G. Button</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Routlege</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The language Myth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<publisher>Duckworth</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaboration and control: Crisis mangement and multimedia technology in London Underground control rooms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Luff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="94" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>An. International Journal</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convergent activities: Line control and passenger information on the London Underground</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Heath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Luff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cognition and communication at work</title>
		<editor>Y. Engestr? m &amp; D. Middleton</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="129" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Configuring awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Svensson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hindmarsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Luff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="347" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Journey to the ants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>H? Lldobler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Bellknap Press/Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stigmergic epistemology, stigmergic cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Onof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A survey of environments and mechanisms for human-human stigmergy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Parunak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>D. Weyns, H. Van Dyke Parunak, &amp; F</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Environments for multi-agent systems II</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Berlin &amp;amp; Heidelberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impedance matching: When you need to know what</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ramduny-Ellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HCI2002</title>
		<editor>X. Faulkner, J. Finlay, &amp; F. Detienne</editor>
		<meeting>HCI2002<address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The conduit metaphor: A case of frame conflict in our language about language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Metaphor and thought</title>
		<editor>A. Ortony</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive stigmergy: Towards a framework based on agents and artifacts environments for multi-agent systems III</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ricci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Omicini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Viroli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gardelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>D. Weyns, H. Parunak, &amp; F. Michel</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="140" />
			<pubPlace>Berlin &amp; Heidelberg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The concept of mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ryle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
			<publisher>Hutchinson &amp; Co</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modes and mechanisms of interaction in cooperative work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<pubPlace>Roskilde, Denmark</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Ris? National Laboratory</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cooperation and complexity in sociotechnical Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>P. Salembier, &amp; T. H. Benchekroun</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="483" />
			<pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Remarks on the complexity of cooperative work. special issue of] Revue des sciences et technologies de l&apos;information, [s¨¦rie] Revue d&apos;intelligence artificielle (RSTI-RAI</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taking CSCW seriously: Supporting articulation work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">An International Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordination mechanisms: Towards a conceptual foundation of CSCW systems design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Simone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Supported Cooperative Work: The Journal of Collaborative Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ordering systems: Coordinative practices and artifacts in architectural design and planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Journal of Collaborative Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="408" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schoonderwoerd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Holland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bruten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rothkrantz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ant-based load balancing in telecommunications networks</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adaptive Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mathematical theory of communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Shannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Bell System Technical Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The mathematical theory of communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Shannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Weaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1949" />
			<publisher>University of Illinois Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Urbana</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An investigation of the mechanisms underlying nest construction in the mud wasp Paralastor sp. (Hymenoptera: Eumenidae)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Work and the division of labor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Sociological Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The articulation of project work: An organizational process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Sociological Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social organization of medical work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fagerhaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Suczek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wiener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Plans and situated Actions: The problem of humanmachine communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Centers of communication: A case and some themes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Discourse, tools, and reasoning: Essays on situated cognition</title>
		<editor>L. B. Resnick, R. S?lj? , C. Pontecorvo, &amp; B. Burg</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social cognition, artefacts, and stigmergy: A comparative analysis of theoretical frameworks for the understanding of artefact-mediated collaborative activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Susi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ziemke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="290" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A brief history of stigmergy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Theraulaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bonabeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Artificial Life</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trace signals: The meanings of stigmergy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tummolini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Castelfrananchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">E4MAS 2006 lecture notes in artificial intelligence</title>
		<editor>H. V. D. Parunak, F. Michel, &amp; D. Weyns</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards multi-swarm problem solving in networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pagurek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of third international conference on multiagent systems (ICMAS &apos;98)</title>
		<meeting>third international conference on multiagent systems (ICMAS &apos;98)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="340" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sociobiology: The new synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<publisher>Belknap Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
