<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 D:\grobid-master\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-09-07T03:29+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">TOSI: A trust-oriented social influence evaluation method in contextual social networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Elsevier BV</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guanfeng</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">An</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhixu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaofang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">TOSI: A trust-oriented social influence evaluation method in contextual social networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Neurocomputing</title>
						<title level="j" type="abbrev">Neurocomputing</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">0925-2312</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="volume">210</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="140"/>
							<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neucom.2015.11.129</idno>
					<note type="submission">Article history: Received 4 May 2015 Received in revised form 5 November 2015 Accepted 9 November 2015</note>
					<note>Contents lists available at ScienceDirect Neurocomputing journal homepage: www.elsevier.com/locate/neucom a r t i c l e i n f o a b s t r a c t</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Social network Social influence Trust</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Online Social Networks (OSNs) have been used as the means for a variety of applications. For example, social networking platform has been used in employment system, e-Commerce and CRM system to improve the quality of recommendations with the assistance of social networks. In these applications, social influence acts as a significant role, affecting people&apos;s decision-making. However, the existing social influence evaluation methods do not fully consider the social contexts, i.e., the social relationships and the social trust between participants, and the preferences of participants, which have significant impact on social influence evaluation in OSNs. Thus, these existing methods cannot deliver accurate social influence evaluation results. In our paper, we propose a Trust-Oriented Social Influence evaluation method, called TOSI, with taking the social contexts into account. We conduct experiments onto two real social network datasets, i.e., Epinions and DBLP. The experimental results illustrate that our TOSI method greatly outperforms the state-of-the-art method SoCap in terms of effectiveness, efficiency and robustness.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Background</head><p>Online Social Networks (OSNs) are becoming more and more popular and have been used as the means in a variety of applications, like employment, CRM and e-Commerce. In these applications, the social influence of a participant can affect others' decision-making. For example, at Epinions (epinions.com), an OSN based e-commerce platform, a buyer can write a product review to rate the products and corresponding seller. This review can be viewed by other buyers and thus can impact their decision making in purchasing the same products. As indicated in studies of Social Psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[3]</ref> and Computer Science <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[4]</ref>, a person is more likely to accept the recommendations given by participants with higher social influence (named as Influencers) in a specific domain. Therefore, it is significant to accurate evaluate the social influence of participants and identify those Influencers from social networks.</p><p>In the literature, many social influence evaluation methods have been proposed <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[14]</ref>, in which, Independent Cascade (IC) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref> is a typical model to find the Top-K nodes who have the maximal social influence in a network. Subsequently, some important works <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">9]</ref> are proposed to improve the scalability of IC model. In addition, in recent years, the Local Influence Maximization method <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[15]</ref> has been proposed to evaluate the social influence of a specific participant in OSNs. Furthermore, as some OSNs are becoming a large real-time generator of social data-streams, some streaming methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">17]</ref> have proposed to evaluate the social influence of participants in OSNs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">The problem and motivation</head><p>As illustrated in Social Psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[20]</ref>, the social trust between participants (e.g., students trust their lecturers in a specific research area), the social relationship between participants (e.g., the relationship between a father and his song), and the preference similarity between participants (e.g., they all like to play basketball) have significant influence on participants' decisionmaking, and thus impact their social influence. However, these important social contexts are not fully considered by the existing social influence evaluation methods. Thus, these methods cannot deliver accurate social influence evaluation results. In addition, with the growth of network scale and complexity, social networks become susceptible to different types of unwanted and malicious spammer or hacker actions <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[21]</ref>. We propose a trust-oriented ranking strategy to defend against this kind of attack. social influence evaluation. This paper is organized as follows. Section 2 discusses the related work. Section 3 introduces the preliminaries. Section 4 proposes our TOSI method. In Section 5, we investigate the effectiveness and efficiency of our proposed method by comparing with the state-of-the-art method, SoCap. Section 6 concludes this paper. Example 1. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> depicts a social network from Epinions, which contains five participants (i.e., P 1 to P 5 , they are all buyers). The trust relationship (represented as arrows with solid lines) between P 1 and P 3 , P 2 and P 3 , and P 4 and P 3 can be established based on the quality of the product review of P 3 . Their social relationship and preferences can be mined from the their profiles and purchase history <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[22]</ref>. Suppose P 1 has closer social relationships, and has more similar preferences to P 3 than that of P 2 , then P 3 can more likely affect the purchasing behavior of P 1 than P 2 , which is not identified by the existing social influence evaluation methods. However, in traditional social influence evaluation methods <ref type="bibr">[5- 10]</ref>, the probability of the influence between two nodes is random in LT model or unified in IC model, which cannot reflect the realistic influence of participants. In addition, if P 5 is a spammer, in tradition social influence evaluation models, like the triggering model <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref> and iterative model <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref>, he/she can utilize plenty of spam neighbors to establish fake strong social influence to affect P 1 's decision-making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related work</head><p>In the literature, existing social influence evaluation approaches can be categorized into four groups, i.e., (1) global influence maximization, (2) local influence maximization, (3) stream learning of influence, and (4) individual influence evaluation. We discuss these methods in detail as below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Global influence maximization</head><p>The above-mentioned problems motivate us to develop a social influence evaluation method to accurately evaluate participants' social influence in OSNs. In this paper, with considering the abovementioned important social contexts, we propose a Trust-Oriented Social Influence evaluation method, called TOSI by adopting iterative method. Since our method is convergent fast, thus we can deliver accurate social influence evaluation results with good efficiency.</p><p>The global influence maximization is to find a group of nodes that can impact the maximal number of other nodes in an OSN. <ref type="bibr">Kempe et al. [5]</ref> propose a greedy algorithm which guarantees ( ? ) e 1 1/ approximation ratio. However, this algorithm has low efficiency in practice and thus it is not scalable with the network size. In order to improve the scalability, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[9]</ref> proposes an algorithm that has a simple turnable parameter, for users to control the balance between the running time and the influence spread of the algorithm. Jung et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[7]</ref> proposes an algorithm IRIE that integrates the advantages of influence ranking (IR) and influence estimation (IE) methods for the global influence maximization. Ref. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[10]</ref> provides a scalable influence approximation algorithm, Independent Path Algorithm (IPA), for IC model. In the model, they study IPA efficiently approximates influence by considering an independent influence path as an influence evaluation unit. Moreover, in order to spend up the evaluation algorithm, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[11]</ref> develops the CELF algorithm, which exploits sub-modularity to find near-optimal influencer selections. In addition, Leskovec et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">25]</ref> divide the relations between two participants into two types, i.e., positive influence and negative influence, and predict them via theories of balance and status from social psychology. Based on the above study, Yanhua et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[26]</ref> make the first attempt to investigate the influence diffusion and influence maximization in OSNs with both positive and negative relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.">Contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Local influence maximization</head><p>The main contributions of this paper can be summarized as follows:</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work that fully takes the social contexts into account in social influence evaluation.</p><p>In order to defend against the typical spam attack, i.e., Spam Farm <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref>, in the process of evaluating social influence, We propose a Trust-Oriented Social Influence evaluation (TOSI) method that adopt sspam mass <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref> to measure the probability of a participant to be an attacker.</p><p>We propose a novel social influence evaluation method, TOSI, which achieves 竹 ( ) 6 N 2 in computation cost, where N is the The local influence maximization is to find a group of nodes that have the maximal impacts on a specified participant. Yeung et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[13]</ref> have studied the relations between trust and product ratings in online consumer review sites. Moreover, they propose a method to estimate the strengths of trust relations so as to estimate the true influence among the trusted participants. In addition, Guo et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[15]</ref> propose a method to find K nodes that have the maximal impacts on a specified participant. Furthermore, Iwata et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[27]</ref> propose a probabilistic model to discover the latent influence between participants in OSNs. The model is used to find influential participants and discover relations between participants.</p><p>number of nodes in an OSN and 竹 is the iterative times in computation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Stream learning of influence</head><p>We have conducted experiments on two real social network datasets, i.e., Epinions and DBLP. By comparing with the state-ofthe-art individual social influence evaluation method, SoCap <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12]</ref>, our TOSI method greatly outperforms SoCap in effectiveness (on average, it improves precision by 225%) and in efficiency (on average, TOSI saves 89.2% execution time) for</p><p>In recent years, OSN is becoming a large real-time generator of social data-streams, like Twitter (twitter.com). The streaming methods of social influence become more and more popular. Kutzkov et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[16]</ref> propose a streaming method, called STRIP for computing the influence strength along each link of an OSN. In addition, <ref type="bibr">Karthik et al. [17]</ref> propose an approach to mine the flow patterns, following specific flow validity constraints. However, contrasting with microblogging platforms, the other OSNs cannot provide sufficient contexts to perform information flow pattern discovery. Thus, the streaming methods cannot be applied for the social influencer finding in the OSN based e-commerce platforms.</p><p>Social Relationship (SR): It is the social intimacy degree between two participants <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[19]</ref>. Let s denote the intimacy of the Social Relationship between two participants.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">↙ ( ) = R s 1 i j ,</formula><p>indicates that P i and P j have intimate social relationship, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">↙ ( ) = R s 0 i j ,</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Individual influence evaluation problem</head><p>indicates that P i have not contacted with P j . The intimacy of the social relationship between two participants can be computed based on their personal information (e.g., the father and his son) or their online interactions (e.g., the frequency or the contents of their interactions).</p><p>In order to evaluate the social influence of a specific participant, Subbian et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12]</ref> propose an approach, called SoCap, to find influencers in an OSN by using the social capital values. They model the problem of finding influencers in an OSN as a value-allocation problem, where the allocated value represents the individual social capital. In addition, Franks et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[14]</ref> propose a method to identify influential agents in open multi-agent systems by adopting matrix factorization method to measure the influence of nodes in a network.</p><p>Summary: The existing methods do not fully consider the social contexts, like social relationships and social trust between participants, and preferences of participants in OSNs. As indicated in Social Psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[3]</ref> and Computer Science <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[4]</ref>, such social contexts are significant for social influence evaluation. Therefore, these existing methods cannot deliver accurate social influence results.</p><p>Preference Similarity (PS): It reflects the differences of the preferences between two participants. Let p denote the value of Preference Similarity between two participants.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">↙ ( ) = R p 1 i j ,</formula><p>indicates that the preferences of P i and P j are exactly the same, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">↙ ( ) = R p 0 i j ,</formula><p>indicates that there is nothing in common interest between P i and P j .</p><p>Although it is difficult to build up comprehensive social trust, social relationship and preference similarity in all domains, it is feasible to build them up in some specific social communities by using data mining techniques <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[28]</ref>. Mining these social contexts' values is another challenging problem, which is out of the scope of this paper. </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">↙ = ? ? R 1.0, 0.5, 0.6 2,3 , ↙ = ? ? R 0.8, 0.5, 0.2 4,3 , ↙ = ? ? R 1.0, 1.0, 0.8 1,3</formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">↙ = ? ? R 0.1, 0.5, 0.8 3,1</formula><p>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Preliminary</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Social influence evaluation problem</head><p>Our method aims to evaluate the reasonable social influence of each participant in contextual social networks based on the social network structure and the social contexts.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Given a contextual social network = ( ) G V E LV LE , ,</formula><p>, and a set of social contextual impact factors R, we evaluate the social influence of individual participant and deliver the social influence set SI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Contextual social network</head><p>4. Trust-oriented social influence evaluation method</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">A Contextual Social Network (CSN) [28] is a labeled directed graph = ( ) G V E LV LE , , , , where</formula><p>V is a set of vertices; E is a set of edges, and (</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">)﹋ v v E , i j denotes a directed edge from vertex v i to vertex v j ;</formula><p>LV is a function defined on V such that for each vertex v in V, LV</p><p>In this section, we propose a Trust-Oriented Social Influence evaluation method, called TOSI, by adopting the iterative method to evaluate social influence. TOSI takes the above important social contexts into consideration, and thus can deliver more accurate social influence evaluation results, and therefore can find more reliable Influencers.</p><p>(v) is a set of labels for v. Intuitively, the vertex labels may for example represent social roles or social influence in a specific domain;</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">4.1. Algorithm description LE is a function defined on E such that for each link ( ) v v , i j in E, ( ) LE v v , i j is a set of labels for ( ) v v , i</formula><p>j , like social relationships, social trust and preferences in a specific domain.</p><p>In our TOSI method, the social influence of participants are constantly computed and replaced until the social influences achieve convergence by using iterative method. Next, we introduce the process of iteration and the details of TOSI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Social contexts</head><p>Let P denote the set of participants, and R denote the set of social contexts vectors,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">↙ ? ?﹋ R t s p R , , ( ﹋[ ]) t s p , , 0, 1 , where ↙ ( ) R t i j , , ↙ ( ) R s i j , and ↙ ( ) R p i j ,</formula><p>represent social trust, social relationship and preference similarity between P i and P j respectively. In addition, we use IN i to denote the incoming neighbors of P i and ON i to denote the outgoing neighbors of P i .</p><p>Social Trust (ST): It is the belief from one to another, based on their interactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[28]</ref>. Let t denote the trust value between two participants.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">↙ ( ) = R t 1 i j ,</formula><p>indicates that P i completely trusts P j , and</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">↙ ( ) = R t 0 i j ,</formula><p>indicates that P i completely distrusts P j . The value of ST could be given by one participant to another based on the experience of their interactions (e.g., the purchasing experience of a buyer in social e-commerce platforms). The social influences at iteration time + t 1 are based on the social influences delivered at the last iteration time t. In the process of evaluating new social influences, we consider the social contexts <ref type="bibr">(ST, SR and PS)</ref> between a participant and his/her neighbors equally. Let For a participant P i , the error at iterative time t is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">﹉ 老 ? = ( ? )﹞ ( ) ? ? ? k t k k i 1 , ﹋ SI SI SI SI 5 i t i P IN k i</formula><p>? SI i denote the social influence of participant P i , which can be computed by the following equations:</p><p>Using the Triangle Inequality, we can obtain the expression as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">﹉ 老 = ﹞ ( ) + ? ? ? i t k t k i 1 , ﹉ k t k k i 1 , ﹋ SI SI 1 P IN k i 老 | ? | ≒ | ? |﹞ ( ) ﹋ SI SI SI SI 6 i t i P IN k i</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">老 ﹉ = ﹋ 1 P ON k i , i k</formula><p>and Next, we sum over all the errors of participants to obtain total error. Notice that</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">老 ﹉ = ﹋ 1 P ON k i , i k : 老 = ↙ ( ) ﹞ + ↙ ( ) ﹞ + ↙ ( ) ﹞ ( ) R t TTTR R s TTSR R p TTPS 3 3 3 . 2 k i k i k i , , , k i N N k k k , ﹉ ﹉ ﹉ 老 ( ) = | ? | ≒ | ? |﹞ ? ? ? Error t SI SI SI SI 1 , = = ﹋ i i t i i P k IN i k t k k i 1 1 = ﹉ ↙ ( ) ﹋ TTTR R t k P j ON k k j , , = ﹉ ↙ ( ) ﹋ TTSR R s k P j ON k k j , and = ﹉ ↙ ( ) ﹋ TTPS R p k P ON k j , j k . N ? ? ? ?</formula><p>Here, 老 k i , reflects the whole influence probability from P k to P i .</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">﹉ ﹉ ﹉ 老 老 = | ? | ﹞ = | ? ( )| ﹞ SI SI SI SI P ↙ ﹋ k i 1 , = ﹋ Rk i R k t k k i k k t k P i ON k , 1 , 1</formula><p>Example 3. In <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref>, for participant P 1 , there are four social contexts from four participants, i.e., P 2 to P 5 . The details of social contexts and social influence at iterative time t have been shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref>. At iterative time + t 1, the social influence</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">= ℅( + + ) + ℅( + ( ) = ( ? ) 7</formula><p>Error t 1</p><p>Recalling Eq. <ref type="formula">(6)</ref>, we find that ( ) = ( ? ) Error t</p><p>Error t 1 if and only if</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">? ﹋ ? &gt; ? ? P P SI SI , 0 k k t k 1 or ? ﹋ ? &lt; ? ? P P SI SI , 0 k k t k 1 + SI 0.8 1.0/2.0 0.5/1.0 0.6/0.6 /3 0.7 0.5/1.0 0.5/ t 1 1</formula><p>. But, our iterative method reduces the total social influence to 1, it means that </p><formula xml:id="formula_20">﹉ = ﹉ = = ? = SI SI 1 k N k t k N k 1 1 1</formula><p>. It cannot satisfy the above condition, so ( ) &lt; ( ? ) Error t</p><p>Error t 1 . Then Theorem 1 is proved. ↓</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Convergence of the iteration</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Spam attack</head><p>For an iterative method, a very key and basic task is to guarantee its convergence. Haveliwala et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[29]</ref> have analyzed the convergence of PageRank, stimulated by their ideas about iterative method, next we use an error function and prove the convergence of our TOSI method. Let ? SI i denote the real social influence of participant P i . And then we define the total error at iterative time t to be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">N ﹉ ( ) = | ? | ( ) ? = Error t SI SI 3 i i t i 1</formula><p>where N is the number of participants. Theorem 1. TOSI is convergent, i.e., ( ) &lt; ( ? ) Error t Error t 1 .</p><p>In our method, we consider to defend against a typical spam attack, i.e., <ref type="bibr">Spam Farm [23]</ref>, in the process of evaluating social influence. The attack way of Spam Farm has been shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref>. The spammer P s has partial honest in-coming participants, i.e., P 1 and P 3 , and many own participants, i.e., P z . Such own participants only have relations with the spammer P s . For example, at Facebook, zombie fans always play the role of own participant. Such network structure like <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref>  process of evaluating social influence, we also consider the social contexts (ST, SR and PS) between a participant and his/her neighbors equally. The detailed equation as follows: <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref>. Computing social influence in iterative process.</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">﹉ 老 = ﹞ ( ) ? ? k k i , ﹉ + i t k t k i 1 , ﹋ SI SI 4 i P IN k i 老 = ﹞ ( ) ﹋ TR TR 8 P IN k i</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6:</head><p>↘ TotalSI 0; 7: for each P j in P do 8:</p><p>if P j is not isolated node then 9: ↘ v tr , 0; 10:</p><p>for each node P k in the incoming neighbors of P j do 11:</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">老 ↘ ( ↙ ( ) + ↙ ( ) + ↙ ( ) ) R t TTTR R r TTSR R p TTPS / / / 3 k j k j k k j k k j k , , , ,</formula><p>; /n Calculate the influence probability from P k to P j n/ 12:</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">老 ↘ + [ ]? v v SI k k j , ;</formula><p>/n Add up the social influence propagating from P k to P j n/ 13:</p><p>if P j is trustworthy participant then /n Add up the TrustRank propagating from P k to P j n/ 14:</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">汐 老 汐 ↘ + ? [ ]? + ( ? ) tr tr TR k J 1 / k j , ; Fig. 4. Spam attack.</formula><p>where 老 k i , has been defined in Eq. (2). Next, in order to defend against the Spam Farm attack, we select a set of trustworthy nodes that are widely trusted by the other participants in the OSN. For example, at Weibo (www.weibo.com), we can select the participants who have been certified as the trustworthy participants. Here, we use TN to denote the set of trust nodes and J to denote the number of the set. Otherwise, we adopt a decay factor 汐 for biased TrustRank <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref>. Then Eq. <ref type="formula">(8)</ref> can be improved as:  <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref> that reflects the probability of a participant to be a Spam Farm attacker. The larger the spam mass is, the higher the probability of a participant to be an attacker. Let SM i to denote the spam mass of participant P i . The equation of calculating the spam mass as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">﹉ ? 汐 老 汐 ﹞ ﹞ + (?) ( ) ? ? TR J if</formula><formula xml:id="formula_27">5. Experiments = ( ? ) ( ) SM SI TR SI / 10 i i i i</formula><p>So, our TASI method can recommend those reliable social influencers who have strong social influence and identify the participants who have high probability to be a Spam Farm attacker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Algorithm</head><p>The pseudo-code of the algorithm is given in Algorithm 1. As TOSI is convergent fast, and the iteration times of the TOSI method is a constant. Therefore, the time complexity of the TOSI method is 竹 ( )</p><p>In our experiments, we compare our proposed TOSI method with the state-of-the-art method, SoCap <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12]</ref>. In order to investigate effectiveness, we compare the accuracy of the two methods in Exp-1 and the number of nodes that are influenced by Top-K influencers delivered by the two methods in two classical diffusion models, i.e., Linear Threshold (LT) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref> and Independent Cascade (IC) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref> in Exp-2. In order to investigate the robustness of our method under the Spam Farm attack, we explain the process of how to distinguish the Spam Farm attacker in Exp-3. In order to investigate efficiency, we compare the execution time of the two methods in social influence evaluation in Exp-4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Experimental setting</head><p>6 N 2 , where N is the number of participants and 竹 is iterative times.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1. TOSI algorithm.</head><p>Require: The set of participants P, the set of relation vectors R, iterative times 竹, decay factor 汐 for TrustRank, trustworthy nodes TN, the number of trustworthy nodes J; Ensure: The social influence set of all participants SI, the spam mass set of all participants SM; 1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">↘ { ( )} SI TR SM rand , , 1 ; 2: ↘ ? NewSI NewTR , ; 3: ↘ TotalSI TotalTR i , , 0; 4: while 竹 &lt; i</formula><p>do /n Iterative evaluate the social influences which are based on last social influences n/ 5:</p><p>↘ + i i 1;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1.">Datasets</head><p>We adopt two real social network datasets, Epinions <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[32]</ref> and DBLP <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[33]</ref>. The Epinions dataset has 75,879 nodes and 508,837 links, where each node represents a buyer, and each link corresponds to the relationships between buyers. The DBLP dataset has 317,080 nodes and 1,049,866 links, where each node represents an author, and each link corresponds to the co-author relationships between authors. The details of the two datasets are listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2.">Ground truth</head><p>As indicated in Social Psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[34]</ref>, if a participant can influence the maximal number of participants who have a high social influence, then such a participant has high social influence as well. Therefore, we rank the influencers based on the number of influenced participants as the Ground Truth in Exp-1 and Exp-3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.4.">Experimental environments</head><p>All experiments were run on a PC powered by two Intel Core i5-3470 CPU 3.20 GHz processors with 8 GB of memory, using Windows 7 Professional. The code was implemented by using Visual C? ? 2012 and the experimental data was managed by MySQL Server 5.6. All the experimental results are averaged based on five independent runs. The ratio of high indegree nodes 2.679% 0.054%</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Experimental results and analyses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.3.">Diffusion models</head><p>In Exp-2, we adopt two classical diffusion models, i.e., Linear Threshold (LT) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref> and Independent Cascade (IC) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref>. These models have been widely used to investigate the effectiveness of social influence evaluation methods in <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[35]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[36]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[37]</ref> by comparing the number of nodes that are influenced by the seeds in these diffusion models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1.">Exp-1. effectiveness (by ground truth)</head><p>We measured the precision by varying the Top-1000 influencers retrieved by each method against the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers.</p><p>Firstly, we observe the trend of Retrieved Number with the inLinear Threshold (LT) Model: LT model is the first model to imitate the diffusion process of information. The approach is based on the node-specific thresholds <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>. In the model, at time step t, all nodes that were influenced in step ? t 1 remain being influenced. A participant P i is influenced based on a monotonic function of its influenced neighbors</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">( ( )) ﹋ [ ] f In i t , 0 ,1 (see Eq. (8)) and a threshold 牟 ﹋ [ ] 0, 1</formula><p>creasing of times of iteration to investigate the convergence of our TOSI method. Here, Retrieved Number is the number of retrieved influencers, which are both the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers and the Top-1000 influencers delivered by our TOSI method. The experimental results delivered based on Epinions dataset and DBLP dataset are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 5</ref>, where we can see that the Retrieved Numbers of our TOSI method keep stable after 5 times of iterations for both datasets. Then, in the following</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">i , i.e., P i is influenced at time t if 牟 ( ( )) ≡ f In i t , i .</formula><p>experiments, we set the Iterative times 竹 as 5. Secondly, after five iterations, the experimental results are listed . In our experiments, in order to investigate the effectiveness of our method based on different thresholds, for each P i , we set 牟 ﹋ { } 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, 0.7, 0.9</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">﹉ ( ( )) = ( ) , ﹋ ( )</formula><p>in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>. For Epinions, our TOSI method finds 840 out of the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers, while SoCap can only find 247 influencers. Based on the precision function in Eq. <ref type="formula">(8)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12]</ref>, the precision of our TOSI method is 84%. In contrast, it is only 24.7% for SoCap method. Therefore, comparing with SoCap, on average, our method greatly improves the precision of social influence evaluation by 240% in Epinions dataset. For DBLP, our TOSI method finds 138 (precision is 13.8%) out of the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers, but SoCap method only finds out 44 (precision is 4.4%). Therefore, on average, our method improves the precision of social influence evaluation by 210% in DBLP dataset.</p><p>i . Independent Cascade (IC) Model: IC model is a dynamic cascade 900 model for the diffusion process. The model is based on the interacting particle system from probability theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref>. At each time step t, each participant is either influenced or susceptible. A participant P j that was influenced at time step ? t 1 has a single chance to influence each of its incoming neighbors P i . The influence succeeds with probability p i j , (see Eq. <ref type="formula">(10)</ref>). Therefore, for participant P i , if at least one of its influenced outgoing neighbors succeeds, P i gets influenced. The probability of participant P i getting influence at time step t is: where ( ? ) In i t , 1 is the influenced incoming neighbors of P i at time step ? t 1. Here, we set</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">= ( ↙ ( ) + ↙ ( ) + ↙ ( )) p R t R s R p /3 i j i j i j i j , , , ,</formula><p>.</p><p>In our experiments, we select the Top-K influencers delivered by our TOSI and SoCap to act as seeds in the different diffusion models respectively, here, ﹋ { } K 1, 5, 10, 20, 50, 100 . Based on the properties of the diffusion models, the number of nodes that are influenced by the seeds delivered by the diffusion models can illustrate the influence of the Top-K influencers <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">36]</ref>. The more the number is, the higher the effectiveness of corresponding method is.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> The comparison of TOSI and SoCap with Ground Truth Top-10 on Epinions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">﹉ ( ) = | () ? () | ( ) i i ﹋ AE method dataset RA P GTRA P , 15 P GT i</formula><p>where GT is the set of Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers, ( ) RA P i is the influence ranking of P i evaluated by each method, and ( ) GTRA P i is the Ground Truth Ranking of P i . <ref type="figure">From Fig. 8</ref>, ( ) AE SoCap Epinions , is much greater than ( ) AE TOSI Epinions , and ( ) AE SoCap DBLP , is much greater than ( ) AE TOSI DBLP , , so the error level of SoCap is high.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nodes' ID Ground truth ranking TOSI ranking SoCap ranking</head><p>Finally, we study the accuracy and absolute error of our TOSI method by comparing the Top-1000 influencers identified by each method against the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers.</p><p>Since SoCap ignore the social relationship and preference similarity between participants, it cannot deliver accurate social influence evaluation results. Therefore, our TOSI method outperforms SoCap in Effectiveness based on Ground Truth results. </p><formula xml:id="formula_34">= | ? | | | ( ) Precision Relevant Retrieved Retrieved 14</formula><p>Next, we list the results of the Top-10 influencers retrieved by each method against the Ground Truth Top-10 influencers in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. From <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, our TOSI method can find all 10 influencers, and the TOSI Ranking is very close to the Ground Truth Ranking. But the influencers delivered by SoCap is far away from the Ground Truth Ranking, and 5 out of 10 influencers are missing in the Top-10 list.</p><p>5.2.2. Exp-2. effectiveness (by diffusion models) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. 9</ref> depicts the experimental results of LT model, where we can see that in all cases, the number of influenced nodes identified by our TOSI with different K and 牟 i is more than that of SoCap. The</p><p>The experimental results of Epinions and DBLP are plotted in</p><p>Figs. 6 and 7, where we can see that the number of the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers retrieved by our TOSI method is more than SoCap's with higher rankings (the small red circles of our TOSI method are closer to the center of the large circle). Therefore, our TOSI can deliver more accurate social influence evaluation results than SoCap.</p><p>average number of influenced nodes identified by our TOSI is 5609.18, while that of SoCap is 1371.02 which is 75.56% less than that of TOSI. In addition, the number of influenced nodes identified by the two methods increases with the increase of K. This is because that with the increase of K, the number of sources for the spread of information increases, which leads to the Top-K influencers identified by both of TOSI and SoCap can influence more nodes in LT model. Furthermore, the number of influenced nodes identified by the two methods decreases with the decrease of 牟 i . This is because that the limit for the spread of information decreases with the decrease of 牟 i , which leads to the Top-K influencers identified by both In addition, we use an Absolute Error (AE) function to measure the error of each method. The error is the absolute value between the influence ranking delivered by each method and the Ground Truth Ranking. The detailed calculation is as follows:</p><p>of TOSI and SoCap can influence more nodes in LT model. Therefore, based on the properties of diffusion models <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[5]</ref>, the experimental results illustrate that the Top-K influencers identified by our TOSI have more influences than that of SoCap in LT model.  Fig. 10 depicts the number of influenced nodes identified by our TOSI and SoCap, where we can see that with the increase of K in IC model respectively, where we can see that the number of influenced nodes of our TOSI is more than that of SoCap in all 6 cases on the two datasets. The average number of influenced nodes identified by our TOSI is 24,441.92, and that of SoCap is 21,069.5 which is 13.8% less than the former. This is because that based on the properties of the IC model introduced in the Section Diffusion Models, with taking the three social contexts into consideration, the Top-K influencers identified by our TOSI have higher probability to influence their neighbor nodes. In addition, with the increase of K, the number of nodes influenced by the Top-K nodes identified by both of the two methods increases.</p><p>From the experimental results in the two classical diffusion models, i.e., LT model and IC model, we can see that the Top-K influencers identified by our TOSI have more influences than that of the state-of-the-art method, SoCap. Based on the properties of diffusion models, on average, our TOSI improves the effectiveness of SoCap by 90%. Thus our TOSI method outperforms SoCap in effectiveness based on the two classical diffusion models.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref> lists the corresponding execution times of social influence evaluation (except the time of "loading all data into memory") of two methods. On Epinions dataset, the average execution time is 444 ms for our TOSI. By contrast, it is 6436 ms for SoCap. On average, our method can save 93.1% of the execution time. On DBLP dataset, it is 1244 ms for our TOSI and 8364 ms for SoCap. On average, our method can save 85.1% of the execution time. This is because that based on Theorem 1, the convergence of our TOSI is fast. Therefore, our TOSI method greatly outperforms SoCap in efficiency. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.4.">Exp-4. efficiency</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3.">Exp-3. robustness</head><p>Firstly, we set 5 Spam Farm attackers who have 500 randomly honest in-coming participants and M own participants respectively in the two datasets. We give them tags "SF-Attacker-M", here, ﹋ { } M 50, 100, 200, 500, 1000 . In addition, we select the ? Top 1 influencer delivered by our TOSI as "Honest Influencer" to compare with these attackers. Next, we select the Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers as trustworthy nodes, and set 汐 as 0.85 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref> to evaluate the TrustRank scores. At the end, we investigate the Spam Mass of participants based on Eq. (10). From <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref>, compared with the "Honest Influencer", we can see that the attackers have much higher Spam Mass in the two datasets. As indicated in Section 4.3, the larger the Spam Mass is, the higher probability of a participant to be a Spam Farm attacker. Therefore, our TOSI method can identify the Spam Farm attackers well via Spam Mass, which improve the robustness of the social influence. However, SoCap cannot find these attackers.</p><p>In this paper, we have proposed a Trust-Oriented Social Influence evaluation (TOSI) method which is based on three social contexts, i.e., social trust, social relationship and preference similarity, between two participants to evaluate the social influence of each participant. The experiments conducted on two real social network datasets (Epinions and DBLP) have demonstrated our TOSI method greatly outperforms the state-of-the-art method, SoCap, and can deliver more accurate social influence evaluation results with less execution time.</p><p>In future work, we plan to apply our TOSI method into real OSNs to deliver accurate social influence evaluation results and recommend reliable influencers. Lei Zhao is an Associate Professor in the School of Computer Science and Technology at Soochow University, China. He received his Ph.D. in Computer Science from Soochow University in 2006. His research interests include data processing, data mining, and parallel and distributed computing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Xiaofang Zhou is a Professor of Computer Science with</head><p>The University of Queensland and Adjunct Professor with the School of Computer Science and Technology, Soochow University, China. He received the B.Sc. and M. Sc. degrees in Computer Science from Nanjing University, <ref type="bibr">China, in 1984 and</ref><ref type="bibr">1987, respectively</ref>, and the Ph.D. degree in Computer Science from The University of Queensland, Australia, in 1994. His research interests include spatial and multimedia databases, high performance query processing, web information systems, data mining, bioinformatics, and e-research.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. A social network of Epinions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Example 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 depicts a contextual social network, which contains the social contexts as</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. A contextual social network.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. The convergence of our TOSI method. X-axis is iteration times and Y-axis is retrieved number. We use stairs lines to show the trends of retrieved number with the increasing of iteration times.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6. Top 1000 influencers of each method on Epinions. X-axis and Y-axis are all ranking of social influence, and the large circle is the boundary which contains the Top-1000 influencers (small red circles and blue stars) delivered by each method. Small red circles are both Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers and Top-1000 influencers delivered by each method respectively. Blue stars are Top-1000 influencers delivered by each method rather than Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers. The more close to the center of the large circle, the higher influence ranking the influencers have. (For interpretation of the references to color in this figure caption, the reader is referred to the web version of this paper.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 7 .Fig. 8 .</head><label>78</label><figDesc>Fig. 7. Top 1000 influencers of each method on DBLP. X-axis and Y-axis are all ranking of social influence, and the large circle is the boundary which contains the Top-1000 influencers (small red circles and blue stars) delivered by each method. Small red circles are both Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers and Top-1000 influencers delivered by each method respectively. Blue stars are Top-1000 influencers delivered by each method rather than Ground Truth Top-1000 influencers. The more close to the center of the large circle, the higher influence ranking the influencers have. (For interpretation of the references to color in this figure caption, the reader is referred to the web version of this paper.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Fig. 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Fig. 9. The number of influenced nodes on Linear Threshold model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Fig. 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Fig. 10. The number of influenced nodes on Independent Cascade model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Feng</head><label></label><figDesc>Zhu is currently a Master Student at the Research Center on Advanced Data Analytics (ADA) in Soochow University, China. His research interest is social influ- ence evaluation. Kai Zheng is a Professor of the Research Center on Advanced Data Analytics (ADA) in Soochow University, China, and an ARC DECRA (Australia Research Council Discovery Early-Career Researcher Award) Fellow with The University of Queensland. He obtained his Ph.D. in Computer Science from The University of Queensland in 2012. His research interests include uncertain data- base, spatial-temporal query processing, and trajectory computing. An Liu is an Associate Professor of the Research Center on Advanced Data Analytics (ADA) in Soochow Uni- versity, China. He received the Ph.D. degree from the University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, and the City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, both in Computer Science. His research interests are in the area of service-oriented computing, social network, information security, and spatial databases. Zhixu Li is currently an Associate Professor at the Re- search Center on Advanced Data Analytics (ADA) in Soochow University, China. He used to work as a Re- search Fellow at King Abdullah's University of Science and Technology (KAUST). Prior to that, he received his Ph.D. degree from the University of Queensland in 2013, and his B.S. and M.S. degrees from Renmin Uni- versity of China in 2006 and 2009 respectively. His research interests are data cleaning, big data applica- tions, information extraction and information retrieval.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 1 Experimental datasets.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset 
Epinions 
DBLP 

Nodes 
75,879 
317,080 
Links 
508,837 
1,049,866 
Average indegree 
6.706 
3.311 
High indegree nodes ( 
≡ ) 
indegree 50 
2032 
170 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="true"><head>Table 2 The performances of TOSI and SoCap with Ground Truth Top-1000.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Method Dataset Retrieved 
number 

Precision Average execution time 
(ms) 

TOSI 
Epinions 840 
0.84 
444 
SoCap 
Epinions 247 
0.247 
6436 
TOSI 
DBLP 
138 
0.138 
1244 
SoCap 
DBLP 
44 
0.044 
8364 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="true"><head>Table 4 The spam mass for attackers.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Tag 
Dataset TOSI ranking, SM(attacker 
probability) 

SoCap 
ranking 

6. Conclusion and future work 

Honest Influencer Epinions 1, ? 1.13(low) 
1199 
SF-Attacker-50 
Epinions 53, 0.94(high) 
2127 
SF-Attacker-100 
Epinions 48, 0.93(high) 
809 
SF-Attacker-200 
Epinions 51, 0.96(high) 
1170 
SF-Attacker-500 
Epinions 42, 1.06(high) 
423 
SF-Attacker-1000 Epinions 58, 1.97(very high) 
230 
Honest Influencer DBLP 
1, ? 2.24(very low) 
65,256 
SF-Attacker-50 
DBLP 
20, 0.86(high) 
19,754 
SF-Attacker-100 
DBLP 
17, 0.95(high) 
5165 
SF-Attacker-200 
DBLP 
18, 1.21(high) 
30 
SF-Attacker-500 
DBLP 
9, 1.93(very high) 
856 
SF-Attacker-1000 DBLP 
19, 2.23(very high) 
82 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This work was partially supported by Natural Science Foundation of China <ref type="bibr">(Grant nos. 61303019, 61402312, 61402313, 61232006, 61003044, 61440053)</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fast influencebased coarsening for large networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Purohit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Prakash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Subrahmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/2623330.2623701.URL:?http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2623330.2623701?</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2623330.2623701.URL:?http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2623330.2623701?" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1296" to="1305" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Influence in social networks: a unified model?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chelmis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Prasanna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1109/ASONAM.2014.6921624?</idno>
		<ptr target="?http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ASONAM.2014.6921624?" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>ASONAM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="454" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attraction and close relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Berscheid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Reis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Handbook of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Receiving other peoples advice: influence and benefit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Yaniv</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organ. Behav. Hum. Decis. Process</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Social Beings: Core Motives in Social Psychology</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust based recommender system for semantic web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kaur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Marwaha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>IJCAI</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2677" to="2682" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">?</forename><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Irie: scalable and robust influence maximization in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Heo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>ICDM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="918" to="923" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Time-critical influence maximization in social networks with time-delayed diffusion process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>AAAI</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="592" to="598" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Scalable influence maximization for prevalent viral marketing in large-scale social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1038" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-K</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Scalable and parallelizable processing of influence maximization for large-scale social networks? in: ICDE</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="277" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Costeffective outbreak detection in networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Guestrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Faloutsos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanbriesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Glance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="420" to="429" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Finding influencers in networks using social capital</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Subbian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>ASONAM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="592" to="599" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strength of social influence in trust networks in product review sites</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-M. Au</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Iwata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>WSDM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="495" to="504" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning influence in complex social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Franks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>AAMAS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="454" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Personalized influence maximization on social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>CIKM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strip: stream learning of influence probabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kutzkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bifet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bonchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gionis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="283" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Content-centric flow mining for influence analysis in social streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Subbian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Aggarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>CIKM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="841" to="846" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction: Trust and Crime in Information Societies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mansell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<pubPlace>Edward Elgar, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intimate Relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Brehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<pubPlace>Mcgraw-Hill Book Company, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Luhmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Raffan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Rooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Trust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Two Works by Niklas Luhmann</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Wiley, Chichester</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A data mining-based spam detection system for social media networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the VLDB Endowment</title>
		<meeting>the VLDB Endowment</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust network inference for online rating data using generative models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-P</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="889" to="898" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Link spam detection based on mass estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gyongyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Berkhin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd International Conference on Very Large Data Bases, VLDB Endowment</title>
		<meeting>the 32nd International Conference on Very Large Data Bases, VLDB Endowment</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="450" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting positive and negative links in online social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Huttenlocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="650" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signed networks in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Huttenlocher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 28th International Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, CHI 2010</title>
		<meeting>the 28th International Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, CHI 2010<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1361" to="1370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence diffusion dynamics and influence maximization in social networks with friend and foe relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sixth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining, WSDM 2013</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Rome, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="657" to="666" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discovering latent influence in online social activities via shared cascade poisson processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Iwata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ghahramani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>KDD</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Orgun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trust transitivity in complex social networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1222" to="1229" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>AAAI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient Computation of Pagerank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Haveliwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combating web spam with trustrank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gy?ngyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirtieth International Conference on Very Large Data Bases</title>
		<meeting>the Thirtieth International Conference on Very Large Data Bases</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>VLDB Endowment</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="576" to="587" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threshold models of collective behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Granovetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am. J. Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1420" to="1443" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust management for the semantic web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>ISWC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Defining and evaluating network communities based on ground-truth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>ICDM</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relation between trust in the supervisor and subordinate organizational citizenship behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Deluga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mil. Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Influence maximization with novelty decay in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="?http://www.aaai.org/ocs/index.php/AAAI/AAAI14/paper/view/8485?" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>AAAI</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="43" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Guanfeng Liu is an Associate Professor of the Research Center on Advanced Data Analytics (ADA) in Soochow University, China. He received his Ph.D. degree in Computer Science from Macquarie University, Australia, in 2013. His research interests include social networks and graph mining</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
